Okay welcome everyone thank you very much for coming to this the first lecture
On a course called
Information Theory pattern recognition
And neural networks
The first lecture is an introduction to information Theory
Information theory was invented by Claude Shannon to solve communication problems
And
The fundamental problem
That Shannon defined was the task of reliable communication
An unreliable Channel
Sorry that's a fundamental problem and I'll give some examples
All right now
So some examples of channels
1 channel by using right now is the channel that goes from my voice to you
And the medium is
I know the channel that we may be using is a channel it goes for my eyes up to
Bits of our nervous system
And that the medium is so bags of cytoplasm intellect limp lump impulses
Another example of a channel that we're all carrying around with us is DNA about
10 to the 13 copies of our genome on Boris and
And every time one of those bells replicates and two copies of the gene
Repeat that 40 times and you've gone from an egg to a human being and maybe I'll
The Next Generation
And
Another example is the spacecraft baby Mars Rover or something like that
And I'm 10 on Earth how to use the vacuum
Transmission medium
And
Send signals to the miles and make it back
Signal settings of the channel that can go in both directions
And another example it is a phone line so you maybe have a
Copper wire
If you're old fashions
Connecting One phone
Turn off the phone
Another example is a disk drive so the medium is some sort of film
Hannah standard
Hard drive
And in that destroying
You store a message which might be the file and use
Send it
Do yourself
At another time so many of these towns go from one place to another place
One place to another place you can have channels that go from one place to they strive to the same place but
The time and was still trying to communicate a message from that one location to another location
And all of these channels have in common with property
That the received signal isn't identical to the transmitted
Signal
So
Because of noise or
Other processes I receive signal
Is Maybe
Approximately equal to
The transmitted signal
But we've got some noise
Added as well
Maybe some of these channels
Maybe there's no relationship no simple equality relationship but told you just have to message
How to receive signal depending on the transmission signal in some way for a toy Channel
Northeast signal by adding some sort of noise
And
In most of these applications we might say that's bad news because we would really like reliable communication we would like
I'd like to be able to deduce the receiver precisely what the
Irish middle transmitted
Signal was
So
We would like
Communication systems
Received message
Is equal to
Message message
That would make for a better phone call about the disk drive
How better communication between Electra
And audience
So imagine that
What trying to achieve this goal was trying to make a reliable Communication System what sort of approach
Kids could we go for what Solutions are there
Well we can tops categorize solutions to this go into a
Eva that physical Solutions
Where you throw away the lines you just drive and replace it by a better one that's more expensive
Maybe you take your couple wires and you put better insulation on them
Do you use
Dakota magnetic field you add cooling so you change the physics to reduce the noise
Cyber physical Solutions
Open System Solutions
The idea of a system solution is we accept the lousy Channel as it is
Encoding and decoding systems around that channel to turn it into a reliable chat
But this is a much more exciting approach in the physical approach physics is exciting to but the system approach except
Unreliable system as it is and transforms it into a reliable
System
And that's what information theory is about we're going to be taking Souls messages
I saw his message which might School s
Is going to be put through an N Kota system and then Kota which we will Design
Encoda will spit out the transmission
Tea
This coded transmission then gets sent
Have the channel
What channel will do its thing
Aladdin oil lamps
And then look at a received
Message
Which is going to be a corrupted version of this coded message
But then we can have another system in systems going to be cold at Dakota
Invent last two
The Dakota
Will try and come up with a guest
PS4s with a half on Top Hat meaning guess
What's going on here
Bianco de is going to be some sort of system that adds
Redundancy
I will think about that
Will detail in a moment and then the Dakota makes use of this noon system for adding
Redundancy to try to infer
T & N
What if you like both the source message
And end
So the decoder is going to be a system for inferring
And
Okay let's give ourselves a toy model to think about
The Playmobil that will work with for a while
It's cold
The binary symmetric Channel
To Binary symmetric Channel
Adult an input
And we'll idealliance and assumed that that input is a
0 or 1 but you get to choose each time you use the channel is it a 0 or 1
You sent
And then
What comes out is ultherapy or 0 or 1
And we're going to assume
That the probability that what comes out is what you put in
Is 1 - F
90%
Find the probability that it is not what you put in
Is
For example 10%
Whenever you put in a zero cuz it 10% chance of one will come out
With a 90% chance is there a will come out and symmetrically
Dell way round if you put in a wall and there's a 90% chance you could have worn out
At Petra
That's the binary symmetric Channel
That's probably very few channels in the real world but all the binary symmetric Channel but it's a nice simple my voltage
Discuss that has all the essential properties that we need
To study of information Theory
So we can think of this as a model for a disk drive let's say you've made your new startup companies
Cambridge blue disc drive and you make your first purchase like this drive using your new invention
Technology and attested and you find it flips 10% of the best
Is that useful destroying for let's just have a quick think let me ask you question the long hair
Question 1
Try again
Okay
?
A file of 10000 bits is stored on this disk drive
It's stored on a disk drive that flips
10% of the bits
Let's read
Assuming that f is .1
Assuming that each b****** independently either flipped on Netflix
Roughly
How many bits
Puppet
Money
Iflix and I'd like you to discuss this weekend and give it
In the form roughly this many plus or minus
This money
Does everyone understand the question
Okay please talk to your neighbor and then we'll see what numbers go in here
Number flip
1000 plus or minus how many
Debating okay
Anyone else ae1000plus mice
Plus I minus
+ - 900
Tennessee
I got a few answers that
Who said who wants to give a reason for their answer
So anyone who gave an answer
Reason
900 Sam's Club
Yeah wife us- 900
The date of the actual good cuz he doesn't need to understand things if you got the title book
I wanted to take the book side
Okay and you're looking at the variance of what
Binomial distribution
So you look up the binomial distribution
And it's what I mean
All enzymes pyp hair is f
I just got a variance event EQ IQ is the other thing
All right take a look at it and then you need to know what variant means and how that relates to well roughly.
- 1000 + - 1
10005.1 mm the variances 900
But what does that mean the meaning of the variance it's the square of the standard deviation
Service is
The square of the standard deviation you take the square root of it which is
Sissy that tells you roughly how many bits either way
Hillary Clinton not a binomial distribution is pretty much the only bit of mathematics you need to know
It's coarse and I do encourage you to review the binomial distribution and get good at working with it because
Use it over and over in this topic and another topics in information Theory as well
Okay so we have an answer 1000 +
Thanks to miss the binomial the inventor of the distribution that says his name
Okay so we've got high disk drive
We launched the company
And are we going to have a happy customer when we sell the first just drive
Any opinions
No Lie
It is slightly too many flips isn't it if someone storing important information
Question 2
To have a salable this drive
Salable 1GB
Describe
If it were a disk drive
That's a binary symmetric Channel How small would it have to be for you to be able to make a successful
High School
Does the flip probability
Need
To me please turn to your neighbor
Can have a chat about this question
Okay
Any answers how old do you need to be to have a salable this drive
Have a viable company
Yes
10 to - 13 and the other one says
Pentillie
10 to -5
That's true many people need 20 GB disc about 3 years old
Go put a little please
Pretend that you are that's in the past 3 years ago
We can redo it for another size of this might be less than gigabytes gigabytes
USB sticks.
Okay so trying to make a bootable usb stick
Saint Francis
Temperature
10 / 3
We got quite a range of ancestor
Yeah
No S10
Okay so
Let's have some explanations from the extremes of the range please
Where to take the -13 come from what was your
Okay every thousand times you fill it online
On your judgment was 1000 was was enough
Okay
Right
So
2-3 come from
Like I said let's redo this calculation let's kick the tires on it a little bit
So
Let's imagine that customer is going to use the drive every single day you going to be
Sally intensive user that say that they might use the drive to five years because that's stingy and they believe
And sustainable use of resources
So let's save. 5 years of use
And we're going at a rate of Wong gigabytes today
Then the number of bits
That will be sent through the channel is 5 years * 1 GB
And 1 GB
Is 8 * 10 * 9 bits
I'm 5 years is 5 x 365
Chase
So that's our number bits
That we want to send
And if you multiply that out you got 10 to 13 so very much on the same page
Do you want to sell it and say you're expecting a failure within 5 years
Maybe that's not quite good enough we'd like
It's be quite unlikely that our first customer will ever complain
Yeah so if we want a 1% chance
All the disappointment disappointment being that any file a tool
That's messed up
Then we need the error probability to be something like 10-15
And if you want your first 1000 customers will be happy then you need to answer 10 - 18
1000 happy customers
Pushes you towards one thing tenth of -18
And if you talk to the Fitzroy industry and he say what is your industry standard for performance of a disk drive
-18
For today let's accept 10-15 has a reasonable answer
Stop blaming for
Panera probability of 10-15
I would not want to
Step back to the diagram I just rubbed off to talk about encode is and Dakota's I'd like to discuss
Ways of adding
Redundancy I'll clean the board and if you have a chance we tell her about how could an end CO2 work how could we
Redundancy
Profile
Okay
No I'm not asking you to give me a name code of it Solstice problem space off I'm just asking
Just a tad redundancy
So do we have some ideas behind to add
Redundancy
Yeah
Pirate according what does parity coding mean ghost
Okay
So we're taking some string of zeros and ones that we want to transmit
Like ice how long is the string that we're going to do the power TV off
A bike so maybe take a 8 Bits
I was I was looking and then
That's what the sauce came up with and then we add an extra
Parity bit here
Who wrote Poppy
And he's the some of those
1 2 3 4 5 in 5 example using binary so we right
One because one is the famous five okay
It would have been for we would have written 0
So that's a parity coding up a way of adding redundancy
Good
Any other ideas for how to add redundancy
Repeat things multiple times so we'll have what was the code how many times
For example would you want to repeat
Okay so we'll cool repetition codes
And I'll write out the code
We're going to take each bit and I'll resend it will repeat it some number of times
So we could send zero and then repeat it twice which I'm going to hit from now on repeating 3 times okay
That video
3 x + 1
Get send as one or more
I'm Loco with all three
And I accept you could pull this repeating it twice because you send it then you repeat it twice but I'm going to pull it repeating it
That's my convention
And I made one of those that are
And this is what it looks like
So we've got to find a 10,000 bit on the left and then we repeat it
Three times about stereo the debate so the first that is sent after the whole file has been sent
Repeat the whole pile three times logically just the same as repeat
8-bit
So let's give ourselves a source file and the source file could be the string 01
Andre transmitted
0 0 0 1 1 1 1 1 1
One one
So that's how we encode a file
Let's not give us all some noise and start talking about dakotaz
I will stop at the repetition code
So let's have a noise back there in the way I'll represent noise is it going to snow for the Packers
If a flip
Because
So hear the noise Vector binary symmetric Channel could produce for us
And that would that mean that they received that the difference from tea and some
Some of these places
So that's how I received letter
Did I do that I did
The transmission to the noise and I did the addition modulo
2 * 1 + 1 + 0
Okay
How should we decode this
A decoder is a system that reason
I received
File and spits out I guess
4S
Suck
In general
How should we
Decode
All three have a chat to your neighbor
Okay any suggestions of how in general yes or the back
Okay so take the mean of each group of three is that what you mean so we read it three of the time
And you say
Is the mean above a closer to 1 or 2 0 okay
Did anyone else have another way of putting the same concept yeah
Best of Freehold majority vote Yes
We reckon that the sensible Dakota is
The best of n
R3
And the length of this block of a transmission
Best of free
Dakota or majority vote
Dakota
All right. If we received their 0-0-0-0 if you received
1103 cyclops
If we were saving one beside one
Do Japan if I make
Okay so does eight possible receive that doesn't is what we do according to this
Dakota Dakota hair then
Juan
And what we cannot assist in this case
Is that some good things to happen
So here
I flipped because
That was a flip
How to train cleaned up because this is the same as this
And so that makes us happy
And
Something else has happened
Head of a two flips in a block
Unless you've been going to want actually an Arab so that's not good
It's not about that
But
Fair enough
Maybe this Dakota does improve things
So if we apply the majority vote Dakota
This is what we get
And if you compare the
Fluffy Mastiff
The source file and the
Decoded file that
You can say it's improved things we have reduced the probability of era
But it doesn't actually that
That's the ten to the minus 15
Progressive Era
Not before we
Proceed and say
How to make besan become better at encoders and decoders
I just want to prove this
Intuition
Why is the majority vote Dakota the right Dakota
As I said earlier decoding is inference we want to infer
What the source
Message
Ross
And to do inference we need to use inverse probability
I just want to remind you how to invest for the cigarettes because
In due course we're going to do slightly more complicated problems while you may not leap to the correct answer quite so
Easily
So inverse probability needs the rules of probability the rules of probability of the product rule
Which says that the probability of two random variables for exempt
The Source bit and the received
Vector can be written as the probability of s x the probability of
Kevin S
Play SPF PFS
The definition of conditional probabilities if you like it tells you how to get a joint
Probability from a marginal probability
And a conditional probability
Then the other rule of probability and they're already too is the summer rule in the summer
How to get a marginal probability
By adding up all values of a joint probability
P of S&R and I will give you. Are
All right
So if this is a variable that takes on two values this is
City of s equal 0 & R
Plus via vesicles Wong
We can use
The rules of probability to then tell us how to decode
For example if someone tells us off and we want to know how probable alternative values of s
That's cool the posterior probability
You got that
Bye
Taking the two versions of the product of 11
The thing we want is on the right hand side so we'll divide through body of a
And we'll get the answer
So this is
Fee of R given x x
/ theater
Until we can compute using the sum rule
Which we just write down over that so I wouldn't run it again
Wow I will actually that's right there
I'll go one extra step is we can take each of those terms
Over there
See if given s equals 0 x p a vesicle
To write each of them at
Explicitly
Okay
So that the rules of probability tell you how to do inference that tells you how to do decoding and we can take
An example of vector se01 1
And we can apply these rules
So this is how it's not only that this is a sensible Dakota but it'll tell us how probable each of its answers is
To be correct so for example if you received 01 Wong
And the two things we need to know ever had we need to know
This thing was just killed the likelihood
All of us
And here we thought the prior or the TV
So we need to work out what's the probability that
Has that value is equal to 0
Combination of the Pro Bowl get off if x is equal to 1
So what's the probability of getting 01 warm out if the sender was trying to
To send a single zero I have to be
A non-flat which has a problem
Then how to be a flip
Then have another flight so that's the probability of guessing that
Was there a
That's the light to go to vesicle Sarah
FS1 what's the probability of getting 0-1-1 in the first bit
And then both of the last two bit would have to be in each of those
Independent probability of being Netflix
Okay
So that's
1 - 1/2 x squared
And this is after the 1 * 1 - F
And this exponent are which in this case is Wong
Is
The number of bits that would have to be
Flips for this hypothesis to be right
Number of bits
Fat wood
Have
Pain
Well then
A list to which is no longer missing
Is the number of agreements
Between
What the transmission Vector would be for that ass on the C factor that we're actually dealing with
Okay and the more agreement you have the bigger the likely it is because Walmart his ass is bigger than
Okay suck
That's not derive this Dakota
Let's make an additional assumption we can only answer this question if we say what the probability of s is then we can
Get an answer
The posterior probability
Am I going to say the following I'm going to say if the probability of 0 is
Obviously the wrong then
We can actually write down the inference the probability that his long given our a011
Is 1 - 1/3 squared
X f x 1/2
/
The same time as grass downstairs like this Plus
The other time
The other explanation
American simplified
How many Council everything out you got
One- at
So we've now answered in that table we just had going to ask hot we've looked at 1
The road is there a long and not what we what is the probability that SS
Equal to one given or is there one one
Is 1 - 1/2 which is 90%
So it was a sensible thing to say you should guess
I want
Write a note you can repeat that for all eight possible answers
Almost all of them just the same but if you received
Slightly different
Answer for the probability of
What the Dakota says you should guess
Suck
Just to finish this off I'm laboring it because it's good to be clear on the simple case then we can go and
Do more complicated ones
The probability that it was a warm is bigger than the probability that
It was a zero
Islam is the best guess
Okay
Has the best gas because it did involve the smallest number of flips
So I'll leave as an exercise doing the case is warmer one so you can work out
Their probability
In that case
Suck now we have a new task
This was using probabilities to do inference
Now what I want to work out is how well does this Dakota perform
So this is an example of
I want to ask the question if we use a repetition code
Frank Otis
What's 70 / binary symmetric Channel with a flip probability ass
And then we use the majority vote Dakota to give us
What is the probability that
Will not equal
That's what I'm talking here about a single bit so we send one bit over the channel using this procedure
What's the probability that the S 1/2 we end up
Spitting out about Dakota will not be the same as the bit that went to TNA
Okay
Announcers
The flip probability IS F
What's the probability
Have an error of this system
Animal
What probability distribution are you thinking about anyone
Savannah distribution imagine that
What outcomes would cause this thing to happen
Outcomes you need to look up in the daytime book
Two or more Flats in a block the probability of 3 Flats in a block
Is f cubed
That's pretty unlikely for them old beef lips
The other thing that could happen and these are exclusive possibilities is that exactly
32 flips
I'm more likely things that we should refocus attention on this time
How
Probable is it that two flips will occur in a block
S3f Squad 1 - x
Which you can read out of your day to book on the binomial distribution
Thank the three ways of a happening that's why the three
Comes from the three ways of choosing which bits off limit when you're flipping 2 from 3
That's roughly 3x squared plus some other stuff
Remind us to fq
This is the dominant
Tamil eating Behavior
Alright so what we done so far we started out
With no code
Andre had a probability of bit error
Which was
For example 0.1
And when we didn't use a code at all
Alcoa communication at rate one because every time you use the channel you are attempting to send one bit
Then we invented the repetition code which is got a rate of 1/3
Set all three
How the rate of Wallingford
You send one bit for every three uses of the channel
And it's our probability is roughly 3x squared
That is some good news
Assuming the Earth is a small number like 0.1
The repetition code is making things better
But the bad news is the rate has gone down
Sucks
Remember what we want to do is want the system solution that gives us an error probability of a
About 10 to the minus 15 will maybe even ten to the minus 18
We could continue with repetition coats
And a hug what problem is to look at
How many repetitions do you need
In order to achieve
10 - 15
Assuming that we using a repetition code
How cold is probability of bitter ipb for short
So that's how my problem
And I'll tell you the answer for free it's about 61
We wanted a system solution
And here is one solution
Let's say that this is a single disk drive what we do is repackage up 61 of them all inside
The Box
That's why it's great big stack I would put a single wrap around it
This is one gigabyte disk drive
You copy the file
On to all of this right and use the majority vote
And outcomes
Answer
I'm at majority vote will be right with the probability of ten to the minus 15 but each bit
So you may have one happy customer
But you probably wouldn't have a thousand happy customers and you've got a very big stack of this drives hidden inside this
Fox
Okay so that's one option we can repeat lots of times
And we can get the error probability down
Initial customer say no 10-15 is not good enough and he just like
Cost more Destroyers I put even though this rise in the box and you can still achieve any Target but the cost
Go steadily up
Okay
Let's not get to the exciting bit
Where can we get to on this diagram
I got to tell you
Another way of making coats
Which is to use parity bits which cost adjusted at the beginning I'm going to tell you about the seven Full House
Encode
And then I'm going to tell you Shannon's result but where we can get to on this diagram
Codeworks
It's cool to 74 Hammond code because it takes four Source bits of the time and then close them into set
7 transmitted bits
So we can have three extra party bits and it works like this we write S1 S2
3 + 4
Into the circle tattoo
And then we set
The remaining
3 bit switch local t v
P6
27 steps of a parity in each circle even
So let's do an example
I'm going to encode for u1000
Set wish send as in the clear 1000 and then we're going to send three more bit afterwards
And those fits I determined by writing 1000 in order
And then
We find the parity in this circle
Wang so that the total party is even with a zero k
What's the one that we read the matching the right Toyota 01
That thing
Let's do one more example
Taiwan
Party in here
Three so far which is also put another one and even
This is even already so we write 070
So that link codes 21110
Halo by 100
Okay
No
That's the encoder
We need a decoder for myself
And
Just as for the repetition code the decoder is going to be the Dakota that spits out
I guess s
The difference
Who's transmission sorry to ask who's transmission TFS difference from what we were
Received in dispute
Flips as possible
Black cat
So the general idea is
PMS giving off his P of all given ass
Likelihood David s's baby have the
The fewest flips that comes up with the hypothesis that involve the smallest
Number of flips I will do that
By writing what we receive in to the same diagram that we
Created over that
So we got to write the man in the same order are Wong
Aa203
And I'll fool and all 5 up there
Not because the noises come along and could have flipped anything
This all could be
Anavex virtual and it may not satisfy these rules that we had I would have the rule being that the pirate
Cnh Circle should be even
And what we're going to do is identify
Which of those rules are satisfied in which I'm not satisfied
And then we'll use that
Pill identify
Which bits we think they've been flat
So anything could happen
Let's imagine that we send this signal this transmission
Let's imagine
Along the way
Is received
Flips
Okay
So what we receive
110-0101
We don't know what happened that so little secret that we will remind us
But we don't know that
So now we right
That into
Histogram
So we write in
Warm
Wang
Sera
Warm
Announce we
Color the circles in accordance with whether that happy or not
This is unhappy that will color that red circle
Listicle
It's happy
Not positive happiness and sadness will cava syndrome of the received
Signal
And now I'm going to tell you what rule for coming up with a hypothesis of what happened there are many hypothesis
Could account for the syndrome because there's all sorts of flips that could have happened
The rule is going to be
Find
The bit this is inside Olson circles and outside Oliver happy circles
And then identify that one has the bit that must have been flipped
Not sure but that's going to Be Our Guest
So inside all the sad circles outside the green circles is this guy
So we identify this guy
As I guess
We guessed this was flipped
And so then we spit out
I'll guess fatigue is 100010 long and I guess for s
Is the first four bits of that
Which is 1000
Which is the right answer
In this case we have succeeded
Now
If actually what happened with the noise of come along and split two bits
Then this decoding rule is going to go and find a single bit that it can run flat
Two account
So what happened
Pokemon that with three bits being messed up so this Dakota is not infallible
It is the case
That this
Encoder and decoder
Can detect and correct any single flip
So any single flip
Canby
Check it on credit
So that's nice but
More than one because
Then
It turns out and you can prove this is a hard work
Problem
Then your guest pass
Will not be the original s
Vidalia vet
It's only want to sleep in a block and sixties just like all three the repetition code
But if it's to flexo more than more in trouble and this diagram
On the screen shows the performance of The Seven full how many code
100 problem is to workout
What is probability of error is
What's the probability of a flip
Of an error occurring
When we use this and codrin Dakota
And what you'll find out when you do that moment problem is the probability of a blood Cara
Is roughly 21 f-squared you'll find that out using the binomial distribution
Find the probability of
Is about 9 ft squared
Deleting order
Okay
So Shannon asked the question
If we make encoders and decoders
Where can we get to on this diagram
Got a few ideas repetition codes on I-71 code using parities
The question is what's the boundary between achievable and unachievable points
On this diagram
And before Shannon
Conceived of asking that question I think conventional wisdom was at the boundary between achievable
A knowledgeable points
Just have to be
Some sort of line going through the origin
Because songs lost as if you were really small then surely you're going to have a really small right
Just like our gnomus stack
I've described that we are imagining
So conventional wisdom knew that points over here where it's evil
But conventional wisdom probably was assuming that the boundary
Went somewhere
Soundproof an absolutely remarkable results and this is going to be
Of the secret door latches to prove
Bits result
China proof that you can get the error probability small
Without the rate having to go to zero
Search an improved
Set the boundary between achievable and knowledgeable pints
Is a line that looks like this
Everyone here is achievable
And excitingly
This line
Meet the re taxes
I don't know right
Handicap that's an exciting place to talk about we give it a name and we'll call it see the capacity of the
The channel that were disgusting
For example
The capacity of the binary symmetric Channel
Where the flip probability ass
Is
One- the binary entropy function of F
Function
For you
Right now
It is
So there is the line between achievable and not achievable points
So what does this mean
Shannon sports are selling a test drive at this drive is the one gigabyte destroyed mate
61 drives Inside the Box
Annie sez
You don't need 61 Drive In The Box
Together and our probability of 10-15 you just need to disk drives
Because
For the case where f is 0.1
The capacity when you work out this formula
Comes out to 0.53
Which is bigger than a hop in the Box
And then there exists an anchoring system in the decoding system that can correct as many hours as
As you like whatever ever prove it to you name that exists an encoding and decoding system
That are probability
Pennsylvania's 15th no problem to describes
10 - 18
To destroy
10 - 60
To Des Moines
That is Shannon's
Noisy Channel coding theorem
So for any channels
Encoders and decoders that can achieve reliable communication
At any rate up to this country called the capacity of
Channel
I'm going to wrap up now I've just got three things to say first election oats
This lecture chapter 1 in this book which is a free online book also available from all your favorite book
Bookshops you can get it from Amazon you can get it from Cambridge University press and it's free on the website
Hibiscus as a PDF
Like two notes on chapter one
For the next lecture I recommend that you read chapter 2
And the remaining lectures of its core organic of information Theory will continue discussing the
Noisy Channel coding theorem
How to make files smaller
Then we'll move on to discussing data modeling and recognition
Learning and memory I will talk about various inference methods approximate inference methods
Neural networks
The final thing I want to say is please before the next lecture have a think about this puzzle
Physical the waiting
Problem the weighing puzzle
When it goes like this
The given 12 Bulls
All of which are equal in weight
Except for one and you're told that exactly one of them has got a different way and it's either heavier or lighter
Girls are giving a balance and the balance is one way you can put any number of bulls on one side and the same number on the other
And then initiate the weighing and it even comes I like this or this balance
And the task is to identify the old bull
And whether it's heavier or lighter in a few uses of the balance as possible
So that's going to be the first thing that we discuss
In the next lecture
Thank you very much for coming thanks for listening