Walking directions to re
We'll talk about sauce
Coding orthodontist data compression
The big picture is in lecture one I introduced you to the middle of the course noisy Channel coding
Step back and think about how to measure information content and how that relate to doing data compression
And for two topics for today are we going to continue examining the evidence for the assertion that
The Shannon information content which I burned down here
Is the right way to measure information content
We will prove to Source coding therapy that actually proves that
The sun information content is the
Will SketchUp roof the details are in the
So
What disgusting how to compress redundant files and as a toy example of a redundant file
You could imagine
An alphabet with just two possible car doesn't it is 0 and 1 Generation by tossing a bent calling
Has a nice chance of coming up 0% chance of coming up
So that's an example of a very simple toy redundant file and we'll talk more about that
If you cuss
The general claim is the son of information content of an outcome
Is a sensible way to measure how much information
That outcome gives you
Add if you take the average of the Shannon information content you get the entropy
And the second claim is the entropy is a sensible measure of expected or average information content
We
Discuss the last time a first
Experiment if you like a first case study
For testing these claims about but kind of information cannot be looked at the weigh-in problem
And must be going to try and Foal billing problem struggle a bit and think about it quite a lot
Maybe after a couple of days struggling they still haven't got the answer
And the Shannon information from 10 gives you an idea where it says if you want info with it why or why not choose one
Not with maximum entropy
When you follow that principle you got a solution that got you done in three Wayne just fine
Out of a 12-volt which one is the old one and heavy or light
In 3 weighings
And that's all it needs
And that's the best you can do and so it's a it's a little piece of evidence that hey maybe this
We think it's useful
If you don't choose
The waiting at each step that has the maximum possible entropy that you are going for a strategy that
Does not guarantee to get you done in free
It's a good idea
Probably think about entropy
Deferred payment going to discuss is the seal coating serum that says it if you guys got a big string of N Out
Outcomes from a source
Then they can be compressed
Into roughly n times the entropy
This
Sir
I asked you last time to have a think about the bent coin Lottery
Puzzle
We'll come back to this very soon the best coin laundry in voles
Nothing's been calling a thousand times to determine which is the winning ticket and if you
And the winning ticket you win a gazillion pounds
And the question I asked you was if the mafia boss tells you that you must buy enough
Tickets from the shop to guarantee a 99% chance of winning
The price which tickets would you buy assuming that you try to minimize the cost of the tickets they cost you a quid
H
And how many tickets would that add up to
Okay so we'll come back to the first one to look at to slightly simpler example
Two more little games to think about these claims about the showing information contact the first game is
Code 63 and it works progress
In 63 I think of a number and the number is drawn from this hat is everyone...
So I pick a number
And then you ask me questions and I say yes or no to go questions
And when you know what it is
How do you say I know X
How to talk to your neighbor
What strategy would you use to try and identify the number I'm thinking of
As rapidly as possible using as few guesses as possible
Okay who'd like to suggest a way of
Ask a guy asking questions to
Play the sky
I don't be shy
Okay
So your first question could be is X bigger than or equal to 32
How's your day and I could say
Yes and then your next question will be
I can't is it in the range 48 to 63 and I could say no
I keep on having and you're getting for simple eye-popping you just continue as warm
Ask your second question for you in a general way you could ask for edx modulo 32
Number greater than or equal to 16
Okay
Enat
Xbox X32 means throw a 32
Alright so this answer the first question was yes which I could go Wong
Second question was 0
Question is going to be his ex
Body like 16 or equal to
Marketside
And then he'd ask
Is X mode
And I might say no
Like I need to keep on going and going and you ask this phone
How do I say yes
Pioneer
The X1 July 4th pick 2
The same as asking is it an even or an odd number
And I might tell you
No
Analogy day
Okay
I'm what I'm answer is 42
Because what you
Nitrostat is 101010 is 42 in binary
I don't got any comments questions everyone with me
Okay
Suck a solution to the game of 63
And
An observation we can make is that
If you want to be sure of identifying an outcome in this alphabet
Then it will take you six binary questions to be sure by identifying it
We could also have a think about these Clayton what The Shining information comes I bet School answers
What's the first question wrong
C2 C3 C4 and song
Questions
What was the Shannon information content of each of these answers
Well it's time you asked the question question
You didn't know what I was thinking also it was 50/50
Well dance with me
So the Shannon information content open.com walls
Log base 2 1 over the provision of outcome which was a hawk whatever happened
So that's love II
Cheap one bed
So the total information content according to Shannon that you got total
Heinen
Information
Contents
Put your games
Throughout the whole Burlingame with six bits
The string of answers that you don't
C1 to C6
Is an encoding of x
Heinrich
Karolina kurkova tfx string of 642
1010 I-10
When making a connection to session
If you got an outcome you can compress it into 6 bit
And 6 bit to shine information content and it's all making sense there's nothing very surprising Happening Here
Text of this is very weak evidence
The idea yep
Shannon information content is looking promising
Why was it a good strategy to split
It into switch everything into some people
So why don't you ask first is it a prime number
Why is it a good idea to split exactly into
It got Maxim information content maximum expected information contact the probability
I wouldn't be
Haha
I'm trying to say hey you're not getting as much expected information that you could cause a channel Samsung like the
In the big sat out of the two to go crashing can talk to 7:15 then
You're going to need more than
The remaining whatever it would it be in 5 questions
Okay
Let's ask you one more question based on this game and then do another game
All right
Suck it the question
If I cover sets with s possible outcomes in it
How many bits long must each name be if every outcome is going to have a unique name
The question is I have got a drawer full of
Underwear at home
I don't want to be Farrah and systemic can give every one of these a unique name so I can record on Facebook which player
I'm wearing today
Talking to right little names on them
And the question is
If I'm going to post on Facebook the
Binary name of each of these items
Capital S different pieces of underwear
How long does each of these binary names have to be assuming I give them oil binary names of the same
Likes
Habitat your neighbor
Okay
How long do my labels need to be
To label my underwear
An outcome from the set, uncoded
Healthy communication in how many bits
Yeah
Log base 2
Alves any Advance America
But we're going to round it up a bit in case this isn't an integer longer 64 or 6
Which is nice and convenient
In general logos 67 or something
We'll have to round it up a bit so maybe you need to go up by almost 1 and weak feeling
Symbol hand means ceiling
Which means
Take this number rounded to the nearest integer
Okay
Telogis is definitely the spirit of the arm sore after and if we're being obsessive we stealing longest
Rachel hunt net worth
We got the right temperature
An outcome from a certain size asked if you give them all names of binary
This outcome can be communicated and low base to pass
Burrell
Okay time for another game
This is a game based on battleships but a slightly more boring game
It's called submarine
Man submarine Wong submarine is hidden somewhere in the ocean and then have to stop firing at it just like in bed
Tips to try and find the wrong submarine
So let's run submarine
Hair It Is
Sucks let's have a game Sally built in some Shannon advice so who can see
For every possible thing we could do hair you can fire a tiny Square tells you what the probability of getting
Yes but you hit the submarine submarine is just one square of 64
63 / 64 that's right
It's 67-64 for the square
Better with time
Marinas
Actually fire this crap and
It will keep in track what was the probability of the outcomes that happened Greenwich is no no
The answer for that first outcome
Is
The probability
That response number one
Was no
What is 63 / 64
So The Shining information content of that first
How come is log base 2 of one over that which is lowest 264
All right
And that's a Slightly bizarre
Number 0.02 to 7
At what kind of trivial examples weighing problems
We looked at
Identifying underwear with fiber strings
I got you a 63
Uneven
Shannon says when you find out square in no
You got this much information .022 7 fix
But it's not obvious
Okay
Charlottetown playing and see what happens
Africa
And the public you know it's 62 every 60 take a shower fire
Boom what happened
The probability of getting another is what happened
2 / 63
Shannon information content with log face to event
Which was
Slightly more
But no
Sorry.
North
3 and the right-hand column is keeping track of the total information we've gained so far let's
Write that down
Dwell
Turtle information gained so far
I carry on playing all of these
Maybe if we could have suggested
Dying for a little while
We could go if I can find fire this way but the probability of snow is One Republic
And that would give us no information content and nothing happens
Hahaha
Okay what's happened so far.
Half of the squares
And what's happened to the Shannon information content when you add it all up so far I got lots and lots of nose
Who's in the final long that I've just asked
Is log 33 / 32
Samantha Shannon information
What's going on
Well
It's a bit like playing 63
And choosing to ask question is the number one hit song
Very silly sausage in 63 and we got home late or is it his
Fetty WAP
And the answer is
No it's not that
And the great thing about this and that's just the same as asking
Is it less or equal to
Which
This is consistent with what we already felt was completely obvious
All right so that's promising this lot has ended up to
One bit very painfully acquired information content but it makes complete
Sense
Okay
What happened
La love
32 / 31 and what attempt was did this
Well we would just about to expect another know it would had a probability of
19 / 20
Latest thing we just
Did the Gullah know information competitive log
But then amazingly
We got a sudden enormous flu full .3
Send information contact over something
It feels a little bit
How much is it'll add up to
Look
Chex Mix
Hey I thought that expects we found the submarine we found which number I can 63
The computer was thinking of
Why did it come to such a beautiful routing number was that
Some special coincidence or does it always happen but let's just
Checkr report occasion
S&S I'm blessed I'm blessed I'm blessed
Preventative
Unless unless I'm so the answer is always going to come out once you found
Submarine Malone face tattoo
Look at that snow proof
But it's a nice little bit of evidence that maybe this log of 1 of A P thing which looked a bit strange beginning
Maybe that is the right way to measure how much information you got when something happens
You want to play again
Maybe not any questions
Okay
So that submarine
Now that there's been calling Lottery
Suck the question is the mafia boss tells you
To buy tickets
The outcome is going to be the string that is obtained when the coin is tossed
1000 * it's been calling
Redheads and common tiles
You can buy any of the tickets you want from the box office
If you roll
The winning ticket then you got a gazillion pounds
And the mafia boss forces you to buy
Lotto tickets in Oakland have a 99% chance
What are the questions I'm going to ask you if instead the rule of being forced to buy one ticket
Stop pounding.
To go and spend it
Which ticket would you buy
Have the best chance of winning
Then
Question 2 is going to be have a 99% chance of winning which tickets would you buy and how many tickets is that
And please express your answer in the form 2 ^ something that's three questions
For you
Please answer all of these questions
I want the board
Okay let's start with the simple question
You're forced to buy one ticket from the shop
Which
Ticket would you buy
Penny Wong
The old man I was ticket
Is
Anyone want a different ticket
Really
Yeah
What is 900 + 101
Chat
Does the older I get
Which one would you would you buy
Which of these
You don't mind
I'll take one for you I'll take this one
Are you happy with this choice of would you like a different one
It's up to you
You like the most spread out I can't
Okay I'll give you one where the most for that
Okay we could still have the details
But we would come up with a particular answer whether spread out until you say you're happy and then we sell it to you for
Okay
Let's run the lottery now and see which of these tickets
When Sarah got a choice of three we could go this too today this is be mrs. tickets
So I got a computer and computer the great running lotteries
So
Nautilus submarine
I'm his v card for running a lottery
U-Pick and
You said f
And you do a loop and time spitting out zeros and ones
Look like I'm going to run it runs and times to see who wins
To make it a little bit faster because you might anticipate that it would take a long time to actually run this Law Firm
Might have too many thousands of simulations before we go anywhere this I'm going to change and
Will change into 20 I'm going to use the same kind
All right I'm going to take the liberty of updating the answers you've given me so group
Who liked the old heroes ticket out using the old zero tickets till
3br voting for the one that has to office immediately followed by
18 zeros
Okay
Andrew Percy
This is your chance to say what you want you can read it out to me if you want I'll make it up for you
Then you can say if you want a different one
Speak speak speak
Is that alright
That long
Hi okay. Two wrongs in it
If you want to 10% and you wanted them spread out
Join a different one we're about to run the lottery this is your chance
Okay I'm the winner gets a chocolate biscuit
But you're not allowed to eat in the election
I'm going to keep running it in fact because if we just had a winner that was the luck of the draw
I'm going to run until someone has run 10 times alright
And then we'll see how everyone else did
Yeah if you wanted a right so this group
Let's Get Rich As for me and you can check to see whenever they happen will keep count
Until someone is 1/10 times already
Hahaha
Surrounded that night we got a warning about variable names
So that's the first one
All right no one chest just don't get it right
Second lottery ticket
FreeOnes goodness make
Who won one
K
Hahaha
Hello what the LeBrons
Okay turkey pan
If you've had one win the ticket
As Roma two wrongs
I want to talk to you on
What's wrong with that was to
I want to talk to you wrong
Second wind
I also got three this week up to
This is. 322 warm
1 long
One one
Reruns for Wee Ones
Hey how many of you want so far group a
3 winds well-done
But you're just lucky on you
QuikTrip
Nachos but I think being delayed
McKay
Oh that sucks Pokemon you see that
But
They had an extra one Ono
How many begotten
Okay so what happened with had 10 wins
For this ticket
Knowing for the Swannanoa and so that one
All right so what was the last dinosaur
Looks like he was a good choice or ticket is the most probable ticket
This
A much higher chance of two woman coming up
That is very improbable thing having no one's at all so that intuition is absolutely right that you're not expecting the old
You are expecting typically to Wong's
Something
But the most powerful ticket
Is the old zero ticket
All right so what was Christian
If you have 99% chance of winning at lowest
Which tickets would you buy have another chat to your neighbor
I'm going with Anna's a thousand again
Okay I already heard of chocolate biscuits
Send it for talking so whoever suggested deal zero ticket gets one at the end
I know
Got a 99% chance of winning
Which tickets would you buy
Speak up
Yeah
Okay so you would buy the older or ticket
Only one
0 tickets 10
Tickets
One one
Well then
Boulevard one
Full movie
To Milan
Tickets
Find
Okay which is where I want to eat you already said you got
So give me a bit more information
Okay they didn't add up to some and what do you anticipate is going to be
Let's call it movie
CarMax
Juan
Tickets I'm introducing a babbling now going to happens when the lottery
Run
You're going to buy movie tickets will it take to have all Max
One's on the roughly what the max needs to be if you do that calculation you described involving a
Probability distribution
Binomial distribution again
Good
Roughly
What are mikes
Something like two to the 100 the baby okay so you'll talk me the number
Tickets that you need to buy I'm asking what does Max need to be sorry
120th
Okay
Set
Why 120 ish
The standard deviation of the number of ones that we got
Okay
Okay see you in 4 to send the deviations
Around the mean the mean number of 1 is 100
And the variance is an F1 - 1/2
Pictures of 1000 * 1.1 * 0.9
Which is roughly a hundred
But exactly 90
Which is roughly 10 Sigma the standard deviation is 10
Answer key to sanity be like you need to go
20 is 95%
The number of one's is going to be
Give at 8:20 so it's going to be between 80
I'm going to let you know that you all to buy bills Aerotek ticket even though it's very unlikely stay by everything down there as well
Because that's good value for money
But you stopped once you get up to
Navigate to a chance of winning of roughly
What's the probability that a normal variable
Is within two standard deviations
Have the main his long Sigma
Has two Sigma
Republican marriage
95%
What is 95% in that
And we've already bought this Taylor out here as well cuz it is the freaky lots of 0 tickets
What are the best value-for-money so the probability of its
And
Stylish 2.5% is 97.5%
Roughly if you buy all of these tickets movie
Suggesting or 121
Tickets
Write down a little bit. It's a hundred plus a small number
Compared with Android
How to K
Strategy and I think we're understanding what's a good strategy and now we need to know how many tickets is that
So if you buy this many tickets
How many oliveiro tickets are there is one how many Wong
Wang tickets
There's a thousand right
How many Q on tickets on
Thousand
Choose to
Which is more than a thousand bike light
Answer for how many hundred twenty
Wrong tickets all that
The number of them is
Choose 120
So the number of tickets
Boss
Is 1 + 1000 + 2 + 8 + 1200
In the middle hair with the most probable value of which is 100
Okay I'm the question is is that something like 2 ^ 100 or not
Cactus big questions because this may be wrong
How to attach to each other
Which of these terms in the sum is the biggest
And what's a good approximation for is it to 200 or is it something else
Okay
I've slightly corrected the answer we had a moment ago cuz remember buying everything up to the 121
Tickets only got you a 97% chance of winning in the rule what you could have a 99% chance so I've gone
The tickets that have 123 ones on them
Country standard deviations and that's what you need
Sucks in this series has a sum of terms
Which is the biggest
Roughly how big is it
Press which is the biggest
Right one
Any alternative answer
I don't think it's not
He thinks it is
OK Google okay
Stop this is right answer
If you plot a graph of and shoes which is that first Factor the binomial distribution
As all goes from 0
2 and becomes extremely big and then comes back down again and its biggest
And I would too
And we talked about the first up to here and then getting steadily bigger and bigger and bigger
We could hardly see them on this graph
But I do like the last one we just brought repair
Resume in
I got like that and that's the last one hits the biggest okay
How big is
This one Rock Lee
This is roughly 2 to the power something
And how big
Is this in the Forum
2 to the something
I think this is the biggest we don't really care about Lenny face we just want to know what's that number start with this one
Perhaps a little bit more familiar
Roughly what's 1000 choose 100
Anyone
2 to the power
800 something
Where did you get that from
Approximating
Okay so you approximated and factorial
And minus are factorial factorial
Okay
It's quite tricky the first time you do it maybe two bucks mate
Factorial and this
What
What happens when we approximate
This dude
Okay
500 - where do you get 500 from
So you're saying it through to the end times the entropy
All the distribution
Point warm, no point nine
W i k
Kiss
Let's check the book
Which I have encouraged you to read
And we go all the way into the book to page
I'm page one says
The binomial distribution and it talks about how to approximate the binomial distribution
And it has approximation
4 + Tucson
I can't indeed
How is the homework problem for you
To confirm
Love this thing
Is well approximated by an X we call it the binary function of Our Own
All right
Good
Lottery
This one's about 2,500 is actually more like to the 470 this one's a little bit bigger than 2 to the 500
It comes to true to the five
And in general if it's if it's a been the general
Length n
Lottery Robinhood 1000
Lottery
Then
The number of tickets you would have had to buy
I have a 99% chance for General and an s
To have a nice chance you would buy one.
And juice
FN
Pop a little bit
A little bit
Hit something on the lines of f- at times and square rooted with some factor out front like to
2.3 to make sure you got enough standard deviation
That many tickets
Which is approximately to the Past
And
X
The Byron Bay
Off
F
Plus something smoke
Plus something
Pascal's eyes be
Square root
Right
Sex
Reductant counting yes?
Okay the mafia boss gave you instructions the question is why you won't have the lowest possible cost
That's because it's the rules getting invited not here he's paying for the tickets
He wants to minimize the cost every ticket cost one pound
Please
Spend the smallest amount of my money or I will kill you
And we must win the lottery early haven't proved to me that we have a 99% chance of winning or I will kill you
Okay that was the rules of the game
And now having followed his instructions
You get home and you have bought
This many tickets to Sao Paulo 550 tickets
I'm not now we're going to use
That result of how many tickets you bought to give us a crazy proof
Episource coding theorem
Okay
When you take those tickets home
Let me draw a picture of what you got
You've got yourself
A big bag
For the ticket
And every ticket
Has a great long string of ones and zeros on it and most of them have about 10% lungs
And it's a very long back for the tickets I'm bringing the tropical filter person
You decide to give every one of these tickets a shorter name
So you take every ticket
I need to turn it over I don't know if this side of that ticket
You write a shorter name
Which organ to write in binary
So the first one is Michael
Over to you
Replacement name which will be a shorter name of some lights
Here with me this is just because you're my father, it's like me and my underwear
Recycle your ticket to turn them all over and on the back you're going to write a unique name for ticket
So that
When the winning ticket comes along you have a nice short name when you can post on Facebook the winning ticket had this name written
Reverse
Attack
If you do that
How long is it to be short names going to be on the reverse of the ticket
Yeah
Okay
Set the cost of about 2 to the 500 tickets in your bag
The length of this is the house
Is there a set of size tutu they 500 the length and needs to have the ceiling off to be today
500 vs 500
Set it is roughly 500 actually
We have to buy
So in this particular case is 530
Long opposite direction the front of the ticket has x on it the outcome that might happen
I'm at a thousand fitslim
Travessa got a short name 550 bit slow
Now what are you got
You've got yourself a practical compression
System for the vent point you got a compressor compressor
How does it work look impressive looks like this so you won the lottery for the
Boss you pay him the zillion pounds and then you keep the bag because the bag is your compressor
The way it works is whenever someone create the file using the Bank coin
Eureka bag
Can you find the bag of V winning ticket
But you're almost doesn't have in that 99% chance U
You find the winning ticket and you write the short name and store that on the list
Strife
And then when someone says
Tell me that filed but you can press for me
Negative the zip file real telling you the short name on the back of the ticket and used
And you look in the bag back of every ticket until you find the wrong with that
Best name on it
Okay
That what we have shown is we can make a compressor on and on compressor let's go to 99%
Effects
We could have made it 99.9 just fine fastening that standard deviation little bit
The compressed length still would have be 500 plus a little bit now
It is just as the square root of an and that's relatively small
So what weekend
Michonne butt
And out comes from the coin
Can be compressed into roughly
And * the entropy of 0.9
Bets
Freetime compress
Capcom into
V money
Bits in a little for the batteries not included conditions apply in college
Deal with the  and roughly
Which is bacillus coding Center and increasing the address
Statement like I said
Return compression. Comes into roughly at age fits and we proved this by counting the typical set
The book contains
The general rigorous proof of the source coding theorem for Dental Source not just the band coin
The Hobbit chapter 4 if you want to see the full proof and the general definition of what we cool
Typicality typical set the typical set for the bent coin is old
Come here that which we expect to see most of the time so go down
A couple of standard deviations
This is the typical fat
On the precipice of skirting theorem depends on defining typicality and shoving that when and is very big
What usually happens is almost always
Typical
Next lecture
We're going to discuss
More practically have to do compression because you may be aware of the fact of how 500
Is substantially bigger than the number of electrons in the universe
Service I call this a practical compressor well is not really fast and then the next lecture.
Real practical compression systems for trying to get close to what the source coding theorem proof
It's possible
I'd like to give you a project so you're thinking about this task already before I tell you the answer
All the answers
The project is please invent a compressor and turbine compressor
Which is a practical pair of systems
Assuming that we consult
And let's assume it's been calling for the probability of 1% of coming out
Alright I like you to implement
Your compressor and a compressor on a computer and or estimated value method
What I think it's the valuable exercise for you to do
As we move on to discussing practical compresses
Harrison recommended exercises and reading
From the book
Thank you very much for coming