Welcome Fletcher 12
Today we're going to be talking about
What color methods one of several methods you can have in your probability to whenever you call
Distribution that you are interested
When we were first looking at simple interest problems we just did a complete enumeration of
10 million
So that's always available as an option but typically complete enumeration just end up taking too long
Not more than two or three
The plastic method is in the book I'm not planning to talk about it
It's complicated distribution it's a bit too big to enumerate and You approximated by a simpler distribution
Mainly I got him
Approximate
The distribution of Interest by Gaskin
I like Nicole useful ways of dealing with
Nasty complicated
Distribution by using
Random numbers
So we're going to use random numbers today
Simple lecture today and in the next election
Advanced methods it really
It's in a good place
Call someone that can do things.
At least I can do is pasta
Bendy
Call Alexi will be about variational method switch iMessage
Optical problems
Set yourself
Just to remind you this course has a website on the book
Esprit online
On the way
So here's a little road map of where we're going with want to call him at this very simple Monte Carlo methods
Slightly more complicated
And then we'll get home today I really fancy method
Electra plan is already discussed clustering
In this lecture on simple Monte Carlo what country get up to
Whisper by the red line go get up to
Truckers message on Gibson playing leaving the second half
The following
Lecture
I want to remind you what we did
In the last lecture which was a bad clustering
This gave us an example of
Distribution that we were interested in and it would
It would like this
Probability distribution we were interested in
Call
A whole load of unknown me you on YouTube
A whole load of unknown standard deviation signal Wong
Citgo 2
How late is unknown weight High Wang Pi 2 to Taipei
A whole load of unknown assignments all
Foster's C1 C2
C3 up to cm
You can think of
C walk
Walk to 3
Decay
I still have complete the list of things you don't know or how I guess that's the list of all the things you don't know
Given the data which was at a point X1 X2
Talk to text app
The problem is he were interested in is the posterior probability distribution
Call
All of these things given the data
Given the assumption
Today tithi
Come from
Distribution with these means and standard deviations on white circle
Given that the X's are assumed to come from a mixture
Call cassia
That was the model we receiving in the last election
And we discussed briefly the idea that you could
Alternative models instead of a mixture of gaseous a mixture of some other sort of distributions
I'm still you would have an indifference problem why you are not interested in exploring the unknown factor locations
Sizes and shapes
I need the unknown assignments
Given
Bodega
As a real world example of this
You could imagine that you have a thousand manuscripts that have been transcribed by scribes back in the air when
When everything was done with handwriting
And you take those thighs money script situations official documents
You want to install a couple of these characters
Which characters were written by which Stripes because if you can infer that interesting things about
Sociology of the community
Scribes in the ancient world
And they're all trying to make a hundred writing looks very similar to each other but nevertheless you can actually most of them
This guy's I use Robin the other guys
Example of
Why you might want to do this with handwriting recognition
Stop what does that supposed to registration look like
Well
If we call all of these promises
Pizza
Then the probability with dealing with
Is a pizza given over later
And that's why Bayes Theorem is reversible
Texas
I'm going to change my mind about
Viola paramitas it say where the men's cut
Assignments be another thing.
Where are the closest
Well how well did those hypotheses predicting
How credible
Emagine Novi
Dividing by
Often it's a good idea to deal with the long sauce things like
Great big brothers from 1 to end
LakePoint
Things like log overseas
Best
Lunch
Okay
No
Ashley
Book about
Walk the log
Episcopal
Pizza and see what you
Charles look like that and once you tell
Cheap eye glass.
These terms hat will be will have your pride distribution is
List me true that I have my PSP Vita
Some of those is this walking
The Lord's eyes
Being
Coming from hair
Point
Armstrong
Assignats 2
Feisty
Micellaire
Is
Why am I writing Miss Alaska remind you of what we did last time and remember size that
We are interested in is something we can write down
And we can ride on almost the whole law
Except usually this normalizing cousin Pat is complete pain in bum
Because you actually write them that we would need to do an integral
Sigma
Play Popeye the gravy summation of April fees as well
You got this
But it is just a single constant
Just one number
Stop
What we notice about this distribution that we are interested in
We noticed we can compute it except normalizing consul
Song not going to define the rules of the game apply
When was stealing
Rules of the game
Probability distribution that were in president
And it's going to be cold pay
And it's going to eat Pista
/ zet
The rules of the game are
That we
Evaluate
Please stop
And secondly
We don't know that
Call Empress
Tell us that we would be delighted to
No it be call
Remember what was that so this is what we needed to do if you want chicken pad.
Did you like that with the one that says the 7 plus you need to know this moment
So
Return about right piece.
We don't know that we love to know it but will
Be playing if we don't end up
Goal of the month
In general I'm not going to generalize it's a good thing
This thing here in this case the unknown parameter assignments
I'm going to get that a name is going to be cold packs from now
This is the thing
The unknown
Variables
I'm going to call X why is the name
Texas the names of the unknown mean to send deviation
Assignment
Major points
Two Costas
Stop
What else to say about the rules of the game
What we actually want to know
Regardless probability distribution we are interested in
We can evaluate it that any particular
Any particular
Argument so you can pick an axe I'll be trying to go that
Lugging that value
Call
I'm workout
Well
What we want to do is solve these two problems
So just to recap notation we could have read distribution and I always write the nasty distribution in red
Red
Have you written without loss of the minus key of x / 10
I was just take you to log off Pizza
So the assumption is that we can if I were a pizza or we can evaluate
DMX
Child allergy attack smiley
And to ideally
We would like to draw samples from this
Dusty distribution
What does that mean
That means I want to take this posterior distribution and come up with some plausible representative
Obit
I want to know what the means
That's just one
Right now when I say I'm drunk samples please don't get confused growing point in this
It's
Taking a risk taxes now the name for
The date was given its fixed and I was wondering around
Pasta station
Coming up in sample from the posterior distribution
From 2 is
We would like to estimate the expectation of sanctions under this distribution
What do I mean will it give you an example
Let's imagine that were very interested in knowing
Weather
The characters
Well written by the same scribe Illinois results
Right
So what would that mean you want to know
That means you want to know
2 datapoint
The N1
And end points
Lavezzi
Or not
We don't know but give him the date that we can infer
So what we want to do is take the posterior probability
Call timer thing
We want to know that average
Averaging over Theatre
Coming over
Barry Simon we want to know
High probability that this proposition is true
Walmart Pharmacy
We want to know the average under the function which is wrong when the two
Is there another one if we can compute this
Expectation hat
Tell me about the answer to the question
So what am I saying I'm saying that the question how probable is it that these two seas are the same
Can be written as an expectation
Another thing you might want to know if you're doing clustering
Is
You might want to know
How probable is it
One of the means
Is somewhere in this is is in this box
And again you can introduce function that is wrong when the meat is in the average
Under the table
Questions that you have
And usually be expressed as expectations
Questions office wall
What should I believe about this variable
Given the data
Generalizing that General puzzle minimum distribution and they give you some functions
Average value state
And now we can forget about clustering
Just in case you don't care about my strength I'm going to give you one more problem that can be expressed in this way
Let's train
I'll give you another problem physics
Problem of understanding
Is nanotechnologies really cool
So let's say you come now I'm like this
And you got
A theory of what the energy of being anemic
The energy depends on the state of all the things in your nana Market
So that's cool X the state of Atlanta Market
And let's say the time is not a magnet
Made out of 10 by 10 by 10 Spencer's only a thousand
Honey
Oh maybe it's a planar object made us Russia x 32 spin
House in Spanish
And we gonna sell
An energy function which is the energy of those things if they're in
What might that look like
Well maybe it's a nice simple not a magnet
You energy
Singles couplings between thighs
Call
Spence
Each of these
Texas takes on the valley the - 1 + 1
I'm so ex lives in space mice long
Anne Bonny pirate
I may be DMX
Given the couplings J between spins on the
Convert temperature Ibiza
Is 18 - 3
/ depends on pizza
And the coupling where the couplings
Box determine the couplings jj72 energy in the fall
Find and Prime
Coupling J and and Prime text and
So that's a fairly standard expression for
The energy of a magnet with
Subnautica
And what sort of things does someone wants to know about that Nana magnet
Well they might want to know what's the average Energy Office thing
Under the distribution T distribution T and read vs read
He is radon's nasty
Cufflinks
Lookout Valley high standards
But it does not say because I actually if I tell you I got his a couple of Matrix what is the average energy
You'll struggle to answer you could try to do if I complete enumeration
If you wanted to do my completion you might have to do some over all values of x
Red
And
That would be the opportunity
But to do that you would have to some over to Sitar and state switches to supply 1000
State
PewDiePie 1000
Is
Let's put it this way
Imagine that you had access to all the electrons in the universe
10 to the 80
Electrons in the Universe imagine that you might have to send every one of those electrons into a powerful computer
I'd like to do operations for you
I know you have the entire age of the universe to do it then
The age of the universe
Is that the truth of time 98 seconds
2 to the 266 Electronics
You have every single life in the universe age of the universe
Is operations you must like those two by each other and see how many operations you can do
Pick some up
Allstate 10 by 10
So you can do this even though the energy is a very simple thing
So that one thing you might want to know another thing you might want to know if I can get his hands in it
Its energy so you might want to have a variance of the energy or currently average energy
If you know both of these fluctuations are an interesting thing to know that
So you might want to know that
You might want to know what the mean magnetisation
The magnet
What's a very intimate magnetisation so you can find the magnetisation in some way
Function you invented
Play I am interested in knowing is mean or is variance
You might want to know the entry of your nana magnet than that is the average of log
1 / p
You might also want to know that
Bruno Mars in concert
Because that is very exciting you don't have to
The mothers that is essentially the free energy
We Energies
Property
Things like these as well
Can Ole be expressed
In times of exit expectations
Expectation
Find the ethical the log deadlifting in it as well that is roughly the average of the energy
So
That's the second example
Call
Problems that we have
Probability distribution
The energy can be evaluated
Easy thing to do but the entire distribution
A difficult think I'll give it to you and I
What's a typical States samples show me 10 random samples
And just look at it
And random samples from the sea
Final thing to note is we want to solve problem
Both of Interest
The salt problem to which is to know the expected values opening
If you have sole can you use that as a way of solving problem to
If you walked so problem to
Can be sold
Because
Someone
Gives you
Some point I'm going to go get your label within a random sample if they give you a set of capital
XR
Which do really come from Moonachie distribution paid because you have souls program War
Then
You can
Estimate
Expectations of function for example if someone says what is the average value of FX
On the p
Expected value
Time estimate that by saying
Well I'm going to ride down hat pass
I'm just got.
Through all the points that you just given me in this random set
I got to see what the mean of that is
Honda
Empirical distribution
And that means any functions app
I can just take you the are random places you give me and I can estimate
Expectations
Using those are points in the bigger RS
The better those estimates will be
Play Someday We'll be to the true value of the expectation
So that means
It's a great trip.
Message will solar Pokemon
Things went by there on the screen
We are not trying to find the most probable State the goal of these masconomet is not to say
What is the state that minimizes dentist
We don't want to do that
You might want to do that if you how to do motivation
You don't want to know what is beam
Most rural States
And for the assignments of points to clusters and where the means go we don't want to know
Assignment
Like remember last time
Make some cow seems like this the most probable way of assigning points to me
It's disabled all of these are in
Flights to NOLA
It's not
Call Sababa allocations where these guy tails
You're being
So not trying to find the most probable state
Your is the purpose of problem wall
To visit
Allstate's we're not going to try and exhaustively new Rachel States and in some random way
Because that would take the lifetime beautimous
When visiting all states not even visiting oil typical State because
Still have two to the very last number
States
I'm trying to be clear what we want to do in the morning
I see what we're trying to do it would be brilliant if we could just roll say it doesn't point
Call my baby
Call Pops
Any size are probably doesn't matter if it's very very hard
Zillow you need in order to estimate
Expectations of functions
Alpine Ski
What's
So let me know
Show you some elements
Is Adventure introducing green things in green things
Navigate to work
Thumb problem I can show on the screen which means the main going to be one-dimensional problem
So care is
In red
A probability density curve apps
I'm not in bed
Which is what you would get if you're stung the girl hundreds of pets
Summer
So we don't know who's that
All we have is the ability to
Take a Valium
And then the computer will speak out
Value
Pictures of the misleading the real world of a month colorful
What is Pista
Then you go somewhere else
You have the ability to evaluate by which is a function of interest and have 5 Active
A linear function
Call Pat
It could be could be
I'm over going to do is
Progressed through the secrets of steadily Monte Carlo
Delta blinds Supply in Culpeper the blanco person is not going to be around by some random numbers in Subway
And they're going to take the blindfold off and CP.
I'm going to get you grounded
ICP start again and somehow the goal is that these extra random numbers that we used
Take them around
Actually help them answer problems longhunter
Getting a blind man to run the numbers help them appreciate the big picture
That is the beauty of Monte Carlo
What I just showed you with a p that was just finding a real valued
SpaceX
We could
Licensing place
Prepaid with 2000
Volume
And you can
And then you can go somewhere else
Values of Pista
This is a simplified depiction of
Okay
I'm going to stop by
Introducing
A proposal distribution
Oris sampler density
He's going to be the uniform distribution
So what we going to do is going to say
Let's assume that we can draw points uniformly
Rolex
I'm going to use that ability to then discuss
Solving problem to
But maybe we can find the expected value of pi
So what I'm telling here is our role in yellow
How is my cousin random points in yellow
And then what we can do points
We can write down an estimate
All
Function
Is a
Nasty distribution rash
Simply distribution HQ that we cannot see drool points
Sample identity has the
Wrong
EQ Michaelis
When we drop points from Q something you could imagine doing
Is finding the average of all of these functions
So as we drool
Random point buy at Lowe's
If we just invested average / then what were you doing
Is finding the average of spy
But it should be the wrong thing
I understand we would get it fix it up
8 point
In the ratio of
Sophia Valley Way. East Point
Askew
Do there is well into the uniform distribution wolfychu's will just be
Send
Replacing points in places where Q is too small of a Down Wiki
And I said to you but I think he started thinking about it right
And then we need a different nobody customs
And something you can pass yourself off as such
I know magic will do the job is the sum of all of these plates
Puppy Starbucks
CEO of Exxon
So what I'm doing here is
In general called
Importance sampling
So we chondrule points from t
If we could then we would have a way of solving problems
Are we doing says we draw from a different distribution the weekend Reliant from and then we correctly relatable
Correct sport using the wrong
And that gives us an estimator all
Is the truth
Shopify
Is the true average value
Just think about this
Excuse
Say what is the expected value of
Hee Haw facts
I would sum function Spotify
Next expected value office
When you drool points from 2
Answering the question that work the expected value
One of these terms hat
Expected value of P star that saw
Play vacuum
X fi Alexa
That expected value is the integral off that thing under Q
What is integral
Please stop
Pyrex which is apartment
So that's a justification for why this we waiting at the right
What we have on the screen here
Is
The estimate
Gratifying
Apple pie hat as the number of samples increases the top graph is showing
Increase from wall up to 50
What happened to the estimate
Uniform distribution that you can use this formula
For any distribution so for example we can make the green distribution the symbol distribution
I got you
And is a green gas in like a week but I got like an drawer joints
Call Daniela
Define
As a function of the number of samples
And you can do this with any width of gas in July
So you could take a very narrow Gaskin
Jessie
F i
Something you might realize is that if it was meant to be on the registration
Most of the registration is hat a none of the elephants actually visited that
This is actually completely wrong
Novus way of realizing that because
Pushing the blind man Iran takes off his blindfold
How you look city season 5
We telling this magic ways to be wasting by
I promised him the eventually if he does is provide a long time we give him enough points are
Then he'll eventually get the right answer
Well that's a very dangerous thing to do, because obviously you could
Just keep visiting places in you might never visit the places where
The red caboose
Remember to go I said it would be fine if it doesn't
El Paso
That was for solving problems
Using
Wrong distribution
I'm sorry
The number of points required for this could be absolutely no it just depends how close
Green distribution is the registration
And it is very narrow or if it's in the wrong place
It will take forever
Is Metro distribution and now you draw 51
One of the themes of
Lecture on Simple Man, it will be
That the month, may have some sort of guarantee that it will work well as our gets big
But you have no way of knowing I do run the algorithm whether it is actually giving you the right answer yet or not
Is a graph showing for those four distribution so we just played with in Greece fix the red
Mission
We went through a green distribution uniform than one Gaston & Gaston
This shows the estimate that you got most full mattress
As the number of flights increased from Guam
50 draws from the greatest
I need to see the old bumbleride
Volume
From the others
So what would you say if you run this experiment
Call Andrew just don't know any of these you don't know
The value that begin to look talk and completely change the let's run it for bit longer
R2000 decorations
This is what happens
So all of them wander around 11
Three-button moms are settling down on something
Because
It managed to hit a place where.
Naruto
Please change
This formula may have Samsung Direction behind it but it doesn't come with a health warning the health warning should say
Please wait could sometimes be almost infinitely large
When you use this formula for only re
Because you haven't included
Point
How much is 11 pesos
Neverside Maybe
Yes sir the comment is if you see some shoes way it's an indication that you could have died distribution
So does that help you you could have got you something I keep an eye on the way to see if any big weights
Just rewind a moment when we don't you think
That's just the fact that it wasn't any big weight doesn't mean but everything's fine
Business
Must Implement, is always a nervousness that no matter how many
Messages looking like it's okay it could be that you all just something from complete
Eventually applicable come along
Finally that is in the typical set
You can keep an eye on the variance of the weight lover of a movement of the way and that may help you
But you can't get any guarantee you that you're in.
Next
Let's talk trash
Rejection sampling
The rejection sampling uses a
Sampler
Which is simple enough that we can draw samples from it
So we have the same
Master distribution t
The assumption is
Can we have a simple distribution cute
So which we have a mathematical proof a guarantee
That we really know
That
3 * Q
Is everywhere
Biga Pizza
So the assumption is that somehow you have been able to prove that
Is Grayson Dolan or equal to
East Arvak's everywhere
And assuming that is true
Send
We draw points from cute
Anytime you draw a point
We also drawer
A vesicle coordinates
So the algorithm is like this
Rolex from
Jewelry uniform variable
From uniform distribution
It goes from 0
Times to All Pets
So that means having drawn the next from the screen distribution
Say yeah
Revente give me a uniform
That could come
3 fu is less than pizza
Switch the line Pokemon
Then
Accept
Text
Except mean that we spit this out and we put it
In the bucket
Contains all about EX
Otherwise
Rejected
Amsterdam rejection sampling
Let me just throw it away if you don't put it in the bucket
Serum
Points to get put in the bucket 6 drawer from
Victoria Lee
So what I'm done
Tara Strong
50 samples
From the green distribution
Everyone
Uniformly distributed between the horizontal axis
The green light
That means that all of those points needed in blue or yellow
Area
Under the green cup
That's what this construction give you that warm
That gives you a point he's going to text you
Our uniform under the green cup
Then if you use scissors and you cut out all the ones that are colored blue under the red cup
Those points must be uniformly distributed in the area
Throw away all the other one, exactly
Brompton registration
And it's absolutely crucial that it must be true
It's bigger than
Play Store
Because
It's not true as shown by
This example of point to pretend that you're doing rejection sampling
You will reject the other points of the distribution you are actually drawing Point call its substrate
Change distribution
Cream of chicken
So it's crucial that you must be stopped
Alopecia reason complicated distribution this understand
It may be a very difficult
True that you have colic you for which this is true
It's not just that you have to know that it's true for some say you have to say that it just repurposed
Need that seat
X c
Beautiful number
Okay
Okay so the comment is it's very easy to check
Whether SECU is bigger than the places where you actually Drew
I'm at signature
So you could
Check
Los angele
Broad point you but also see if you had a good warm
Glenwood
Sorry if you would equal
60 * 2
Would it still be left in peace.
So yes you can check if you really want us there on this has
If you run this algorithm School long enough
You'll get the right answer
I'm so just checking in
Okay interrogan is the estimate of the expected value
The message restore are we still using
Importance sampling
And then in green answer for rejection
Throwing from the stretch
Distribution
You can see it
It's settling down as well in the same way as the other three
Okay are there any questions about
Sampling or
Rejection sampling
How to draw simple cute cute the assumption is that shoe is a distribution that we can draw
So
In a real space in my P I got you
In a case of the spins the sort of thing you could use for Q might be
The distribution where the end spins in the magnet
Just flips a biased coin of some sort to decide whether
Then that's a very easy distribution to draw
You might use
Navigate distribution that doesn't have strong correlations in it
It does have correlations in it among variables
That's simple enough that you can still
Rejection sampling is wonderful and usually you can't do it
They'll be two reasons why you can't do it either you can't think of it
Such that SECU account
Call if you can come up with such a
Have a proof of this property
It may be so much higher than the TV that you end up rejecting every single point running
Navigate
Maya
Come the Reckoning
Okay so that's the sad truth about rejection something unless you're very lucky or very clever
You would make a test
In one-dimensional, like the ones we had on the screen just now
Japan realistic approach
The message we're about to discuss
Metropolis
Is you can't have two projections of the component in those
So let's move on now I'm talk about the Metropolis message
Send a message we looked at so far
How much kilometers
The blindfold man
Was told to go to a random place
Moving around
In a way
Where every move
Is independence
Avenue locations
The Metropolis method
It's going to be an example of a Markov
Chain
Which means that instead of asking
The blind old man
You go to a new location
Independence Square
There is now going to be a dependent on where he is at the moment so wherever he is now
We're going to move him to a new location
The depends on his current location
Why you should not help is not at all clear that is why do we want that to be a dependents
That's what we're going to do
Try
Well this is the next location
And this is the current location
I need something is going to be that we can draw from here
Becky was going to be something simple like a gasoline distribution or flipping Bank on
Resume that we can evaluate
We have an Icee distribution
Red
Shoes
It look like
This is the current location
Listen to current location
Then maybe you might look like
That's the sort of concept rehab Maybe
Choose just a distribution that send it on the current location and put those things a little bit
It can be any distribution you lie
As long as you can draw from it and you can evaluate it so you can think of that you as being completely General
Distribution
That you can draw from this is the sort of thing that people use
Is a small nudge to decide
Perhaps a big nuts could you say broadcasting if you want
Any distribution that you can draw from
So it's okay
But used to be
Simple or complicated
And something to imply to
Is
It's okay but you
Knox
Look like me
Importance sampling
Rejection sampling really well it's cute looks just like me because then you're done
If you can make it to that looks like pee and you can draw from it
Then that means you can solve the equation problem.
In the Metropolis it's okay.
It could be
Completely different so it would be okay
Abiquiu
Like this and it looks like
And that's not going to be a problem
Typical property that she was actually going to have
Is going to be the typically shoe just makes a small change in the energy of the sea
It is going to work
Then
Usually
Makes
Just a small change
The energy
How does you being logged.
Smol meaning
Okay
Distribution were granted replying from depends on the previous state
So how does the algorithm work
It's kind of like
Thyme tea
We Alright location XP
Can we do the following
Generate
A new point
From effects
Compute something
Tells us whether we want to go there or not which is the acceptance ratio
And a looks a lot like the
Things we had an important something about just going to have a Pista
Display
It's going to be divided by
Acute
This place
That looks just like a waste of Haddon
But we also need to take account of what weight is in the place
What would come from still take a piece out of XT
I will take the corresponding chewy says if we will
Annex and we drew from
This place hexes
Shoe distribution
How likely is it that we come back to NXT where we are at the moment
So we work out
Ball sack
How big to of XT is assuming that you stop
Yeah
The question is
Do we need to know the normalizing constant
And the answer is well no not necessarily both of these cute I have
The same normal I can come see each other
Then you don't need to know
On the other hand it
Call Chu house the pool
You saw that
And that's that depends on this argument hat
Then
You do need to know this hats
In general
That's the nature of that it will in general have an XT dependents
But it does
Zedd
At least you know I need to know this that religion some
All right
This is what we do
If we ignore the acceptance ratio then all we would be doing is something to run the world
It wouldn't be looking at the atoll
Never looking pistol
Set 3 is where the blank old man will look at Pizza
Those that leakage of information is going to like you
Exactly
Then we accept
Otherwise
Whitsett with probability
Hey
Inspiration
Now what we mean by except
Except means
Reset x equal to
Sorry about that.
If we reject on the other hand
Which is what we do if we don't
Either of these tests
If we were Jack then what we do is we set XP + 1 equal to
XT so you repeat we stay where we are
We reject the proposed move
How we stay where we are
And in this way we create a list
What's algorithm
Ask Polly mobile
Step step step step
Step
Same same place same the same place
Same same place
Stay the same place
Stainless steel plate
And this is generating .01
I want the point of that you might have
Bunch of that
Isotopically
Is
Sounds like caca
So let me show you
Rolepoint Staten topically
Will be coming from the red distribution
And I'm going to start a novelty .02 Top Ramen doesn't matter where it is we're going to run this thing for a long time
And what we do is
We stopped at that point
Mike shoe is always going to be a Galaxy and sent it on the carpet
And it shows
In Our IT services the X
Just done
Then we evaluate p
The new location
And we say what the ratio of P of the new location
At the current location
And by symmetry but you choose canceled
Proposal
Distribution
So these shoes are going to be the same as each other
How big is a Galaxy in
Send it on me at you
How big is the galaxy
This place at your place
And those are
By symmetry the same as the ratio of these P what is it
Tea at the new location is bigger than 2 years
Current location
Generation X
Now we draw from Augustine send it on that point
Close the small set right
And it's Mula
So will it be accepted or not we don't know we have to draw another random number
Send coin with a biased essay
Is it acceptable and the answer is
Yeah but then Connie came out had to accept
We make another drawer next to
It takes a bit so we're going to accept this definitely
Lights
Now it's going down by big fact we've already started this new location
And the ratio is about
Wanted to tell
Glass of 50% chocolate what happens
Except
Go again
No change in peace I will accept that
So that was five steps of algorithm in every single set accept it
Which means that essentially we were just doing a random walk
On the Q
But if we run it for longer
Then you can see some rejection love each other
So you can see we spent more time in places where.
And we didn't do so much rejecting if I slap you with smoke
The decision to reject moves
When you are in places where people take us to get more samples
If you run this thing
Trinity long
And then pick one pointy place at the very end
Many types of point
Thumbs
Distribution is ever closer to the registration
I love you Rhonda
So that's a beautiful property
At least with a lot of question marks though you don't know how long to run this thing so
Anjappar menu
As well
When you run it
N&d if you keep on running it for longer than substance
Independently
The probability distribution of any one of them
If you have enough
Okay
I'm not going to
Tell you about
Get something
I'm just sampling is
A
Michael Shane Macaulay method
Which only makes sense if we have two dimensions
So what I'm going to talk about now is a problem that has two Dimensions namely
The inference of the mean and the standard deviation or gas station
Given n points
I've got you
So how does get something work
I'll be done in 5 minutes
Sampling
This assumption is Mississippi
Miss you
That even though
T itself is a redfish distribution
Who assumed we can
Sample
Chrome
Conditional distributions
Long
These Dimensions conditional on Ali Abbas Sophie is a nasty red thing
Some complicated
Shape
The assumption is that
Slice a bit hippy
Text to XOXO at 5
And just let me let you draw from this conditional distribution
Andro4all trx-1
Even in the case of us
Problem weather of two variables
Stop somewhere
Drool
Text ones you value from the conditional distribution of X1 given x 2
It's cheap
Lindru x + 1 value of X2
Devon you value so you take the new value
And then
How you do it with the two variable pay variable
You just Cycles are you doing each of them from his distribution conditional
Assumption that you can do this but there are examples where this is quite easy and the cast
Is a good example outfit
If I give you some data is Phi Beta Sigma
The answer to that you can
And you right. It's a dependent
Distribution where
Call hosain concentric
Looks like
But any slice through this is fantastic
Even though this is a dependent distribution slicing misdirection
Sliced in this direction
Denisa Gamez
Unreasonable
And as long as you have a piece of software that controls distribution you can do each of these steps
You want then the other one
In red I'm showing you what the distribution Happy Looks like that multiplying whole plan cost
Rochester
I'm showing you in Texas pay this looks like
Cassian with meaning
And then you tell him okay update you by drawing it from the gasoline distribution
Which
Leaving Sigma fix to this road value
He can draw from that guy
What's the conditional distribution mean
Given Sigma
Nazi swastika
And then the second step
Is update Sigma
I need Rosa from gamma distribution
And that changes the
Standard deviation from the volume randomly
Penny value
Tell me update to me
Me and
And there's a dependence between
Every other set i'm highlighting in yellow when we come through
Norfolk running and you can see and yellow what was happening
Is a summary of what happened
Surround
Disappearance this is a metropolis message
No
You can do this
A whole range of models
And the mobile that we discussed
In the previous life why we believe Satan comes from
A mixture of Gaskins
Siletz now change station
Is a new dataset
Fishing points
Can you conceive it looks like
And then maybe there's a protocol
If we insist on saying there is only one gas can then we can use
The
Get something method to draw from the posterior probability
Look at the whole bunch of theories about you and sigma silica
That's something else we can do is we can change them
Is it Asia
Yeah we have
Denote
What plug is it sometimes
I'm representing now about to dance to
I hope this is the two of them
And yellow and orange
Some of these two guys in Hawaii
That's what you get when you have those two
The dates are shown in blue
And then in orange and yellow I'm showing which point to be analogous to which
Vacations
And now what we do is we're going to alternate between
And we will call
Signing
Just like it's okay me
So we can chat using give something
We're going to do is follow this
Industrial air
Update me the sun deviations in this way in this way
And that corresponds to
Assigning
Eration
We look at 3 p.m.
We update on me to the standard deviation using the gasoline distribution
Appropriate Army
Given the points that happiness is be just like in the previous Batman
I'm up safety standard deviation using a guy
Each of the costumes does that or sell
I'm Amazed by working out the
Responsibility but you accusing
Just looking at those socks responsibilities
You actually draw from the band coin with those points
Make a penny coin
I belong to you now
So you can see at least
It's time to change it
Orange
And then
Mister yellow
Orange
Hansford
Fungi
I'm just now exploring weho
The posterior distribution
On this
Really is
Sorry I missed your Gaskins
Prom date
YouTube this is you can do it
They're usually bitter taste to have any positive
Grow exponentially with you
The number of me
Up doing
K means clustering and it doesn't suffer from some of the defects
Get something
Is essentially a randomizer
That's something you can notice is in a green I'm showing what the average is
Stimulation
It said that reading is the answer to the question
Please predictable me where the next point the 14th
Green line is a very nice prediction
Listen to run it for a very long time
You would see a split happening every now and then the moment Mr yellow is the cost of is usually responsible
And doesn't equally probable hypothesis oranges or something for them
Edit the other way around
Logically it must be able to get to that around
Mystery run it provides another 15 minutes
Then you'll see it
Probably Rick Ross
Between those two exclamation
Okay
I'll leave it running on the end of it
First lecture on Monte Carlo methods
All that any
Questions.
Okay so the question is
What about if you wanted to know how many classes The Rock if you want to know how many clusters
You would have to
Represent
Poster distribution all
Weather news
That is a much harder thing to work with because essentially it has to include that normalizing
Mustang Monte Carlo method
They don't tell you the normal I think I'm not get your tit but if you wanted to answer question
These methods
Revealed
That almost color method
Estimate
Correctly play transition
These things exist
They are much more respected
Come along next time and maybe we can
Meet
Next lecture let me just tell you where it where we going
So I'll show you a demo get something
The web genie
Halfway through
This particular set of Monte Carlo method
And the message was showing you served three important problems
Call T-Mobile Challenge number for 3 challenges around
Michael Chambers
So what we would like his message but have less running Behavior
The methods tend to be sensitive Stepside so when we are using
But while it's dirty make small changes but that means it makes more sense between debate
Very slow progress you'd like to take biggest that you always reject
I said problem with everything we've seen so far as we don't know when to stop you don't know when we run it along enough
We have reached
And all three of a problem
Fishing methods Behavior
Rid of sensitivity
The step size
And we're going to discuss a method called exact sampling which is Amazing Grace written
Taking some must not be being able to approve of recite this point is a correct drawer
So exact something is up a really huge breakthrough