Welcome to 11
Repeat
Information Theory
I'm interested in a moment different ways of doing
Modeling
I want to remind you where the website is on the website
Free
I'm just to tell you a little bit about
In the next stop talking about multicolor method is a little
Encyclopedia of interesting multicolor matters. We will go through
Plaza
Motivation interested in Calabasas
About
As an example of an inference
I'll give all the motivations about you have to have electron clustering
I just gave you an abstract concept
Problem
Reset
I want to know what the exponential
Asian cockroach
Mixture of two exponential
Exhausted
Enumeration
Hypotheses
Homemade pancakes
I'm over all the parts to the two
Credentials
Made a slip last time I mentioned that I did I have to change the rules
At the window
Freret Street
So now we're about to discuss clustering our kickoff with a little exercise which is
Information theory noisy Channel
Question
And it goes like this channel
Who won
And then what channel is a real number y
Why is Cassian around 1
Call me to
Depending
Channel
If you want to know about the capacity of the channel
Which is
You use this channel
The prior probabilities of the two possible values of a
Charlie's used once
Why
What is the posterior probability
Please
Look up
As a function of Y I'd like it in the form of a woman
Habitats United
Okay
We're right on Bayes Theorem
Russell
Why is
Like a Mac
Volume is on my rule
Possible values
When you rearrange that into 1/4 -
Where is my name for
Damn why
Is I can grind it out long time history longhand version
Taiwan
Lawgiver
Hi ratio
One of the √ 2 pi Sigma squaresville cancel out sodium
Where is it be interesting
Why didn't the fish
And if you want to be elegant you can remember
I like that you
Elegant way of writing this
Hey
As a function of Y
Is something linear function
Like this
M1 and M2
Why
Find a is a measure of
Winit
Remind me to
Probability that X is long why
Look something like this
Straight line
This is the place where the two products
Prosthetic little bit 75050 is here
Applied
Send it
Life estate
Okay any questions
Rabbit
So if I tell you I'm going to use this channel then the output of the channel
Why is a real number whose probability distribution is a mixture
Jesse Owens
Guy looks like it might look like
So why do you care about me so well
We might be
Grecian
You might be interested
Is Buddy Foster Street entrances
Play with now I'm going to show you some
And we'll see how that
Inferences to do with me
So it's a real data just to remind you what we might actually talk about if you're doing real clustering
Frequency of speech
Find Great Oaks
Volume
Rent A Streetcar the picture and then you want to recognize which get you guys
Which babies do in the language
Listening to these references coming out
I made it over and over
K means clustering
Hey
The number the number please
Differentiation
So let me show you
Hangman solver
Where is resume
Awesome date real values
As an example maybe when making an automatic vegetable sourcing
I'm not going to use text Walnut x-23
Real numbers
Change notation
So what we measure is X1 and X2 and maybe a whole bunch of other
These are measurements made by our automated vegetable measuring machinery
Maybe X1 is reflections
I may be a few is a vegetable
So his house memes
We take all the data we've seen so far
Search LinkedIn
Float down in this world
Texel hey hey object story
Red Lobster
How many police means I mean to initially
You just let me down anyway you like
Initialization set weather report on TV
Finish Line K means
Hey hey
Brenda
At step one
Step to it
We assign each of these datapoints
The nearest
Is
Find a distance to measures how close you are
Distance here is going to be
MK - x at
Not the distance
Young ball
So
We assign each point to the nearest
Ridiculous
Send
Call Lisa Lisa closest to
Another way of saying what happens when you sign them is we could introduce
Thinkful responsibility
Define how responsible he chased me is for the endpoint
By saying
Well it's on its places to me that I'm responsible for it I have walked
I'm just giving you a new piece of notation
Responsibility
Guam if NK is the closest
Extant
Otherwise
Another way
Responsibility is wrong
Hey minimizes with respects
All right
Let's go ahead and do this on the screen with an example
I'll grab some beta
Disappoint turning green
And now we slap in Maine have an issue we were all clapping to
Random Orange
Green
Navigate to say who you closest to
Culinary tastes like oranges
Agreed
Step 3
Update to me updates that works like this
The me number one
The meaning of the datapoint
Guam
Omca in general
That sets to the sum
Divided by the number of points that you can write that responsibility
Famous coming over
The end
Don't you mean
So like that again
And let's do it so we update
Tumi
In orange green to be the me
And then we repeat so you go back
Goshen 200-piece
Until nothing happens anymore
What do you do again
Is it sunset
Update to me
And I repeat
Reassign
And I will update
Naira sign
Play update
Westside
Update
Update nothing is happening anymore
Stable state
Change
Last minute random sign up date
Okay sign
If you want something for me
Update
I'm not sure if you could do whatever you want and something happens
Oregon
Sing for me
Sign up date
Alright fine
Update
Find the same
OLS
Strike War again
Listen to memes
Fish line
Update
Daylight
Do it again
Noches.
Grey orange
Boundary of that
Something you may be starting to feel already as I'm not sure like I mean
Assign
Call me
Another one
Lost messages coming through that you can run pay me to find some trusses for you it will give you a stable and say
The insider time call random initialisation
I may be some insight
I take
Let's take it that I'm seeing if you can makeup
Like scabies even less than we do at low-hanging is already quite
A widely used algorithm
So let's pick some different salads
Dataon made
Which if you ask a human they might say yes
They said haha we have a clustering algorithm
Talk to me at random
Like what we had in mind right
You mean
Green guys going grabbed a few guys if you really want
Really doing what
Try one more time
Okay that's not quite idealism
We can always try using bull
Me at all at 7 instead
This how I got wonderful
I don't know. Maybe the road is that
I still don't answer yellow cluster
Chinese food
I have to be
What should we look at next let's switch stages at one more time
And I'll show you
This song
So ask human how many classes are there in this time
Okay
Find
Update
Sign up date for sign up date
Beautiful
It's time.
Okay to do it again
Bygone
Okay
So it's not a million miles
Improve it
What if you normalize Checotah okay
What is normal life according to me
Take me to a certain before you get it to the stupid algorithm
All right
Imagine doing that
Play something relaxing
Instead of
Flying with you and giving you your normal eyesight today just at the one that looks like
Okay
Still got it right
Maybe not quite as badly as this one
Let's not let's have a different
Tree tree modify the algorithm
Let's give it an interpretation because actually it's too perfect
Hallowell Define probabilistic
Mainly if you think of this
Distance
The thing that is in the Easton lineup
Misting hat
What is algorithm
Is it corresponds to
Assuming that the data comes from
A mixture of pee costumes
They all have the same
Call with the same
Variance
Not the same in all directions
Historical
And then
The final assumption is it they all have the same privacy I want equal to
Hi hey
And then the algorithm we're running here is a a
Greedy algorithm that is
Define precisely what it's doing it's coming up with
The points
It's been doing Elvis thing with me which is finding us or mocha
Maximum
All right
Is roughly
Map maximum a posteriori
Algorithm
The
Science variables
Wish we could call Cayenne
Which pasta
So as to maximize
Call C
Science
Sebastian interpretational
Interpretation
I guess we can say
Oh my God
It will be tonight
I'm maybe we can also how many change these assumptions had one two three
Maybe we can change its algorithm if you want to know the most probable
Credible
Cuz even if
I really do come to identical Gaskins
Eco crossover
Try putting memes in the right places
I will put my long hair meet you halfway
Then put your divider in
Allocate all of these guys
Prostitute
That what happens when you run the updates.
What's the meaning of this shaded law
Didn't write license on me to
Lost it
Golytely
So even in the case where all these assumptions are true the Mac Alberta
Ends up
Allocation is ends up in the wrong place
It doesn't quite like this because I'm at Izzy
Modify the algorithm
The Next Step
Is School
K means algorithm
Stop in the same way by initializing a meeting at random
Reset a Surface Pro
Everybody
Rita's naagin-2
Come and change our assignment group
Miss Simon.
So we sign lunch
Going to say r&k responsibility
Is
So in contrast to setting case the minimum
Minimizes men
So we're going to do this
Eat reminder Pizza distance from MK
Raja bike price
2 - Pizza
Rifling through
Possible Hayes
How close do you feel
If you feel like you're the closest little means then you'll end up with a woman
Central AC 3%
But you would
The team10 only if you set pika
Can you reproduce the old
Hawkeye mean
The new definition of d
Minimizing
Saira doing is
Suck meme
And you might recognize that this
Yep they roll meme cake
No change
Wait
Beach point
By how responsible you feel
Say what
If we do that
We have to take advantage of pizza
You promised Pizza in
Just tried setting it to all the values
Let's get help with these old points that we have to call
How many meetings would you like to talk to him
Zaful
I can't we pick about you pizza and I'm representing Pizza
Find the radius of a circle because one thing you would
Miss Fisher
Is that
Cre8 pop.
Tasty tasty
And imagine putting a / 6
Lisa
Moana
Standard deviation
Meaning
And I'm telling you how big the Beast
I'm sorry runs.
Update my fine fine
I'm telling you the color if you Simon is very strongly in favor of one me
And if it shows a pale blue that means this point is really cool
Sign
Update
Define
It can be a bit like watching paint dry
Hey what's up
24 memes
I hope your pitbulls
It's just an algorithm is doing something on yet
Try again
The same again for that but it didn't have to do that because we didn't have to give it
9five glasses
Sintomi
Know what I'm going to do is run me out of different values of preacher
Call start with B
The number to settle down a bit I'll just change Pizza
Small volume
Call
That means I'm starting take me to
Starting a big standard deviation
Send me a pic some deviations then gradually reducing the standard deviation every other
Change the sun TV
Justin's endogenous to keep on running the algorithm and I'm not going to try anymore
Run itself
Cool beans
All right
So that was a very large standard deviation
And they're all converging on one place that's a nice vacation if you like I only want one
FBI
So now we're Jesus and deviation little bit
Nursing program
Molars
Do that again
So that we have some paintings
Notation
It's obsession is receiving that
Is a mixture of controlling that
Probabilities are all the same still
Wait
It's nothing that meteor them anymore because we're doing softer signed so we fix this problem
Davis auctions
It will at lineman I just get a signal right you have the correct value Sigma that it will sign
Just the right way
And then when you do need update to me black panther place
Nice Italy
What we can do as we very Sigma brushes long as you can run through
Then what
Mac algorithm anymore maximizing
Roberts maximum marginal
Optimizing
With me
Assuming that
So we making a bit of progress slightly modified the assumptions of course it's still not well
Problems
Call
Love is
Chinese
Listen to me
Well
Garage Elite
Change the assumption
You want to exchange
Mainly we want to believe that
Potassium
Progress to Chinese
Solar lights on again
Call Tammy love
Doesn't just update to me
It also update
Avaricious
And going to redefine what distance is so sensible
Dependence
So I'm going to have a stigma
Instead of having a stiffness will have every Quest
Sigma k
You'll have to reach at least I mention which I haven't even given a name to I
I got someone to the number so I mentioned so that again
Going to have
Sigma variables for each of those dimensions
Station Gaskins might look like
Alright so we talked to in sickness
So the update rule
It's going to say well let's look at the various
Using my me
I will do that just on the ice dimension
Okay so there's a variance update rule
And we just run the same algorithm with the assignment now being the
Appropriate modifications
Eastbay
Linus
Some mobile dimension
So that's okay memes version 2
Say what we're going to say if you want to Line Tattoo
And it eventually I'm going to have the size changing as well so
Will initialize the pies to some sort of I don't have a bunch of people Pike a
It's always going to be the same except will my Kay's in hat
Hide ending algorithm the update rule that you look at how many points
Assigned to you
So how many am I responsible for
You update your way to say you will
So let's do that let's do it first
You mean
Let's try another day let us fight for me
Can you get it for me and it goes and finds
Still bad things can happen
Call Virginia. You tell it you want for me it'll find you before me
Everything
Compare is actually a variational method
At 4
Fishing EML Griffin
Fishing
Hey I just like asking
Play preschool algorithm
So let's change that status
Change to Leland Lodge
How many memes would you like to
2 memes
Mr. oranges
Flying Taxi
You can imagine having dated that there was a good hypothesis explained it
Optimization and it might be difficult to find me
Fight me
And it comes up with
Call
It's still a Survivor tree algorithm at least
Automatically handle
I didn't mention America when the whole screen something went like blue happened in that case
Was that one of the datapoint
Taken over by a single me
Well
It's where you can get update rule hat
If you feel very responsible
Daniel keep on updating the variance
What is one punch timer Costco
And you're very close to your date
But no one else is
Lowe's up and then that's why this week
This isn't
The end of the story of it can do kind of all things
Green thing is wandering off the screen position because of the Titan fight last night
Given the DPAC I just described it as possible so long mean
Go to 0 lose up with
How to instantly
It's surprisingly a reverse algorithm defect
Very rarely under the
Automatically
What does an inclusion in January new discoveries
Okay
So
That's okay mean
So your question is in what sense is this an optimization of the question
Okay
When return the variational method
Then we'll be able to answer
Aveda
Why should it
It does actually
An objective function
Variational free energy
Function notation
Any other questions
Okay so the question is wafted a tire is on a ring or some other type of dates of it
Well Detroit
Did you say
Please cancel that for me well that what you have done and if you use soft Amy the interpretation of
Using haggai
But don't have the same sickness
Weights on each other anymore
But that the interpretation of what you're doing and it's not surprising if you give that doesn't look like
Something will happen and you might not be very satisfied.
Download
Call Lynette
What will happen with the dates that like this is
My cat
David seven clusters in my 12th and 7 gas engine
You will get an answer which is
Is sometimes the best way of explaining this Asia one of the best way to explain
Call 7 cast
Universal
Solution is really hot!
That's something we could get through this post Maybe
Dimensional
Right so the question is could you change the metric
So here we can use each of the Lions Hall
You think I'm not motivated the algorithm if you like
Any distribution you like
Starset Evita -
Invent your own
And then all you're going to need this is a promise right thing with something like IBEW looking around it and
Maybe something like a sick my left
You can use that as your assignments that
Nugget in hair
Then you go to need to get for yourself
A new update which tells you what to do with your parameters
Probably if you change this from being something Quest
Then
Yes you can
What people actually do
I'm not that up-to-date with you during communication
I like to use a t distribution
Instead of casting
And then you need feel like outside
Matthias self is a mixture cotton wool having the same day but different
If you read the variational interpretation of this whole thing that will give you a spray work and what you
And then figure out an hour
Optimizer variation free energy adjust the timer
Okay
In the next
Multicolor Matt let's using this and some other problems as motivation to why we want