Falcon flight to 5
In the last lecture we defined symbol codes around theoretical and practical questions
About symbol codes
And
That gave us even more evidence for these claims which we've no proof sufficiently I'm going to take them
Trousseau the claim wasn't the right way to measure information content is with log
Base 2 of one of a p of an outcome that is not a measure of information
It is how many bits you should expect to be able to encode that out come into if you're using a good compression method
The enemy is the average of the information content
And the source coding theorem says
If you got a soul for them to pay hu kind of compress
And I'll come 210h bits
We looked at symbol codes we're without punctuation you give binary string strings of zeros and
The ones to each letter in your alphabet and we established
Some theoretical results of some of them without proof
So we came to an understanding of how unique dakotabilities constrains the length to come make a
Really short you have to if you make some length show that you have to make other length of your code words longer
We
It's just a notion of prefix codes that are easy to decode codes that are associated with binary tree's
I'm noticed that
If you had Cody length equal to the information content then you got the best possible compression and the average length
Pause symbol with entropy
And we stated without proof that with the optimal symbol code you can get with anyone bit
All of the entropy
And finally we
So the Huffman algorithm
Which is an algorithm extremely simple for making optimal symbol codes
So let's just recap plant with these examples
If the probabilities are
Huffman algorithm says combine the two split with smallest prevented hate you can take your pick
I give you 2/5
Combine the two with most probability
Can combine the two it's full again take your pick
And then combine these long and then by Putting Edge zeros in on the edges
We can Define codes this one is 0-0 this 101 coming on the tree
This is 100
This is why I'm there one
How this phone is
On one
Hwang what do I done wrong
Any questions
So let's do another example of the probabilities are proportional to 3/4
Hoffman says
Lyme disease
I'm combine these two six and combine these two got nine
And take the two sixes and you get 12
Then seven of the eight to make 15
Then what
Carefully retype the 2/9
Then who does 10 go with 10 goes with the 12
Introduce
And then the two smallest of 15 and 18
Stringy spit E350
And I slept on zeros and ones anyway you want and request a selfie optimal symbol code
Uncle by
Any questions
Yes sir the question was does the Huffman algorithm ensure that we got a prefix code and the answer is
Yes because when we put the labels on when making a binary tree
And
Where to find any code words from the root of the tree Atwoods what we will get is a prefix code there's no way
Play that one code word can be a prefix or another if that defined in terms of a binary tree
Algorithm always gives you a prefix code
And it's open
You can't make a vesa symbol code then wraps up
Impression
One thing you might ask Edition about prefix code is
Is it sufficient
To make a prefix code if someone said I've got a really coming idea I got to make a code that is not a prefix code
Then it's going to be back up can we prove that that is untrue
And the answer is
Yes we can prove it untrue by the following fairly simple argument imagine that someone has made a symbol code
Which they claim is wonderful and it's not the prefix code you say okay please tell me the length of all of y'all symbol codes
Starting with the shortest length
Up to the longest length give me them sorted by length
Then I'm going to go to the symbol code Supermarket which we introduced last time and I will walk across it
From one side to the other and I will buy the short skirt with first
And then having to move across to the next I'll buy some of the next length and so forth
With the shopping list that you have given me
As long as you have given me a shopping list that doesn't exceed the budget
The craft budget of Wong
Then I will be able to buy your lengths of
Of coats
And because I've stepped across
From one aisle to the next crossed maybe I should make clear what I mean so that I have to buy
To blank too many wanted wanted length free this one and then some rest
I would like for our biolase
As an example because I'm moving across and never overlapping with myself I'll end up with a prefix
Xcode
The only way you would violate the prefix property to the throne the same
Vertical coordinate
MySupermarket
All right
So
The Huffman algorithm is already ultimate it makes prefix codes so we didn't need to worry about this but it just in case
Play songs play me nah I want to do something clever not using prefix code well what's have expected length
They could have got with that non prefix code we can match that we can just replace that code by a prefix code
And the code I showed you for English hair was indeed
A code made with Huffman algorithm and it's a prefix code
So how we wrapped up compression by saying his how to make symbol codes on his how to make
Optional symbol codes for the rest of today I want to argue that we're not done with compression and the
It's because of this looking plus warm
High in the inequality
So
Are we done
No
Let me give you one really simple example
To justify this
An example we started with the band coin
Let's imagine we haven't been calling and it's two phases of cold A&B and let's say the high probabilities .99
1.01
And I compress it to using the symbol codes and you Catholic
Find the two symbols with smallest probability you can buy them in too long
Can you put labels on here and you say I will then code ia01 be as long as in that wonderful it's an optical
It's expected length
Is 1
And that is indeed
Close to the entropy which is 0.08 bits
Is within one bit of entropy
But it's actually about the Pac-12 bigger than the entropy
I just know depressing it's over cuz it's just taking a binary alphabet main coding it directly into binary
So that's a trivial example symbol codes for getting us where we really want to go
Simon says we should be able to achieve more than tenfold compression of that been calling file
So I'd like to know play a game with you
Help us understand the situations in which we might be dissatisfied about this plus one
That's looking in this
Inequality
So
The game is called the guessing game
But when I'm going to do is I'm going to write on the board
A headline
How many Cipher and I have to head line Roofing hair
In front of me
I don't get to write it with you I'll help
Because you're going to guess each letter of a headline as we go along
And if you guess the first letter correctly I'll write it down and I will tell you it's correct and then we can move on to the grass
II
Lhasa
All the headline alphabet of legal characters for this headline
Is on the board of ed
How to space
Remind me to finish the headline. I'll let you know so I'll Supply the
The.
The end of the headline
Okay
You can start guessing the first letter and I will right underneath this line all the guess is that you have made
That I'm not correct I'm going to right above the line it tells you that you've got the right left
So
Guessing time
Naughty naughty
Is not right
Keep guessing
Chinese rice
Next
He is wrong
Do you say a
Hey
I is correct
Next iPhone
No thanks
Nazi
It's not the L&I
Say again
It's not g
No I
I wouldn't say anything about Minnesota's
Not me
Space
It's not
Latte
There's no s
Naqvi
Milton
Nazi
Clopay not you
Nazi Nazi
Not a
No Thai
Yeah
Best
Space
Teeth
Oh
Space
North End
Don't pay
Nazi
Not be
W
Oh
Okay
It's not
No I
Lot w
Was that Seguin
Not ask
Not you
Naughty
Not me
Hey
North Face
Naughty
Not n
Is right
Okay I think I had someone say pee and it was wrong then I had someone which is right
Space
Not h
Nocatee
Hey
Take
Thanks and I'll give you the and the father
Reasonably refusing to work after that day
So there's a headline
And it involves you acting as expert English speakers and using your
Knowledge about English to make predictions
I would like you to know shift some things about the predictions
You made
The first thing is
I think you are well aware that your predictive distribution the predictions you would make at any particular point
Change depending on the context
So for example the second letter of your predictions
Vowels
Because she was struggling to think of
Things that could have come after end but we're not valves be good at being an aunt or something strange like that
So that example
And it was a context where you predicted K as your first choice where eyes in the generic
Location you say things like tea
A insightful
Stop your predictions depending on the context
And
That's because there are correlations in order English between the letters you are aware of what
Words and grammar insightful
So
I'm asking a question what's wrong with single codes we could just use the Huffman algorithm if we used it one side only
Play end of May the optimal Huffman code for the English alphabet
It wouldn't
Correspond to a changing probability distribution
How can we fix that well in principle you could fix that by saying let's run the Hoffman every time
So we'll have some soda process that emulates your expertise when we get to a particular context
We could
Then compress the next character using the probability distribution that is optimal for that contact
I make the Ultima single code and then send the appropriate next three bits or two bits or one bit
And the person on the receiving end could emulate. Process all also
Figuring out which
Huffman code which symbol code you are about to use for every kinda
They could do that but that sounds a bit of a fast
There is a problem
Which is that if the predictions are very precise you'll still be spending one bit for every character
So I'll write it down in just that I went what's my second issue my second issue is
That the context-dependent predictions
Volta change as you learn about
The style of the document that you'll compressing
They change we didn't really see this but the headline because it wasn't a very long document but if I'd said yeah his a headline
Started off and I said right after you made a lot of gas
May Fahrenheit for a haiku Katana way you would have realized it wasn't an English headline
He would have been started learning about the predictive distributions that are appropriate for Swahili
So
Early on you might not know Swahili very well as you get to the end of a very long document you would have started learning the phrase
Phrases and words of Swahili
He's repeating this this long that again let's try using that for a predictions
So the predictions change in the sense that they become
More precise
And refined
As you get data
Nothing is what I just said a moment ago
Austin the predictions you make all very confident
And this is the most important
Taxable
Open your predictive distribution
Is there a
And we could
Confirm this just by keeping track of how many letters you
Got first time or
So let's count up how many guesses you made before you go to the correct one so hey you made five
Casas can you see that on the camera
All right tell you made one to do
So at the beginning of the beginning of a phrase it's quite hard to predict what's going on
Free manga
3 again at the beginning of
And one
Fan 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
At the beginning of the word whoops sorry I ate 9 10 11 is what I mean
11 guesses to get there
3D and then it got a long long long long day
1 2 3 4 5 1 1 1 1
Time had one two three four five six seven eight
And I want you to and one one
For 3
Juan lawn mower
That would have been fairly extraordinary if you'd have so many warnings in that if it would actually the case that you really work
Quite certain about those particular predictions I didn't elicit from you exactly how show you
So we could have gone through some process of figuring out your own money and that sort of thing
Suck
Often
It's the case that the next data is highly predictable
So what am I saying I'm saying typical
Context
Dependent prediction
That we could then feed into the Huffman algorithm for example
Look something like this they'll be some letters that are not very likely there's the one letter that you're pretty damn sure
What is going to happen which maybe has 99% of the mass
MLB allotted by Velazquez which have very small probability so maybe
Your predictive distribution look something like this
So here's a cartoon of a predictive distribution that
Has 10 letters
Those are possible but not very likely and one that has 99% of the mass
Let's run the Huffman algorithm on this should you do quick and at the end
You combine this with all of the others
I got
And that gives you your optimal symbol code if we were insisting on using symbol Coast the lengths you will get
Has to be bigger than one bit the expected length cuz every
Code in a symbol code is at least one bit long yet the ends of this distribution
A bit like the bank calling me earlier
Is .11 thanks
So what's the fundamental problem with a symbol code
If you's a symbol code
You're obliged to a Mets
At least one bit
Soft character
I'm at lousy because the entropy
May often be much smaller than one bit the character
I have to do this
Even
Entropy is much smaller than one
No one I did for coping with the situation is this I all will I do love
So I wasn't meaning to run
Microsoft
All right next to the back
Instead
Abusing helping codes in this dumb way I could try and be a bit smarter you could say let's and code
Skagit artists together
And I could take any kinds of the time and say I can kill off this problem of Wong symbol
Lights Out by having blocks of six characters of the time
Home a B16 time cuz it's high and then I'll list all possible
Blocks of 16 characters
I'm asked the audience what the probability of all
50 ^ 16 sequences of length 16
Alphabet song of size 50
And then we can use the Huffman algorithm to incur the blocks
So you could say let's think in terms of runs because I how many runs of one
Father in heaven we could ask the origin to predict how long do you think you'll get ones for before you got it wrong
How can I ask you for bets on that number how long the run is
And that will give us an integer that was 0 and it was
And then there was a run at like 3 and then with three catches answer. We could do encode into a different alphabet
What we talk about run lengths
And then use the Huffman algorithm
But maybe
We're finding it's a little bit complicated I'm maybe we like to move on and say that was a better way than symbol coats and that's the message
Picture of a slapshot
Sir
If you would to do what I just described for dumpling coding blocks of car do you have to compute lots more
Joint probability if we got up to this point I was being saying to you
Okay if not tell me what do you think the next five characters might be guess the next 5K
For the next five characters which you would have to actually compute even though only one of those 5
Time to sequences is actually going to happen so you would have to think about many more possibilities
So in summary
What we would like is a solution
But they took compression
Where we can use
Context-dependent
Adaptive probabilistic models
So do you want to allow contact dependents you want to laugh at a detention
And we want
To be able to handle very concentrated probability distributions
Start his whistle right
We want the method that can handle
Context-dependent
Adaptive
Probabilistic
Models
That we want to use
And
We want to get rid
Office symbol code gap between L&H
By handling strong system distributions well
Okay
I'm about to tell you how to solve this problem but first let's just think of something we can do with this bullet before we
Do I piss off
There's a game we can play
I'm going to write down the green integers on a piece of paper
So how many guests did you need for v v
5 for the next five for the next three one one one
Wang
11311 1 + 7
And I could write down those integers on a piece of paper
And now
These integers
Contain enough information to reconstruct the headline
So top
Imagine that there is another lecture theater identical to this one
Identical in the sense that it's going to lecture in the front
Here's my identical twin and all of you and Alexa are also there in the form of identical twins
The same thoughts beliefs and predictions only post this through the wall into the other
I know I come in unless we just talked about symbol codes and now we're going to play a guessing game
Thank you very much I'll miss this a paper here
Okay I'll go to headline uses this alphabet please stop guessing
You make guesses and you say t
Abide nice stopping you whenever you guess the right number because we're perfect identical twins
Of the next election
Santa
We would end up writing down exactly the same set of letters on the board we will go through the same reasoning process
End up with hyponic
Okay so that's a fun idea that we couldn't quite Implement because
Identical twins but it's an of all state-of-the-art compressor
Can algorithms that you arrange to have identical twins of the two ends and those identical twins run for
This context-dependent adaptive probabilistic modeling in software
The question is are we assuming that it's a deterministic universe of the identical twins would exactly replicate
Yes for the verses of today the universe is actually deterministic and your identical twins would behave
Exactly the same as you
That's the analogy on I'm assuming
Okay
For this to work in real life we need to ensure that we have to do deterministic
Computers so the Adaptive probabilistic model that I'm talking about Willie a computer program
The try to emulate an expert audience like you and we will have one copy of that program
Encoding
Computer will have exactly identical deterministic on another computer that will work in exactly the same
I'm way so that we can replicate your guesses in your predictions
Okay so how do we do that
Well first I'm going to introduce encoding method called arithmetic coding
And
Out
Introduce it to you using several toy examples
One of which will be the the whole identical twin
Scenario it will start with slightly sinful
Examples
So let's give us those three tasks tasks
Then the general
Design that we have on the border
That's simpler but I have the essence all the problems are grappling with
We might have a bent coin with probabilities a b
Equal to 9.0
So we already know that symbol codes struggle with this we have to do something clunky with symbol codes to
Get any compression
The band coin
The second example
I will discuss
Is going to be the unknown
10 coin so I could tell you look I go to been calling in my pocket
It has been used to generate a great big file of A's and B's
I'm at so I'm telling you I don't know what the bias is but you do know that it's a biased coin
You just don't know
What Pa and PB
Oh yes
Another last on the Fly I want you to stop predicting just like that the headline you didn't know what language were in
Didn't know what it was about as we went along on the Fly you started to figure out what it was
So I don't know who's been calling so typical outcome might be lots of eggs in just a few bezoar
Or it might be lots of bees in just a few days and you don't know in advance which of those is going to be the case
And the third testicle discussed is the general
Situation where an article is available
The Oracle job is given any context X1 X2 X3
60 - 1
The Oracle will supply you with the probability of the next character which you should assume is be
Correct distribution for the next character
And that will be an identical twin Oracle at the other end who will produce exactly the same distribution in response
That same context
So this is any context
And then the question is how should you compress when you got that Oracle
Now the article is actually a complete completely general statement of the compression problem
Could be
Produced by the article he just ignores it contacts me says a has probability 99%
The Oracle has the trivial cases in it as well
The way the article would do the been calling thing is
Given the context he would look at how many A's and B's would have happened he would make an inference of what I think PA
Npb might be uncertainty about PA and PB in making his next prediction
Weather I think the next one is an IRB so he's first guess with no context
It could be blast as obese I don't know so be 50/50 then when you season a
For it being biased towards
Get a slightly bigger probability today and his identical twin would behave in exactly the same way
Okay so that's the three tasks that we want to solve and
Now we are going to
Define
Arithmetic coding
I should mention in passing the arithmetic coding is not the only other way of doing data compression apart from symbol code
But in my view it's the only other one that is really worth devoting Electra to Durham any other algorithm summer
Arithmetic coding is is the king of compression
So do feel free to leave read the the textbook on the other
Depression meds
Stop this harassment coating works
Arthur the coding is based on this idea
That
You can do any transmission
In a binary
Alphabet
As defining an interval on the real line
Suck
Vera Wang for example
Is a little binary string
And you can view that as far as funding to the interval from no point to 525 in decimal
100 we can associate with the Note 5
Turn off my 6 to 5 what would doing it's worth taking the symbol coating supermarket
Hair
And viewing
The top of the supermarket is being the real number 0 on the bus
And any particular interval you can see 01
Lives that goes from quarter of the way down the supermarket shut down the supermarket
All right
So we just
Taking the soup
The supermarket literally as a real line
And something you can notice about the supermarket is as you go to the right if you lengthen a string from Sage
Is there a long 2 0 1 0
The interval associated with that lengthen string is a sub interval
Of the NW started
Trump
So as you lengthen a binary string your old lady finding a sub until you're even having this way or this way
Hahahahahahaha inside the place you were before
So what are you saying
Was saying that you could imagine
Any binary file having a little dots on the front of it
Call the decimal point or a binary point
And then
The remaining characters
The binary expansion of a real number
So for example
Anyone megabyte file
Which begins o 100
4-H
Chameleon
Annie met one megabyte file defines a single real number where the Precision of at 8
Million binary digits or two million decimal places
Anyone megabyte file defines
A real number to roughly
2 million
Decimal places
High-precision nephew
Add another megabyte to Binary to it you defined it to another 2 million decimal places
Sony entire file is sending just the wrong number
So what we need to do next well
We're going to use the probabilities
Produced by our model
Which is either the been calling the unknown been calling or the auricle
We're going to use the probabilities from r
Adoptive
Context-dependent probabilistic model
To subdivide
The current interval
And initially the car and then to vote will be in hole from 0 to Wong
I will ask a probabilistic model what's the probability of a b and c and it might say four
42.5%
42.5% and 15% hopefully those that up to a hundred
For a b and c
How many say thank you very much I'm not going to ask you given that the first character in the file was actually a b
Please tell me the probability of the possible characters in that context and then we will subdivide
Stop printable recursively using the probabilities
But come from our
Expert from Oracle
So let's show you this now
Alright so here we have a little Gizmo
With two real and holes in it and I are the same relatable
And we can subdivide them in binary
I'm sorry I'm sorry
So there's a simple coding Supermarket appearing
And we can pick any probabilistic model you won't at least within reason
And use it to subdivide this world using the probabilities which have a 42 and 1/2
Send see 15%
And
If we're dealing with a fixed bent coin
Orfix probability distribution you can keep a fixed
Probability and subdivide
Hays interval using the same forward as he's a PC because we do that be subdivided into
C divided in the same way
Hand Circle
So you can
Identify on the left hand side if you if someone's giving you a file
You can ask the Oracle for the probabilities
And then you can identify the individual associated with the file would have to happen
Simile on the right hand side you can then hunt around and to find a binary string
Lines up pretty much exactly with the interval
On the left hand side
And then the method of encoding is going to be
Fat
We encode the entire file
Not just one character the whole file the whole file X switches the first time
II said that the end which could be
Millions of characters in length
Green Cove interfile
By transmitting
A binary string
Presentable lies
Within
The sauce strings interval
So
In very simple case where the entire string would just be followed by sea
That binary string we would find out subdivide and subdivide again
And then subdivide again either this way or this way
And we find ourselves a binary string how about
Slatwall
Stop binary string lights fully inside that envelope so we couldn't could be C
As
Skip Russell some zeros
1 zeros and ones
Sarah's ones
It's getting encoded as
Wang
All right
Find
I emphasize we do this for the entire file when you got the entire file you find a binary interval and so you fly
My one great Longbine restring his info lies inside
The corresponding 1/2 let's do this for the bent coin so let's give us
Event coinless reduce the alphabet size tutu
And let's say that the probabilities
Oops
The probabilities could be fixed to be
Say no .9
And
2.1 SAR to find my
Language model to be
The first task
Bent coin
And we revisit this
How are you doing
So now I'm using the been calling
I like to imagine what will happen
Is
Aaba
We'll talk about the details
All exactly how you terminate files of the late today I just want to show you where we find that info so in the
Left on side reviews a b
Subdivide how we can keep on using that on the right we've got
Only by near Landrum.
How to buy a b into a AAA
And then going to be
I'm a guy is it easy and then head we got hostiles to mores
And
So is the individual ignorance from that to that I'm on the right hand side
His binary land
And resume Den in exactly the same way and Vineland
And so this string hair
Is the solo thing wrapped and if we keep on going just keep on getting us out more A's and B's
You can see how the string on the left hand side is getting long
It's not a golf
About a hundred characters in it
Ijh
Something nice to Kya cousin on the right we've got the corresponding binary string
Which is only about 48
It's long what we achieved but I chose to compression
What's the entropy
All
No .9 nobody
So we are achieving the compression that Shannon said we should be able to achieve
We're reducing the number finder contest by about a pack of tooth for this mankind
All right what about the been calling with an unknown
Bias
Wicked
Say that we don't know the probability
Soft press the button cool while it says
What should we got to start off with well it's 50/50 cuz we don't know the price of the Bitcoin but one through CNA then
Makes it slightly more likely that will CNAs the next
How come
Because it could be a strongly by a spine or it could still be in type of bees but that's unlikely proposition
And so let's imagine that aaba happens
So as we keep on going into
This is to Ace this is three days in a row
4 days in a row
And then we get house I was Abby
Zoom in a little bit
Oops too much
I can't say his the three days
Hanabi I think
How many drinks for a movie
Thanks
So here's our adoptive model using probability that depend on the context and let's imagine having put
For a reason to be so that it's looking like you just keep on going
He was actually the improbable character and so you keep on going
I need a self a little B B and B C what happened to the predictive distribution
Hyper Beast
Even though Elian it look like he was the winner
We got lots of bees and we end up
Devoting more of the real line to bees
And that means that the binary string is getting shorter
Okay so we can do unlimited coins
And we can do oracles as well so let's rewind
So let's give us an English language model so I walked the first character going to be
Has a door space Sorry totaling to box in his a to zed
And his
Find reliant on the right-hand side as normal and let's say that we have the quick brown fox jumped over the lazy dog
I got the
Quick
Cute notes after the Q the language mobile says I've Just Seen A Q so you must be very probable
I was debating about half of the probability distribution to to you that's the sort of article what it looks like
Text and modifies the predictions accordingly
Because I try and face on a Linux back and how's the weather
So that's why that's the second most Pro Bowl character
Answer quick
Quick
Brown fox and so forth
Zoe zoom in on the left-hand side and on the right hand side tied to it is a binary world and
And if you. Send that binary string to someone at the other end
They start with exactly the same tool in exactly the same state and they just need to memorize 110-0111
Etc
Which icon do
Oops
So
Reinitialize the tool in exactly the same state
And we going what was the message it was 1 1 0 0 1 1 1 Andre total into that
Wan Wan Wan and so forth and on the right hand side you can see the quick brown fox
Should indeed be coming out because we got identical twin pieces of software at the two ends
So that those Metal Coating
Suck
Let's emphasize
How wonderful alphabet coding is
Dressers Outlet
We should
Give evidence for is that this really is almost optimal
Suck
Let me
Write down a feeling for you
The length of that binary string
But I just mentioned a few minutes ago for the one that we send the length of that binary string
Satisfies this the length of the encoding of X12 X-Men
It's less than or equal to
The sun information content which is what Shannon says it ought to be
But absolutely perfect impression is less than or equal to that + 2
So the entire length of the whole compressed file is only two bits longer than the optimal
Lights that shine would like you to have
And something to really emphasize that is what you compare that with what we could do a symbol codes for symbol codes
The lengths that you got stuck character was with when warm of the entropy
So that means a possible overhead on a file with an characters in it could be as big as an
I never had a van
We could be enormous this is for the entire file
Turn the overhead you get with symbol coats
Why is this the case what why is it that we end up with the optimal length well if you just say
Think about the subdivision process that we're going through the first
Isabel has a size equal to the probability of the first character given your model
Then you subdivide it in proportion to the probability of the second character given the
Fast car
His
The alphabet of possibilities and the product of those two is equal to the Joint probability of x
WiMAX to just buy trivial
Probability Theory
And then when you subdivide again you take that into a shoe size is X1
Connect to so I'll coffee this app when you subdivide
How do you say this is the probability of
You subdivide it in proportion to the probability of x3 given X1 and X2
If you multiply this length by that
Fraction you got
The probability of X1 X2 and X3 answer. The signs of the in
You got on the left hand side in the alphabet world
Is exactly the probability of the string
Not when you find a binary interval that lines up with that individual and it fits snugly inside
Perfectly snuggly
Then how many bits do you need
So that binary
Strength least time you start with 1 and 1/2 and 1/4
Who is the log base 2
All the size of the binary interval you end up with if it fits exactly snuggly
Then
The length of the binary string will be exactly equal to
The number factors of 2
Baptist
Number hair it's more
Sanwa
Which is log base 2 of 1
First Knox
You will end up with a binary string of exactly the optimal length
In practice you weren't quite have a snug fit but it's an exercise in the book you can do that cuz I'm proof
In the worst-case the worst Norm snugfit you can end up with will be the the
Binary string is a factor of 4 smaller than the alphabet string
So you only need an extra two bits to be guaranteed that you found
A binary string that lives inside
Okay
Suck that
Fax number 1
Which is brilliant
And notes number to the other thing I want you to know is how much
What is it to do all this
What did we need to do did we need to think about all conceivable strings that could happen
No we only needed to think about
The probability of the first character
Then the probability of a second character given that particular first character that had actually happened then we need to think
Find the probability given the actual context of what happened
So the work required was only that's only
Needed to compute
End
Conditional probability back-to-school to describe it in terms of the actual probabilities if I is it
Website
We only have to compute and
Times online
Conditional probabilities
And then we just have to do a load of zooming and bit shifting in order to keep track of the arithmetic
So that's a lot less work than the methods we were imagining we might have to use to cope with bent coins
Using symbol codes only told them into blocks of a block of 10
Possible outcomes need to think about 2 to the 10 strings every time you read in another 10 characters
That could be very large prefixes
Hit we only have to think about and I sing and I conditional probabilities how could it be any smaller
This is
A fairly small amount of work that you have to do
Nope number three another beautiful thing I want you to notice that I had a coating is it compared
Packable with any sauce alphabet
A nanny
Transmitting alphabet
As it went through the examples I gave you a ternary alphabet ABC
Can I speak to the been calling A&B and I switch to English with H's at in space you can use any
Alphabet and on the encoding side on this right hand side we didn't have to use
Binary
We could have used
Tannery from now on
Is it sunny file it's coming out with some zeros ones and twos in it
So you can encode into any alphabet
That you want as well it's a very beautiful framework for doing compression
Arithmetic coding is widely used
It's not super well-known
But it is in many of the state-of-the-art
Compression
Standards
So I think coding is used in for example JB
Which is a binary image compression
Standard it's in a language PPM which is very widely used
In a text compression
And it in
Document compression standard Cole deja vu
A final thing to note is about arithmetic coding is it completely separate
Probabilistic modeling modeling from encoding compression algorithms
List things in alphabet
The sum rule for converting a 10 to binary
Hair
The task of probabilistic modeling
Is a task for Oracle so you should do artificial intelligence I make really good articles
And then when you made your really good article to understand how to predict your language arithmetic coding steps in and tells you had
Listen to binary
Search for the complete separation of a task of artificial intelligence from spitting out binary strings
That feels much more elegant to me than many other compression method which may have some sort of asymptotic
Mousy property but they tend to fudge together these two issues they fudged together the probabilistic model
Undercoating task
Next time
We will move on to our next topic which is going to be Communication open noisy channels but I will tell you this
Just a few more ideas about automatic coating I'll kick off with one which you will no doubt have no
Noticed during this talk which is that you can do other things with us on Earth Magic
Coding Concepts
So when I just did
Remember to go that was I was
Demonstrating off Medico de but it's also I looked as if I was writing with the mouse and indeed I was so we can take
The
Athletic coating Concepts
I make a writing tool with my real number generating device called a finger by Ken Jenner
The real numbers if I move into my second time
And
I can write English
I cannot write any string at I want in any language tool I will write in English for you pick a sentence let's talk about
Efficient generation of samples from ensembles
Affogato
Hide a gate
I got lost
Forgot my alphabetical order that's all right
Efficient
Generation
I'm just moving the mouse up and down
And simply by moving my finger
I can write text
And this is a rising methods that can be driven by any muscle any muscle that can generate real value
Signals
So I can use my muscles to move something down and out comes English text to the talk
This is a record-breaking method for communicating English with very small numbers of muscles
With
Just a mouse some people can write at 40 was a minute before she was a minute with just one finger it supposed to
Possible with a gaze tracker to use No Hands a tool to just look with your eye in this world where you want to go
It's a minute
Five days alone thanks to the wonders of arithmetic coding that allows you to get the maximum information
Contact of the gestures that can be quite painful for disabled people to make
So that is cool. Joshua is essentially arithmetic coding turned on its head
And
So Josh is free software is available from the national website
I encourage you to Telugu
Of questions I will ask you next time is a final question about data compression
Here's the question if we've gotten alphabet ABCD with probabilities 1/2 1/4 and 8/8
Is this symbol code symbol codes
Then what's the probability that a bit plucked at random from the encoded stream will be a woman
We'll discuss that question of the first thing we do next time
And as last time I'll remind you that this is a list of exercises
On this site at which I encourage you to do as part of this course as well
Thanks very much for coming sorry I ran over