Welcome to lecture 16 this is the final
Lecture of this course
Today organic around talkin about neural networks and we're going to discuss
The content addressable memory challenge that I set
In the last lecture
And a little bit all right we'll have a little chat
About how that
Idea of how we solved the challenge
How that relates
Two state-of-the-art error-correcting codes that were
I discovered in the late 90s
Total Comfort full cycle back to the topic of the original
First lecture when we talked about
Are cracking codes for noisy channels
So I've highlighted in red are the two things weigh
Doing today
And
I'd like to just remind you what the content addressable memory challenges this is going to be the main thing will
Look at today
The challenge is to understand how do contacts restful memory how do we
Fill in the gaps how do we recognize Things based on that content even when some of the cues on noisy
And a precise wave
Same as challenges
Try and make a model of it make a dynamical system
That can do, is restful memory
I'll show you today a solution to this problem the task is
Botanical system with 25 variables each memory is
I-25 bit
State the dynamical systems 25 variables that change
In such a way that you got fixed points of the Dynamics at these
Say three desired memories
Whatever memories you you're given you should be able to make fix points on those memories
I'm the dynamical system should have
Promises that determine the Dynamics and is by adjusting those se300 promise
That you should be able to make the six points at the right places
And those six months should be attracting fixed point so if you're near to one of the divided Memories the dynamic should take you
To that memory
I'm so if you've added some noise to memory the noise gets cleaned up
That in itself would already be an exciting thing to solve
And it would look like this if you flip say free bits of Addie then you'd like the Dynamics of the dynamical systems
You back to a clean-up day
I know you see shouldn't be sending receipt on this thing
Is lucky day and it should be times that that's the goal
Have this problem
And
That sounds already hard enough
Additional constraint is when your brain encounters a new memory
You don't go out and buy some extra neurons from Dixons
You just carry on using the same brain and make some minor changes to it we don't know how
Buy those instantaneous changes that can be made very rapidly possibly with a little bit of sleep
You got your new memories added to the existing Hardware
And in addition
To be able to add extra memories incrementally with small changes
We would like to have the property that you'll dynamical system can go out for a drink and suffer brain damage and still
Working pretty well
So
We'd like a dynamical system web
A nasty person can come along and randomly delete half of the parameters that you
Lent
And the dynamic should still actually work it should still have attracting fix points that should still be rough
Play out the original memories
Okay so that's what we're going to do and I just want to emphasize how different different this is from
DeSoto standard solution
Is there a standard solution to come addressable memory let's just invent unorthodox approach
Emphasize
How different a solution is going to be so what would an orthodox approach be well you can
Have a piece of
Memory
That contains
The different memories
So have a little label saying his memory number one number two
Number three
And then your dynamical system could take a state
Escalade
X
And we could create little comparatives
Which
Measure how far
X what state is from memory 1
So you have a soda
Subtraction operation that
Compares those bets or distance operation
I only have another piece of Hardware that doesn't distance operation
Comparing
The second memory to Acts
And you have another piece of how do I
That can pass
The FED memory 2X
And
Then you can have a piece of Hardware that measures
How big those differences are
And we're interested in which one of these is the closest
I'm sorry
Computer all of these differences these distances sorry
And then we
Compare
Find the minimum
Aziz
So we need some sort of
Argmin machine
Whose output is not identification of which of those three
Is the winner
And let's say that X is actually closest to the J in this case
Then it could
You can imagine a little
Lights coming on here that says
This one's the closest
And then finally we need a piece of Hardware that response to that light and says okay let's over right
Facts
Bye
Copying in the contents of
Jay
+ 2
Oops
If I'm the winner and the similar lines from this guy saying if I'm the winner
I got to overwrite X
Are you with me this little logic of what you could do you could write a computer program and it could take
Memory number runs from Walnut and the number of memories
Do a comparison keep a list of how far away we are then going
Ha
Figure out which was the closest one
Then go back look up memory on Degrassi
A memory area
You have a
Distance
Vector
Or difference
A different Vector computation area
These will be your distance is
And
Sofa
Okay
Does that have any of the attributes we just wanted well if you want to add an extra memory you have to get some more
Hardware
And you have to add more comparison
Hard rabbit
Measures how far away things are outside that you have to upgrade you log me into that takes full
Things
To see which is the the smallest
I'm so you have to do a whole load of rewiring to Old Memphis and adding another memory
And if someone comes along and says
Here are some of your adjustable promises I'm going to accidentally
Splat a few of these
Then this whole dynamical system
Is going to compute
How far
Exes from messed up sea and it messed up to you the winter then you'll end up recording messed up Cesar
Has the property that if you mess any of this these parameters up
You would have messed up
The Regal so it doesn't have robustness to the slightest bit of damage and if you come
Tinker with the subtraction operation Hardware assembly
You will be in trouble
So this would be an orthodox way of saying
Which is the closest memory okay and mallets
Write that woman 2X
And it's
It is a Content addressable memory
But it doesn't have any of the robustness we won't know the extensibility
I described it as a one step
Orthodox solution then go away another way of making YouTube
Get most of the Dynamics in gradual would be to say
If you are the winner then you get to tug x a little bit towards you
Insert good X good
Elizabeth in the directions of wedding event as this thing it's all rights and settles it would end up
Being talked continuously towards whichever one it was supposed to in the first place
So you can make it a little bit more
Naturalistic but still
Useless pop-up says it doesn't have any of the properties roster
Something I'd like you to notice about this Orthodox approach to content addressable Rico is
What I just drawn on the bullet-head is exactly the same as a perfect brute-force Dakota for an error correcting
Recode decode with the list of words
In hair
Assuming that this distance measurement that you end up with hair is the correct distance measurement for the load likelihood
Viggo timer model
This is measuring how many bits are flipped between the annex
Then this would be the correct dakotah assuming were dating with a binary symmetric Channel
So there's a connection Brewing head of this this may remind you of it I'll decode
Recruiting codes
Decoding error correcting code is indeed
So they'll fine example of content addressable memory
Although
Why we made our accounting codes we didn't think of the code was as being memories that we wanted to recall
Okay so that's how you would do it Orthodox Lee and I gave you a whole bunch challenge to come up with a solution
And I will now show you a solution that was invented
I by John Heartfield to this problem
So
Hopefully shinichi using neural network
Which is a feedback Network that means is build out of neurons
Just like neurons we had before
Neurons that
Adult weighted inputs and send that
Outfits
But the wiring of
The hopfield network
Will have
Connections
Both ways
Between
All passing yards
So
Every neurons output gets broadcast to every other
You're on another way of growing this would be to say his only outputs
Of all the neurons
They all come around a little race track like this
And then this is where they got of that inputs Wong
Free Fall answer for
And these places had one-two-three-four these 16 places here where the
Weights exist
But you could think of if I go in your wrongs
Send as an i x i
Weight Matrix connecting them
So let's go through how helpful that what works in fact told you everything you need to know it's made of neurons
And
So here are the relevant equations
The architecture of a network is is a feedback Network
A rule for the standard hopfield network is the weights are actually symmetric so the weight
Between
You're on wall
And you're on 3 is that equal to the weight
Going from your untreated are on what
Reactivity rule is each of the neurons
Compute this activation AI is somebody wjxt + Peter I do every neuron can
Can have a little biased dangling off as well go feed her
I have a tattoo
Is 3
I'm paid for
And then having computer that activation you've got a choice of two ways of doing it one is
That
X-eye the output
X1 X2 X3 X4
XII is the hello tangent of
Your activation
Or another option is the extreme if you like low temperature limit
Of the hyperbolic tangent function
We just had to step
And that's what the binary hopfield Network
Rhode Island ending with it whether it's
Local field activation
His positive or negative
Okay and his jump field
He now works at Princeton and his retirement
Okay
That's the hospital Network I have nothing told you how to do content addressable memory to do confident content addressable memory
We need a rule for setting all of these wipes
So in the example problem with 25 dimensional
Finally passing stool in the number of neurons will have it 25
The number of weight is 25
X 24 does no self Connections in this network
Find the symmetric 65 * 24 / 2
Is the number promises
Piranha
And what we need is a rule for setting them
And the extremely Simple Rules there are other ways of doing this but the simplest want to go with in order to solve
Discount addressable memory challenge is to say let's set the weights which are roughly 300 number
In this way using a head rule
Federal says
Set the connection between inj by seeing how correlated and XJR with each
Stella in all of the
Passions that you want
Alliance a n is the number of patents
Salon
Which in my djeasy example could be three
Once you add an n
Ben 10 will it become full
Physical behavioral because it's a very simple idea from biology named after
Ochako Donald Hebb
The idea is if you've got a pair of no wrongs
And I'm responding to something and if there's a connection between them
Then
Maybe that connection strengthens in proportion to correlate to the activities of the neurons are
You're on the tennis to respond to
Yellow colored things being in the Steam and if this is a neuron that responds to
The smell of banana
And it says two things
Happen in a correlated way in the world to these neurons fire in a Carlito's Way
Then the synapse between them will get
Strengthen
Which then means that
If in the world are yellow thing comes along you may actually stop
Smelling the smell of banana even though the reasons I've been on
That's why there had been loading
And just one precise those associations that's the sort of thing that interests will memories all about
And her many
Other examples of strong associative mechanisms in our brains and in the brains of animals
I'd like to just mention as an aside is the amazing mcgurk effect which is an illusion
Where you see a video
Of someone speaking
Sardines like Bob
And
The OJ track
Has a voice saying so funny
But actually sneakily they switched up
What the videos doing the soundtrack is doing and if you ignore the video you have the funding specially clearly but when you
See the visual image of them saying different phonemes you got to complete over I do you don't hear the correct phone in
Anymore
Because of the strong Association of the visual
Image of them saying Powerball
When you see that image is it can actually override what your ears are telling your brain is amazing
Okay so we have good I sell the lending rule it's cool to have Rule and we're not ready to go ahead
And demonstrate
The
Hopfield Network
So
What I'm going to do
Is
Train about field network with its 25 * 24/2 weights
Using these three patterns djc
And here are the weights that you got when you run the head rule let's just
Outback
And
Explain where these weights came from
So I'll use the mass killing
His the first weight is the weight between neurons warm and two and it's equals one what why is that
His near on wall
Is Neuron to
Or In this passage 1 and 2
Or this one
1 + 2
I take your head roll it says what's the correlation with holding each of these passengers plus or minus one depending weather for adults
Do Sports give you a plus one and two dogs gets you a plus one when you run your head rule
An Explorer Panda adult give you a -1
So we got plus warm when we look at x 1 x X-2 in this case.
So I have rules
First looks about pageants and get a plus one
So that way
Then you look at this pattern and you got another plus one so the way it goes up to 2 and then you look at the third person and you got
-1
Cuz that related to goes back down to one that's why this way just one
Now let's look at the wait between neurons two and three they are in the same state as what's Bluff
Slav squat
Okay and all of a sudden his row to column 3 or
Rio sweet home too if you like
S37 every time he's got a plus one because they're in the same state of each other
Neuron 3 and 4
That's Victory here again they're all the same and
So logically neurons two and four have to be the same in all states is Riley because another + 3
Okay
So I made all right just by running through all the passengers looking at every pair of neurons and adding
What's the tracking you on as you look at the pattern noticed this rule is incremental you can learn the first two passions if you want
And then
Having lunch then you can go through at the third person that will just involve taking all the weights and shoving someone
All right
No we're going to run the Dynamics and I'm just going to run the binary hopfield Network that
At what each neuron is either up or down
And
Owner off
I'll run through the neurons in sequence of the Dynamics I told you on the the earliest slide when we said what
I said
The activity rule is you computer activation then you sent X I using a step function
I didn't tell him how you do that precisely I'm actually going to run through them one at a time and sequence
Updating them
And I'll go back to the top and I'll run through a second time
1% time until I get bored
All right
So that's the particular way of implementing the Dynamics you could imagine also synchronously updating old
I'm not doing that it wouldn't make much difference in fact
Okay so let's stop by Ashley
Initiating the dynamical system at one of the desired
Memories
Silly old Orthodox way of doing things
Make us a little
Diagram keep track
Of what happens
She wants a blunt the memories we completely throw away DJ and see if there's no such thing in that we've just got the waitzkin
In your own sweet chili
What I'm going to do is make a little diagram
Where we see if we set off
But at what
In the state
DJ NC
Do we have to have a 6.2 tool
So you can think of the state space office dynamical systems
Having a d location in it
Add a location on sea location
And what we're going to do is test Deca if I set off this system where does it go
If you could easily imagine the Dynamics
Take it somewhere else with my so don't wander off
Guy who knows why
We're going to find out what happens
What happened
After 1 ish duration which means every neuron got the chance to update itself in accordance with rules
Nothing happened
So it is a stable point
Effects
So
First Column headers going to say no noise
I'm going to take the day that's pretty cool
Next we set up in the J
Suffix might as well
Then again for the Sea and the sea is also
Fix my dick
This is no nice
Now the content addressable memory challenge says we wanted to be an attractive six-point if we flip a few bits we want Medina
Amex to take us back to those fixed point so let's stop doing that we're not going to
Split a single bit of the day
And then we run the Dynamics and get a chance to change themselves
And what you find is the one that would fit
Implicit self
I will get back to the stable
Okay
So this is
Approximately 4%
Noise cuz we're flipping warm
How tall
So the folks at noise level the D
Came to a k
Jay
See
Right so single flips have oil Bean
Discovered corrected and we have a working
Comfortable memory
Seems
On the basis of its time at residence I'm exhausted looking for single flips
But it has corrected all those single flips
Next
Let slip some more single bits
Jay
See all those got corrected and that third one with two flips
Both neurons 1 and 2 flipped
And then the Dynamics of cleanup so I can correct to Flip's as well so we're up to
10%
Allen still working
That's a j
With three flips
Thanks or up to 15%
IND
Things are still working
There's a sea with three flips
And I got cleaned up
Seguin
Okay
So the way my software works is it always rotates through the DJ CDJ CDJ can test
So when it says setting up three
With their phone for picking memory number three and it makes three flips in so you can check
It was actually freeflix away
No
Is your question is right cuz I'm just going to keep the noise level
Until it stops working and you would very much expected not to work if we're flipping say 50% of the Bay
Cuz if you take any pattern and slipped 50% of it
It just feel random noise
At this point we definitely expect
Djz or not because it would be completely bizarre if it works
I'm just going to rotate through them adding more and more noise
So maybe it
Looks a little bit difficult to think about it
Has an IUD with three flips corrected
AJ
Hennessy
Now it's looking for some up to 18%
We're still getting ticks what was that one
How is a c corrected
Adi
With both lips
AJ
Odyssey
Nike XO
Full Hazmat and the noise level is up to 22%
Flipping five
D
Jay is taking more restoration some time to do the cleanup
So that's apparently annoy CJ
That's quite hard for us to tell now
06 Mitsubishi Eclipse up to 24%
And
Tatsunoya CJ
Got cleaned up
That's a noisy C
But you might struggle to recognize it but
It's okay so
What's next to D6 splits
Smoj
As soon as you see
I think you might struggle to look at that and say it annoys you see but it's still looking so that the 29% noise
And that was a seat
Still working
Nicd with 7 clips
Noisy Jay
And there was a noisy C
And what happened
AJ
All right and that was it 33% noise
So that was our first failure in this little sequence of experiments check
Like I said something bad has started happening
But we couldn't just double-check I've ever made that noise EC
We had a load of noise
The number flips wild eight flips
We can just do a computation now how far away was that initial state
We got hostiles to here
From
Vijai because it's hanging factors equally close to the Jay that we shouldn't really complain about this
Stop giving a subject let's just check
I'll count across
So we're looking at comparing these two with each other so Wong flip to flip 3
9 flips away
From the J
And I looked away from the sea
So you could complain
But Haven differences between
How far to walk from the J I'm from the city so it's almost reasonable
Attraction around to go to Basin of Attraction around here
You can hardly complain
Okay let's kick I eventually because it was loads of noise what will doing
Is not
How to get rid of noise and see if we get home we're just picking completely random starting point the same what happens now
Medical system and has quite a lot of behaviors that we haven't yet seen so let's keep going
This is an OG
I need to see
All right so that's another failure
But again it's probably justifiable
This is a noisy Jay and it gives us a j
Okay
Sarah still getting some successes
His and all you see okay so
Bill from successes
Nicd
Success
Noisy Jay
What's happened there
What's that
The Dynamics of going somewhere every other time Arc
And now we run the Dynamics when we go into Mojo Nicole at
Cute all right so it's discover the letter q
So we added some noise to a J Styles to a place where everything went downhill
I say downhill has any Hill that's all we've gone into a
So we've ended up in the stable site which has been named Q by the audience
All right and we can just some make a note of what a cute name instead of this
Would like that and Jazz at the same time
That is not actually a d is left I'm sorry it isn't the way these look
So
I think he was a good name
Right so that that was a new exciting things
Did the dynamical system we made has got fixed point that are attracting fix D&J NC
But it's not the mother fix
Points as well
Which showed us who knows why that but
His a noisy
Safe
What's happened
The flip 10 bits of a c
Let me run the Dynamics and what state are we in now
Somewhere between a Dana serum embodies look like
These look like that so
How is this thing related to Addy
It's Angie d i k over here in state space is an GD everything is
Eclipse
And it is on TJ and his aunty c
States exist cool DanTDM
And it looks like I'm DD is a stable attracting fixed point that we've somehow got into by flipping
I say so are you dissing flips I'm going to run downhill or sorry we run the Dynamics
Who invented up in an TV
And again we could chat and it was looking 10 bit and I which is almost 50% so
Random starting point now it's completely irrelevant
We're just saying what are the fixed points does this system have
Does it
Only end up in 6.0 could it do chaotic things
And
When you reflect on it it's quite obvious that
The learning will it be hot
Is completely insensitive
Flipping elements of x
So if you
Total annual please learn ngd J&C instead
It wasn't exactly the same weights cuz you just -1 x -1
All right
Save the living room
Is completely agnostic and the dynamic changes
A single person
And that means if there is a fixed Point. D there must be a 6.2 DanTDM as well
Text Ashley Nelson surprise in retrospect there is this fixed Illinois
What's that
Antici all right
Let's add some noise to J
Who got Jay okay
Best bet
We're just exploring random condition
Initial condition
11 flips over sea and it gives us
What's that
Say
It's possible Jay but it's nothing today so it's strange J with is missing
Wake me up right we need a name for that
Tell me another
White
Aurora
So there's a thing that looks like that and that's a 6.2
Dota 2 which was an unintended fixed point
The tracks and we haven't attracting fixed point at the salafi thing
I got in there it is again I can't
Ledisi
AJ Styles AJ seems very good at attracting the Dynamics the J house
The song by DJ
Equally as big a basin of Attraction as Jay has gone both. Huge base
That looks off
Random initial conditions suck me into them
Okay
So what are we learned
It was just a memory by places we didn't intend but that doesn't really
What I'm going to do is
Part 2 of The Challenge was will this thing still work when you take it for a drink
And damaged neurons
Okay so you have a drink
Yes question
Okay so the question was how do you read things out is generating. Memories
Well it's only generating what do you mean by generating false memory if you mean you might accidentally
Some things Romeo driving dynamics that don't exist
Then
Second
I never showed you the cute but it has a fixed Point IQ
But was not in the rules of how a Content addressable memory should work the definition of a Content addressable memory is
If you show it a noisy bunch of a memory it should restore
To the original memory
And this doesn't
There wasn't a rule that said
If I give you a completely random inputs
You should only have a produce
Correct memory
That wasn't part of the job specification
All right
Nevertheless if you want to answer to the job certification we can do that and we can make neural-net learning algorithms
That will essentially fantasize come up with random ideas and check that fantasies still consistent with
Ramsey said that there is a normal strong interesting
I'm learning algorithms to know that your idea that you should make sure you don't have spirits
That's essentially what many of these algorithms about are about fake
They both exposing the brain to reality and then having a dreaming face when that night you go and dream and then you make sure
The statistics of your dreams are consistent with the statistics of reality
That's one of the things
Okay
So much as you just expose it to the training cuz I'm slim that's my best friend
And then we have a dynamical system
So you can call these false memories if you want
Adjust Spirit sites of dynamical system is also
Fair enough name
What is corrupt the lights
So I got to take the weight Matrix that we learned with the head rule
But then I'm going to LEAP in and Destroy some of the weight so all of the weight for either
Plus one
+ 3
-100 - 3
But I'm just going to take
A fraction of those weights at random
N70
And then will rerun the Dynamics
Sucks
Handsome randomly corrupted weights the fraction corrupted
Is 79 out of
And now we're going to rerun the whole game that we just played really say
Is there a 6.5 velocity
So put in a day
I'm around the Dynamics we find
Yes Pacific Buddyfight what I've done is I Flip 3 bit so I'm taking
I'm going all the way to
Sarasota 15% dish
I'm saying
Is there an attracting fixed Point update
And
They say the D is okay for this example of flipping 3 bits
Let's take a giant flip three bits
Honda Civic 2.0 J
Let's take a c-clip three bits and there is a fixed point at sea
That is weak evidence that there's some ticks all over here as well but let's not waste time
And we could go to High noise levels and see how big these attracting fix points
Are we could explore and see is there still looks. Wanaque and want a lesson
Well that's one thing as well
But I'm not going to do that I'm just going to mow lights
So now we're going to destroy Mohlenhoff 258
Over 300 weight so not being set
2-0
Are we we're on the Dynamics we say
If I take Addy and I'd some noise
Where do I go
An answer is
Traffic spot
But isn't quite exactly the day but it's only different by one bit which I think is a pretty good situation given that we've
Destroyed more than half
All the promises
And the network
Suck
Nah
Almost right so I'll give it a tick with a Twitter that just says one bit is off in this next month
Noisy Jay
That's clean up iMessage a
So that's a success
Noisy sea
Gets turned into
IC
So we've destroyed more than half the weights and it still working
And if we had time we could explore what's happened to this boundary hair
Where it stops working service somewhere hereabouts
Presumably the Sun by Andre maybe it comes through so their backs and eventually if I destroy enough weight
Presumably the whole thing is going to stop
Working down here
So there's something about Andre and we just thought it might look something like that green light
Destroyer movie Chester Tech 257
All the way
At random
The question is
What happens to the d2j
Mercy
Which side of the green line have we we go
So we put in an ICD
Angry cat
Something I did not do flips away from
Adi
Alright so
Okay it's not really that great
Put Illinois to Jay and we got mumbo-jumbo rubbish
That's not it still got a fixed point the dynamic have fixed point but
That's not what I wanted
You see which is one click away
Okay so given that
None of those are being correctly stored I think it's fair to say that the green line
Stop somewhere on that that side
Maybe something like that
Okay there's a huge but just want to have rules that looks if you want to and she know where that boundary goes and
Clever physicists have
Explicit closed form solutions for
For this diagram the weakest cast
Now what are we do
What was the other definition of a Content addressable memory you should be able to add some extra memories to it by a small change of income
And it should still have all the old memories on the new one
So what we not going to do is
Telegram
Where
We vary the noise level again
From zero
To say 15%
4 more
And we just found this DJ and see, and now we're going to say
One more memory is full
Or maybe even five
Oh maybe even 6
But at some point
Play imagine this thing light notebook
And what we've established
So far
Is that this worked out to some
29%
So this is all text
Up to here
Play maybe not sure we didn't actually look at every single noise
Vitanova
Mariscos m
So there is the end
And what does that mean we do with the weight well
Every way either goes up by 1 or down by one
Because he just look at the correlation within the empatan of the spins with each other server example this one was used to be
What was it plus one
What's the connection between these two
No in the end you can see there an opposite States
Just going back down to zero
So that's why that weight has become zero and it was plus one
All right and
This weight
Has gone up to full that's the way between 2 and 3
And they are both in the adult State hair
So that's why we got an extra plus woman that weight has been up before
The old way to just mean tweet the time little bit the least significant bit of every weight
Peanuts a little bit up or down
And that tiny change we hope
Has created a completely new fixed point that didn't exist before you can take take it from me I can prove it
The previous dynamical system did not have a fixed point at em
Now we make this tiny change to it
And we put in a d and it still takes pine tree put in a j it's fixed Point could you just see if it can you put in an m
We have fixed points
All right writing fixed points lets out a little bit of noise and fine art
The one bit flips is correct its buddy
PJ
Sissy
And I am okay so that was all right
Oneflix corresponding to 5%
Nice
Right
Next let's try cooking a bit more is another one flip
I'm getting a bit more slowly. I want to be honest with you about when this thing stopped working
But that's one flap corrected
Idonije
I know you see with one flip a not so fine tick
Is annoy the end and it was fine to attack so had to run through
All at 5%
Noise
One flip
I got his another on D
Jay
See
Am I got those Rolex
So it seems pretty good at cleaning up single bit flips
Nicd
Jay-Z
NM
Well like I said I had full run-throughs
Call with single flips
Right now it's looking to
The noise level up to 8%
And the D is I can
D j c
Night so that's correcting to flips
Noisy
Jay
See
Holiday formal text
Again those rules to bits being flipped
Nicd
Jay
See
Okay did anyone notice anything
That is antonym
Yeah
What is it it's two bits away from them
Cast what does the name look like
Become say it anymore that is
2nd drive and 4th Road Blocks initiative.
Right so that's a failure
It's two bits away
So it's not working absolutely perfectly that it got another six point but we didn't ask for
And
Sometimes when we slept two bits it finds that fix bike
AJC
Okay so that was a success again this is still flipping two-bits long 2/3
So just have one failure out of 16 in the to flip
Territory
No sleep in 3 bits
D
Jay
Is it
What's wrong with that it differs by 2
3 bits from a j. Left
Does this one under his bottom left-hand corner
So those are
333 turtles next to that
So it looks a bit like a j but it isn't the J memory
Today
Now you see that's okay
That's okay
Noisy I'm okay so what happened 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 on the failure
There's still quite a d
The three Flats J
See
That was another full of success
I got says not working but it's only failing into out of 16 cases at this noise level
Noisy d j
See
I left something like this isn't it
And I'm alright so when were sleeping full bits
Which is hairish 17%
We're getting some failures show
This is for flips
I'm getting some ideas
All right so I've got weak evidence
That things are getting bad
Hereabouts so still looks for the basis of attraction
Quite so big
What are the next five memories okay so the memories are not Cody j c and x
Is a checkerboard pattern
That I
Picked
All right
So all the weights with - 4 - 2 0 2 or 4 on Arcane Spike
Odd numbers
Right
Do we have fixed points
Let's try the D yes is a fixed point
BJC and context
There is a fixed Point J at Sea
And an
IMAX I kept so we still have
Effects point
Is it an attracting fixed Point can we flip some bits
Pick up things
Short I'm going to go to 15% noise levels I'm going to flip 3 bits
And see what happens
Hereabouts
Announcer is noisy d
Just turned into
Auntie Em
Know your date is it today
OUC is ik
Noisy Adam is okay and noisy actually got turned into
I don't know what that is so that was sort of bad okay okay okay
I'm bad which isn't looking very good so I probably this green line
It's somewhere I like that
I got so it's not really working anymore we ended the fifth memory and is the basis of Attraction if better
If the reservation that's all that really quite small
Let's try again with the noisy d
Lazy J
Alluc
Noisy an
I know you ask a guy old love those actually work so we had five more successes
Write 6 memories
So
Will probably pushing a lot 9 DJ cmx Unlimited
And I look like this
So that's the six persons the weights now it'll be even numbers if you treat them all up or down by one
And we put in D to check it affects point
We got something it looks a bit like ass but it's off by one bit
Jay is a fixed Point C is not fixed point
That turned into
Something that looks like a stupid is off by one b****
And is not a big client is turned into an GS with one bit flipped that's not very good
X
Turns into
With one big lips
I-ness turned into Asheville
So that's bad on this is okay with a little twiddle
Right so it's really not working anymore so this Green Boundary
Comes in hereabouts at
6 memories and if we
Ask the question
Could you have made a hotel that what good did have fixed points at all of these if only you could use a different money out of
Instead of the head roll
Well how could we do that
One way to think about it is every one of these neurons
Is a single neuron
And we already have a learning algorithm for training single neurons
Remember when we were training pigeons
Sorry pigeon replacements
To distinguish raising from Pebbles so we could use the learning algorithm
For single neuron to neuron
To classify
The D passing as a + 100 - 1 depending whether that neurons should be in-state + 100 - 1
Minutes in a day
I'm trying this one simile
With
Every possible input DJ cm in soflo
The correct label being
Blue or yellow football of -1 depending on whether this one should be up or down
How's it going to look up table of what it should do in those those
Those dates and you can run
Individual learning algorithms but each of them
In fact a couple to each other cuz the whites have to be symmetric so you run out of hole
Subjective function
And it is actually possible to come up with a setting of weights
Which O'Hare
Here are a set of Weights that will found by
Training the algorithm
On those
6 examples of each neuron being told whether it should try to be up or down
I'm not when you run the Dynamics talking to a dude you got a d j u got today
Percy you got to see him cuz fam
X cos x sin x cos y so you can
Still tweet the way she just don't use the head rule anymore you do something bit smarter
How do you take the weights just a little bit
And we got six points in all the right places so it was possible to get the whole field Network to have fixed points
If we use the different letting I'll go anyway the main part of the show was the hebra which is so fantastic
Simple and clearly biologically plausible to some very easy algorithm to learn to do employment
All the neurons in a correlated State on alternate route to sign ups strength up or down
Accordingly
Does this thing have a tracking six-point well know if you are mad
Of noise 2D you got ass
J wax
See you guys to ask
I'm goes on TS
End
Text with flipzco SAS
And that's what some folks ghost is still not looking very well but at least
It did have some fixed points in the right place
And I think that might be
The end of that show
So there is a whole field Network and in my view it's a pretty exciting solution to the content addressable memory
Challenge
We've got a candidate solution to come and wrestle memories and the whole field network is itself an interesting thing
It is a dynamical system is it even got fixed why does it have stable States
How many memories can it learn what is its capacity I showed you a tiny example with just 306 memories
25 neurons and bigger
And if all the neurons are connected to each other how many bits can you still have any random patterns
Can you train this thing on using Navy Federal
This is an interesting system we've started to study what house
What can we do with it what ideas inspired by the film Network
I'm going to spend
The final 20 minutes or so
Answering a few these questions why does the network have some stable States well I wouldn't be
Surprised if you recognize what we've just been doing have you seen these equations before
Activation is a linear sum of
Texas exes
Sayings by putting the
Hey use the activation function
Have you seen that before
Yes you see me before because two nights ago we discussed variational methods
Spin system with coupling School jmn
Then you want to approximate the nasty complicated couple system by a variational approximation
Out pops these equations which all exactly the same as knuckle W because that weights in a neural network
And the H's which was applied Fields local fields and the physics problem
Has the biases of neurons
Thanks of equations are identical we seen this before time tables the page of text that we had
In the textbook
And an Alexa why we derived
These equations
As a variational approximation to something
Spitz Auto Parts why did about the world since it's an approximation to something
Maybe we interesting to actually implement the something instead of implementing approximation
And that idea is called
The boltzmann machine
So
A little spin out I'll just mention
Is
Hopfield network is a variational free energy
Minimisation approximation
A probability distribution
Of Acts which is the same old thing that we had for the spin system
Need to be over in jxi
W i j XJ something like that it will take
A possible sign era
Sensei an approximation that we could call Q
I'm not motivated to hey maybe we can make a neural network that Implement p and we could have a whole world
Neural networks that
Actually do pee so the boltzmann machine
Is the neural net communities name full
These the Catholic neural network but samples from this distribution
And there's a whole bunch of games you can play with those you can
Have learning algorithms where you say let's pray in the probability distribution of the bulk machine
To have some properties we want like
Assign high-probability just a memory that we want to learn or you can have other
Things that you want to do other associative memory
So does that literature on both machines
And if you want them to do letting you need to have Lenny I'll go and spoil them
And
Just complete this aside
If you write down what the learning algorithm is
For the bolts machine
If what you wanted to do
Is assigned high probability to send a memories
Then what you find is the very first step about learning algorithm is
Behavioral
Let me have
And I'm the guy so if you wanted where do they have real come from all his one way of deriving it
Write down the real probability distribution
Write down the learning algorithm
Make one step of stupidest Anthony find you got a head rule
That's a little aside
No
The fact that the whole field network is associated with the variational free energy means that it's Dynamics
Have I lie upon a function so that's why but I do have stable States
The Dynamics
Take you down hill on the variational free energy
Find because that is a function
That
Is love a bounded by something obviously negative
So by observing that we've already seen this thing and it came out of
An objective function
We got a proof of the fact that Networks
Dynamics
Do minimize injective function and Bethel that exist
6 points
Dynamics
Minimize vaginal fantasy vaffle
There exists fixed points
And the Dynamics
Always go into one of these six points and stop
It didn't have to be that way you can easily right then. I'm at the systems that don't have objective functions that decrease
It's easy to make healthy systems but just go bubbly bubbly bubbly and randomly wander around and end up in limits like
Wilson cycle
No
Another question almost in question was what is the capacity of hopfield network
And this is being studied by the physics community that goes Attract it into neural networks
And they have established that if n is very large
And if I is very long so I is the number of neurons
And is the number of patents
Instantly the number parameters
Then
And also Network
Is roughly
I spread over to
If you make both I and enlarge then what you find is
Set the hook on that works for an override less than a critical value and it doesn't work at all
Andover eye
Above that critical value so these two graphs are all showing you
How good the overlap is between
Design memory that you're trying to recall on the nearest stable State the nearest fix point
And you can see if a Nova is less than 0.1 full Rosa
Betty got very big of a lot which is wonderful but you go above .14 and you got this catastrophic failure
That means that you can learn
Ventolin perfectly instantly notice how the black line isn't quite equal to 1
To any value of n over I
So good there is a six-point but it's not quite in the right place
Debra Loomis
Does this critical value and crit is 138
That means the number of random bits that are able to learn
And sore Indies
Promises
The number bitchslut if your just below that critical point
Is roughly
And Chris X High because each of the entrance patents you learned has
I randomly chosen bits in it
So that's roughly I squared
* 9.138
If you take the ratio of this number Betsy blunt
To this number promises
The ratio is about 2.2. Weight
So that's a nice for the rule of thumb again
In the last lecture we talked about training a single neuron and we observe that a single neuron
Conlon
Random person random labels
Opossum and it couldn't load up to 2 bits per byte
Nothing that work with the head broken glenpointe to full bits
Hawaii time then it stops working beyond that
This is a result for random patterns onto the Hebrew
My final question balls what else can we do with these hopfield Network IDs
But when I did that John Heartfield himself had walls
Since the Hot Wheel network does minimize things
How about we go out into the community of people who try to minimize things because that's a job
I'm trying to solve a problem with
I think it'll do a minimisation for you
So let's give you an example
Let's discuss the traveling salesman problem
The traveling salesman problem
Is the task of picking a tool that visits in cities
How do you want to minimize the distance the length of the tour
So
Where should we go now
And I'm going to show you
First the traveling salesman problem with full
Cities
I'll describe how you can look
So you go to the back page of the road atlas
And it often has a thing that looks like this yeah
Which has a list of names of cities on Melrose and sisters on half and these are the distances between the 50s
So you have the distance between cities iamb distance between
Hey I'm see here distance between AMD
Distance between BMC and surface
And you looking at triangle of distances and then you'll told
Here are all the cities you must visit a b
See
Andy
You can look up and not trying don't want the distances and you have to pick a tour
Which is
A
Sequence of
Maybe a for us to be second
C4 and then back to a so close tour
And the task is to find a toy
Which minimizes the total distance
This task
Is an NP complete problem that means it's hot
I could give a more precise definition but
Brabus is it just means it's an interesting thing if you can do
Anything on the schedule and we don't expect have a perfect solution cuz it np-complete means
You would
Get an award if you could actually do it perfectly
Okay so you got to pick a permutation
And you want to minimize the total distance
So the goal is
Find a permutation
All
ABCD sucks at the tool
Minimizes
The total
Distance
Okay
You can think of this as
Being a problem with two objectives the real objective is to minimize the total distance but there's no
Objective Lucky in that which is redo one please
A permutation
John Hopkins approach to this problem what you did with David tank
Waltz
Make a network witch
Minimizes a single objective function
That is a sum of you if you like of these two things the objective of minimizing Solutions Plus the objective of beer
Implementation
How do you do that
Well
You making that work
Representation
Oh
A tour like objects that may or may not have to be at or across the top we have place
Stint or does a city come first second third or fourth
And on the left hand side will have cities a b c d
And if a comes first service the tour is say acdb
Secom second
Dcoms
I'm becomes 4th
Then you could imagine switching on these will neurons in switching the other 12
Neurons
And that would be a way with 16 neutrons of representing this particular permutation
There's actually several ways of doing it cuz you can slide
You can wrap around in this way unless four different ways of representing the same
Auto store
Okay
So that's the network representation now we need to wire up
The neurons to each other in a way that enforces these two objectives of please make a permutation
Please have small title distance so we need things that enforced limitation
And we could explicitly have some Uber conversation that says
Is this thing a permutation or not
But that would not be local in it we don't be distributed and it wouldn't be
The way to do it in a hotel Network away well if it's a limitation then there's only one won in a row
And if it would to Wong's in in a row or column
Oh that would be bad so something we can do is we can say
Let's have negative weights
From one neuron to everyone who is in
ISRO
Unless have negative weights
Trevon Hughes in his column I'm sorry I said that back to front but it doesn't matter
They have negative weight
From you to everyone in Euro and everyone in your column
And you repeat that for all your wrongs
Then we need to have a way off
How to make you think are about minimizing a distance as well as just
Creating a presentation
So how do we do that
Wow
If
This neuron is on here
And if this neuron is on
But not means that
Became second
And
Kang said
Anar something in this network had better be aware of that and care about the distance between B&D because be house being put in
2D
So we're going to have a weight
Color green
For minimizing car listings
Between nice
It will be minus the distance between B and D
Similarly
Wi - DVD between those two
A-minus DBC between those
And mine is DBA between those
Etc replicated across
Alright so
If you're in the same Rosie Charlie going to have a red wait connecting you
And that's in column likewise if you're in adjacent columns but different Rose you will have one of these
Green lights connecting you
And if you're not in adjacent columns then you won't have any weight
If you're in different columns and rows the way will be zero so I'm going to have them done that here
So here is the the network with some red squares to hear the neurons that 16 of them
And if I put the mask on in your own you can see all the weights connected to that Neurontin some of them all
Feasible -8
Some of them - 7 sum of -5 -4 and 3/4
Why well let's go look at some of these so why is this wait -7 it's because those
Neurons are in the same rows each other the purple and green one
Rights to all of these seven off of neurons that are in the same
Bro as each other
Thought I just picked seven to be a distinctive number that's the negative weight for being in the same Rohit Samos Evans
On an hissimo 7 1/4
Which is the same Rosita
The sevens roll pin earrings
Okay
Now why is this a 5
Well that's because those two are in the same column is each other and all the fives
Off of neurons that are in each other
All right
Picnic picnic
Why is this a woman relaxing warm because
Not A and B
Inerrant adjacent columns so we need to know about the distance between and I'll just put them on this warm
All of those red weights are warm because
Those are neurons that
If both of them are on a comes next to be in the tour
These ones are warm because
The distance from B to C is 1 and if those
Has neurons are on the NBA's coming to see
Either one
Because the distance
Between C and D is warm
That's it for us oh my actual distance table says
A2B Islam
B2c it's 1
And see today is a distance of 1
Meanwhile a 2d is an explicitly is
Nicoby far and can only get that on the road I think six
Between a and C
And between B and
That's my assumed
Links for this example
So this is the little triangle thing in the back of the
Does that matter
Okay how about explained all the weights we've got. We've got six years we've got.
Virus have not explained every single light and know why is that
Are only the one for 6
Or Bible 7
Was there a met every single waiting here and now we can run the dynamic going to buy it
Set the bias to
-8 + -5
Please switch on wouldn't have that none of them would want to switch on adults
Please my activation is plus I'd so you go ahead and switch your mom
And then you ask you to do you want to switch on and he says my activation is plus one
Yes I will switch on as well
Not very good news cuz it's not going to be a presentation yet but we keep dying
Da3 do you want switch on he says no way my activations - 6
Faithful always activations off in this Orange
Does B101 switch on
B2 says no leave me alone
B302 we could toss a coin to decide whether to
Top 10 mono knot
I don't get a coin
Okay
Let's flip the coin
Okay. That means that we don't turn it on
All right
I was a tale before do you want chicken he's alright that's how I feel
Heads heads
And don't go
Write see why does it want to go on no it's stable
Does si tu no it's stable the C3 it's unstable it wants to to go on it
So that goes
C4 is stable D1 stable D2 is stable D3
Stay with me. Now you keep on running it what you want to do
What they want
Stable stable
Unstable okay
Sable
See
Is stable
C2 C3 C4
Stable
Unstable okay
Unstable before stable back up the top one stable A2 unstable
All right man
Thanks table well
B
Stable stable stable
You can be assured we're not going to be here forever because this thing is minimizing an objective function eventually will be
60s table table
Stable stable
StayWell I got anyone
What you think is going to happen when it's unstable
Okay they are all
Stable happy bunnies
So what's happened
It has a plan and it's in a state that doesn't want me to pay attention
That might actually be the optimal tour I can't remember you can check
Okay so that's all Phil Network being used to solve a notarization points problem
I Got Dirt don't be impressed by people who sometimes sold NP complete problems they can never do it reliably
But that's an interesting thing to do with a neural network
3ir who was a student in the engineering department are back in 91
For his guy she said well let's take this is actually a bit broken to have an objective function That's a Some
Overrule plus the thing you want to minimize update the way hoping that works work
In such a way that we don't have a competition between Trying to minimize the distance on obeying the rules that he tweets
A little bit and came up with a Russian of this network optimization algorithm it's involved
Continuous neurons that gradually got switched on it's like starting a high temperature state
End up
Reducing the temperature and here's a picture of his Network solving the traveling scholar problem which
To the task of visiting all the Cambridge colleges
So that was fun
The final thing I want to say is
And this is a personal story of how my understanding of neural networks evolved into something
An useful
Here's a question for you I've been working a lot I want you to talk to each other for a minute and say what is this from
Healthy distribution
Okay I have a chat to each other
And see what you think it might be
You're allowed to make hubbub
Indeed I
Would really like you to make Ava
Could give you a possible hint I've grown on the bullet just now
A graph associated with the function of written down that
The graph contains
At Square nose
The song includes
Attend
That connects together multiplies
The variables that are only
How does a connected to that's a Preacher Man the song
Is that black blob or a white blob
And that white bulb is connected to the
Times that a couple together
Suck
Okay answer is it's the graph of the 7/4
Hamming code
So this probability distribution has what property if Peter is a big positive number
What happens
That means we favor
States where X 1 * x 3 * x 3 x x 5
Is equal to plus one
And Parolees Act is a + -1 now
So what happens if you were to perfectly simulate this probability distribution
Is Beatrice flight Lounge
Which states would keep on coming out
Yeah
Okay
What would keep on coming up would be States in which the parity of these four guys is even
Find where the parking fees for is even in states where the parking fees for his even because then old full terms would be
Plus one
I'm what's another name we give to State a Conex to at 3:07 that have the property
The parity of these for
Is even
On the property visit even these is even
Those states are
They all the code words of the seven for having code so this is the graph of a sudden.
Mission on the board
Is
The probability distribution that sits with lots of mass all over the code words
Symmetrically
And assigns very little Mass to known code words
I think
So this hasn't gone anywhere it's just an observation that probability distribution
Which is a sum of
Simple terms
That probability distribution
Is the probability distribution of the sensible code within the human code
So question 2
What is this
Do I make hubba bubba gum
I'm drawing the graph of this function for you
And the question is what's the probability distribution
The graph of the function
Just involves simple times each time is b n x x
Adding an extra node to each of these
Variables
Okay so what is this
That's not good 3 and that's connected to what you saying
I've got to find yes well. Thank you
Sorry about what is this
Probability distribution what could it be
Okay so we added a by us to each bit
And in what context might you get such biases and say yes this is an interesting probabilities
Okay let me help
So let's imagine
But someone is sending code words
Using a 7 full how many code so they spitting out tea and it goes over Channel
Which is the binary symmetric Channel
Which is received thing the diff is biking flips using a bench
And you receive
I know you want to solve the problem of saying given our what do I think the code would wasn't that for what
What was s
Okay
Saudia and coding operation was they picked a tee from the first distribution Circle at P North
So they used
Peanuts
Because we have not a clue with that they chose that's what they picked at random
For my pain if you
One of the code words
So they threw tea from peanut
Then we got an observation we get to see
An hour is a noisy version of Tissot in terms of graphical model
AR
Gives you biases on each of the bits
So the posterior probability
Which is
What you want for decoding
Birthday probability all t
Given is the product to be a given t x apply for the
Normalized
This time here
Is penalty and this one is
A product of time is one for each of the
Bits to end
All the probability of
And given that TN
Which you can write if you want as
Give or take some
All right
So
The answer to question 2 is
This probability distribution is the posterior probability
Of the code word
Given
The output of a binary symmetric Channel
Not just a virus message Channel
Any channel where each bit is independently
Communicate
Binary symmetric Channel
Would be the special case where all of the ends is a
+ 2.70 - 2.70
And it'll be the same body 2.7 repeated lots of times with pluses or minuses depending whether the alphabet is
At 1 or 0
If it's another Channel like a gaussian channels on bn's would be different from each other
Apologies for the technical problem I'm going to have to re speak selection from here on Earth
So this observation that the
Error-correcting
Code decoding problem can be expressed in terms of a probability distribution which
Upstairs an exponent is a sum of simple factors
On the observation that
The hopfield network can be viewed as
An approximation
To a probability distribution that is the exponential of a sum of
Simple factors
In the case of a hopfield Network these factors adjust
Quadratic with Turnpike wrj XIX J
Miss observation
Motivates the idea
Maybe we could take
The decoding problem of an error correcting code
And solve it
Using approximate methods
So I'm not just talking about the seven for having code but the idea is to generalize take
Other Eric redeem codes Xpressbet decoding problems
Amazon
In terms of
E to the power
Opus Olive simple factors
And then use for example
A variational method
To approximate at distribution
And hopefully find the maximum
Off the bus 3 distribution
And in 1995 that's what I did I wrote a paper told free energy minimization algorithm
What decoding and cryptanalysis and I made some random simple error correcting codes
And I decoded them
Using variational methods very similar to
The Outfield Network we've been looking at
Feet
Error-correcting codes I made
Happy form of
And identity Matrix on the right-hand side and on the left hand side just in space random ones
Typical low-density generator Matrix codes
And
When that work
Looked quite promising that the window record-breaking results from it but it was promising enough that I carried on
Looking at this topic and discussed with Radford nail
The questions
First
Can we do better than variational free energy minimization as a decoding algorithm
What coats like these
And secondly for what are regretting codes do they sort of spas
Graph based
Message passing decoding algorithms
What the best
Which Eric redeem codes are best suited to these sort of algorithms
And what we found was that we could in fact do better than the racial free energy minimization
We
Rediscovered the idea of using
An algorithm called the sumproduct algorithm which is also a message passing algorithm on a spacecraft
And it also has a variational interpretation but it was a better algorithm than variation
The second thing we did was we
Try to invent new Eric redeem codes and we invented a range of error correcting codes
All of which are better than these low-density generator Matrix code then some of them are quite a girl
And the very best ones that we came up with were actually first invented
In 1962
Bob Gallagher who is one of the founding fathers of information Theory along with Shannon and others
Invented low-density Parts check codes for his PhD thesis
And in
1996 Radford Kneeland I wrote a paper
Showing that you could not achieve nishine Unlimited Performance
With these recruiting codes
To remember
Back in like the one we discussed
The
Diagram of performance of Eric writing coach with right along the horizontal axis and error probability on the bus glass
Texas we had repetition codes that went very good we had some other codes like the 74 Hyman code
Better
And we had this remarkable result from Shannon
Which is that there exists a recruiting codes then that can achieve
Rates anywhere up to the capacity with error probability arbitrarily small
And rebate
Lotus two-party check codes which
AR
Very similar to load it to generator Matrix codes but they look like this instead of
Having
Part of The Matrix
Peace Paws and part of it and identity Matrix
The whole Matrix
Is spas
With three ones McCollum three wants to come all the way across
Or it could be some other number like 405 but the results I'm about to show you three ones McCollum
And so here on the screen you can see a price check Matrix with
20000 columns and 10,000 roads and if you look very closely you'll see that there are three ones in every single way
Opos 20000 columns
The picture on the top right
Chose you
I transmitted Vector which consists of 10000 bits set
Bye
The use up that's the top half of that transmitted image and then the ten thousand
Party Shack beds
Which are set in such a way that over 10,000 constraints in the park check Matrix
Have the 10,000 constraints defined by the fire chat Matrix
All satisfied
And when you send
That
Overchannel
The
Received
That cut
Looks like what we see in this next slide hair this is a binary symmetric Time on Netflix 7.5% of the bits
And the animated gif that we will insert here somehow
Shows
The decoding
Of
This particular
Received
It takes about 15 Inspirations for the sum product algorithm
To figure out
What the correct state was
And the animated gif Loops through a few times during the decoding process
The
Performance of this particular error-correcting code which has raped on her for the binary symmetric Channel with a flip
The probability of 7.5%
Is shown in the right hand side of his slime
It has another probability a little bit smaller than one intent of a five
And that's
Quite close to the Shannon limit which is a bit bigger than
A rate of 1/2
And it's much closer to the Shannon limit than any of these textbook codes which is shown by the pluses
In the figure
And this rediscovery of Shannon's learning CPR cheat codes
Had a significant impact on the field of information Theory and coding Theory
In 1997 there was
At the International Symposium on information Theory the big information Theory conference it was just a single diaper on load
Tea party check coats namely the one by me and Richard Neal
Five years later the same conference
Had six interceptions devoted to Lowden State Park 10 session
Full of papers
Full on the topic of spacecraft codes Wichita
A code like these Lowden special codes defined in terms of spacecraft coats
Once it was established that you could get good performance from message passing algorithms
Sunspots crafts a whole industry was created
Inventing different sorts of spacecraft codes that
That could take advantage of message message passing
So my intention here is to show you how
If you look out for connections
You can discover that everything is connected
I'd like to thank you very much for
Watching these lectures if you watched all 16 you got a special prize
In addition to a free electronic copy of
The textbook on information Theory inference and learning algorithms you are also welcome to download now
A free copy of my other book sustainable energy without the hot here are the two websites for you to
Download the fuel prices from
So thank you again for
Watching these lectures and a big thank you to Emily Marino
The doing all the hard work of
Putting
These video lectures together
Thank you