Welcome to lecture 8 of information Theory pattern recognition and neural networks
This is one of the Pinnacles of the course where we will prove what for me is one of the
Mathematics of the 20th century Channel coding theorem
I will prove it the proof is in the book will give us proof
Complete proof for a special case
Today
What have we been well last lecture we defined the capacity of a channel
What channel is a set of inputs each which gives you a probability distribution
The way you get the capacity of the channel is you invent a probability distribution on the inputs
You been to find the mutual information between the inputs and outputs and you maximize at Mutual information
With respect to the auditory input distribution as a theoretical constructs that gives you this
Ticketmaster
And what we're going to prove today is that this isn't just an interesting number it is actually the rate at which
Virtually every communication is possible over that
That's a really remarkable thing is something for nothing result that
You kind of cheap reliable communication I-10 right as big as the capacity
So last time we Define the capacity and we started looking at a few simple examples of channels and asking the question
What is the capacity of this channel we looked at a few and I left you at the exercise
I'm looking at
The question is what is the optimal input distribution of this noise
And what's its capacity so please turn to your neighbor and discuss your answer to this
Question
Okay who's got a capacity first what's the capacity of this channel
Honeywell
Okay let me take you to it
It's the maximum possible vehicle information that you can get between input and output what's the mutual information
Well you can write it in a
Pair of different ways you can say it's the entropy of the output minus the entropy of the output
Conditional on the input
And we want to maximize that
So
What are these two objects
Well the second one is
What's a trivia on the input and
Any input gives rise to three possibilities with equal probability distribution you choose
Answer to this quantity is it just log
No choice about that
What's the entropy of the output while it's the Envy of what I've a distribution you end up spitting out onto the outputs if you were
S&B then you get a distribution that without your log 3
Bits of entropy but if you use a r uniform Distribution on head
What the biggest possible entropy you could get on why the output answer the uniform distribution
Can you achieve that yes I just told you one way of doing that so the answer is log 27
That's the maximum value that this can happen so this is the answer which is load nice
Capacity and the optimal input distribution is the input distribution that achieves
Maximum entropy on the outputs
By symmetry one way of doing that is to pick the uniform distribution so the optimal
Distribution is 137 137 137
And that is an input distribution for the Chiefs this maximum
Does anyone have any suggestion of an alternative input distribution
Is this the unique one or the other alternatives
Great so if you pick only the letters s a b e e h
Then
You're putting one
On each of those options everything
This has been nice property still that a uniform Distribution on those inputs Will Smith a uniform
Distribution of the outputs achieved its maximum
Nobody way of communicating reliably with the noisy type-ahead Channel namely you never use the other
You just use it and puts beh and Zedd
And therefore you can communicate reliably how fast can you communicate reliably 12 each time
You can take one of nine possible inputs that fall you will be today at 9
Fitspo YouTube channel
So this is another case slightly more interesting than the ones we had
Last week
This is a case where we can find a way of reliably communicating
At capacity of a noisy Channel coding theorem is true for this channel is giving us a bit of inside
How we actually sold communication over noisy channels one of the messages of today's lecture is going to be
That if you use any channel a lot of times
In sequence
Send a collection of say and uses of
Your noisy channel is a lot like
A noisy typewriter typewriter
Applies to
Noisy channels in general
So where we going
Is
We want to establish Shannon's noisy Channel coding Theory which says
Set for any channel
There exists coding schemes
Ditch Witch will have a rate and a
An era write a frequency of mistakes
Coding theorem says that you can achieve everywhere in this diagram
Right way down Albuquerque close to zero error probability while keeping the rate finite at
Which we have just defined
Maximum beats information
Is achievable
Plaza is known as evil and the exciting part
Of this theorem
Is
Respect the fact that you can get arbitrarily close to zero
With
Communication rights as close as you like to the capacity
So this is the really exciting
Part of the diagram
That
And that's what we're going to prove
Today
Namely that you can get anywhere in here as well that proved in the book and the fact that you come
Achieve anything over here is also approved in the book we wouldn't do that today
So his the only deer
Why we should believe this is true for a general Channel
We can introduce the idea of an extended Channel
Which means
The channel that you get when you use
End times in a row so for example if we're dealing with the binary symmetric Channel
You take and uses of it
And do not go yourself a channel whose possible input
Everything ranging from a string of n zeros
What was Arizona Juan
Lots of zeros 1:04 the way up to
So you got an input alphabet now size 2 to the n
For this example extended Channel output alphabet is the same set of strings in this case
Because they put up the binary symmetric Channel
The thing off of that
As the
Input
So
Hey.
If we take a binary symmetric Channel and redefined this new extended Channel
Each of these input can give cries and principal to any output at all but four Lodge and that will be
Typical set
Of
Outputs
Like this
So if you send all zeros
You can be fairly sure if any is very long that you'll end up getting an output that has about
And ones at FN flips
Plus or minus something fairly small that's going a square root event
That's a typical set for this particular input
So then put next door to it there's a typical fat
Which has a lot of overlap
So he is
The typical sat and every one of these has its typical set will have
It almost identical chemical set
End
In general for a general Channel
If you take all of these
Overlapping typical stats
And if you
Inputs to this extended Channel by using a probability distribution on the input
Of the type PX that we just been talking about when we Define the capacity so you pick each input
Symbol just from a distribution PX then
This collection of all the typical sets
That could come out here
Is going to have a size 2 to the end time to entropy of why
And the size of each of these typical sets
Will be about 2 to the end
Hrvy
Get an ex
Now cast your mind back
The noisy typewriter
Where did we got log9 bits from well we took the total number of typical
27 possible outputs 3/3 and we got nine
And that was how many known confusable inputs
Similarly here
We can take this extended Channel as long as that is really large
And we can imagine that we might be able to come up with a set of non confusable input
Do this extended Channel
And the number of known confusable
Inputs when I say non confusable I mean almost definitely
Long confusable inputs
Will be
The size of a typical set of outputs divided by the size of each of these Globes hat
CPN
Hrvy
Kevin X
Okay which is 2 to the end
X Mutual information
Which is h y - 8 Supply given X
I'm sorry if I repeat this is a story we just told picking inputs at random
But using the optimal input distribution we will maximize this thing here
And in that case we will that established that we could get
Don't confuse will inputs whose size it is to to the end
* the capacity
Which means that each time you use the extended Channel which is an uses of the
Original Channel
We can communicate and see bits by picking one of those known confusable inputs
So you can send NC bit
And channel uses
QED and that's amazing that's amazing result this is not a proof it's just us to the plausibility argument
To help you understand why this might be possible
But we're not going to do
Is we're going to actually prove his theorem for the special case
Of the binary symmetric Channel
Yes question
Okay
In the case of the binary symmetric Channel
The actual size of this entire space here is 2 cm
In general or general Channel it could be as big as alphabets
Size to the end so for General Channel
If you got an alphabet size a why you take that and raise it the power and that's the entire
Size of the conceivable alphabet
But what I've been said was you pick the inputs from sum distribution PX
And that's up to you and when you do that you may find you're not using the full range of the output alphabet
Which may or may not be a good thing
So you got to choose PX not been determined which tip
Optical input to using witch what your input sequence
That would mean you never send this one cuz you never said you'd be sending a typical small or over here
Unsimilar you'd never get half the channel or ones because that's very improbable to so it's possible if you want you could
Pick a probability distribution PX
Use the full outfit alphabet
For a symmetric Channel like this you're absolutely right when you do this optimization and he say how big can
Set of known confusable inputs make sure you got a nice uniform distribution
Very often the case
Okay
Any other questions
All right
Here is the proof
And will they cut them a bit more precise and I'll remind you what we already know about the binder symmetric
Channel and then we will prove the theorem for the binary symmetric Channel
Okay
So let's write down a theorem
The theorem says
That
For the binary symmetric Channel
Coin flip probability
Ass
The general theorem is for any channel
But we're going to prove it for this particular case
Minus magic tunnel with a flip table
Who is capacity
Is equals 1 - 8
Now we're getting them statement
For any
Epsilon
No matter how small
As long as it's bigger than zero Epsilon
Looks on this diagram
And for any rate
As long as it's more than anywhere in this yellow region
On this diagram
You can pick him in the number of times you use the channel
Nevaeh put that is full on Jenna fan
Then you can make a code that will be this good
Islam and specificity login there exist
With that length
I'm with the rate
Big unrightful to the audit would be requested
And the Dakota forgot code
Such that
The probability
Look era
Is less than
The required value Epsilon
All right
I'm going to clean the board like you to turn to your neighbor and remind yourself what you know about the seven for having Co
Which we introduced in the first lecture
Okay
The 7th element code when we encountered it in lecture 1
Look like
This
Handling coding rule very sad
The music gets to pick full bit switch everything hair S1 S2 S3
Then we use for constraints represented by the three constraints re
Represented by these three circles to set the remaining three of the seven transmitted bits
C5 C6
T7
Then we had a decoding rule that said
When you receive some receive bits you write them into this circle with three circles
You write and 127 into this diagram and you see
Which constraints are violated
Which is a positive so happy inside circles and then you use that syndrome to did you
The most probable explanation
Explanation being an account of which bits you think probably was flipped and then you can
Close ended 7 transmitted
It's probably what
Okay
So that was a 7 full hamming code
And it has the property that
If you flip any woman if the channel flips anyone bit then that bit can be
Era can be detected and corrected and we use that for the binary symmetric Channel
To take the rate down from wall
Venera probe self
Down to something that was more of order at squared
Since I was 7 full having code
What's the code to the race of 4/7 from one
And it had a small lateral probability examples of a block code
Now I'm the screen I'm showing you another way of defining is having for having code its
The same code but I'm showing you the three constraints by matrix and it has cooled the party check
Matrix
The idea is
That for any linear code you can Define the set of constraints
Buy a set of rows each constraint we will have three here three circles
Each
Constraint is defined by a row of The Matrix
Valley transmission satisfy this equation H * T where T is the transmission is equal to 0
That means that the top constraint gives you 0 second gives you there
Ones are in this Matrix is identifying which bits are in which Circle so this is the first Circle hair
This is the second misses the first
And
Circle one contains bits 123 and 5 which is why the Matrix goes 1 1 1 0
Okay
Circle 2
Has 2 3/4 and 6 so put the wanting comes 2 3 4 and 6
And the food Circle
134 + 78347
And
Because this particular code has the property that every one of the constraints is just
Moon dangling extra power keep it sitting in it you have As Nice simple property
Inside this Matrix the identity Matrix looking
And that makes the code very easy to encode you just slap in whatever values want for the
Best full bit then you can read out what these bits need to be set at 2 but in general you can make codes
You don't have a simple identity Matrix taking that coding a bit more difficult
But you can imagine codes that we don't have this nice simplification
Nevertheless you could come up with an encoding rules that use assets some number of bits k
Which hair is for
And then the total transmission of n Bits hair 7 is that in such a way
About these constraints off at the time
All right so that's the general way of describing and coding list of constraints that must be satisfied
Facenda set some of the bits the constraints determine the other bits
Then you receive
I received the factor which was thinking of us being t+ and when I + I mean mug
So didn't bitwise addition
What do you like to
We compute the syndrome which is which circles a happy and which are sad by x h x
That's cool that that is a name for the syndrome
8 * I
Will an example example let's say that we flip
Bit number
All right
Then whatever we transmit the way the sender is going to come out this is h x
T+
And that equals 8 * 2 + 8 * n
Which is just eight times and because whatever we chose to transmit satisfied
Hate something so we lose EHT molest of the syndrome that just depends on which
Cheap Fitbit
Then the transmission for example might have b0100
Transmission received my 2001
There is there is there a n f u x h x that thing
Written as a column vector
Then it'll spit out Wong Wong Sera
Which is
The three you find in the second column across
All right
And by looking at the syndrome you can say which of these columns possibly could be an explanation for the syndrome when you noticed
Right that's how easy syndrome decoding is in the Sky City just looking to Matrix suicide what is the one called him
That could have been explained this
In general
It's the noise has flipped more than one of its maybe a heart attacks to do syndrome decoding you got some
Received you hit with h and you got his ass and now the task is to say
That's a 10 I wonder what noise the noise was itself is actually an NP complete problems
But we're going to assume that we can
So that's not a problem
And come up with a guess all fan
Bazooka Lenhart
That's the job of the syndrome Dakota that you give it a syndrome comes up with the most probable explanation the smallest
Wait noise vaxxer
The accounts of syndrome
Okay so that's how the 74 hamming code works and
The way I've described it leaves itself very nicely to a generalization namely
Full big Iran
And for any code rate of your interested in you can't imagine making a much bigger Matrix h
So you can make with
And could be enormous
Nmroads
And
If we find K2 B N - M
Then
This set of constraints the Weaver sundown
Probably defines a code with a rate something along the lines of is k / n
It may not be exactly this right because if the constraints YouVersion down rst redundant constraint twice
Then it doesn't count you'll just subtract off one row that you haven't
Imply each other then this is the right of your coat
So if not describe for you the entire field of coding theory for binary channels the task adjust
To come up with architect Matrix
And you'll need a Dakota that consoled this
Problem here
And the accession of Shannon's noisy Channel coding theorem is no Mountain House movie
No matter how close the races to beer you can actually find a Linea
Have to do anything fancy and you can define a party check Matrix h
That will get you places you like to the capacity and it can have an error probability
As small as you like as long as we get to choose N&M
Sufficiently
Lodge
So that's what we are now going to prove
I'm going to prove it with the help of something that we had a few weeks ago remember when
Show me proof that data compression responsible
We sent you off
The lottery ticket office
And your task was to buy
The smallest number of lottery tickets for the bent coin Lottery such that you could guarantee that you were going to
The win the bent coin Lottery
We sold this by thinking about typical sets and you came home with a very large dusting bag full of
On the front of every ticket was a string of zeros and ones of length n
And all the tickets had roughly
A fraction F1
So the number of tickets that you bought all the typical tickets and the number of those we worked
What's 2 ^ enzymes the Bunny Ranch
Plus a little bit to do with square root of n
Which is small compared to end
So that was how many tickets you had in your very big fat
I'm not going to make use of those tickets to prove the noisy Channel coding theorem
As well
And you can imagine this working
In two ways
If I tell you the theorem that there exists a good code
The standard way of proving such a theorem is then to describe how to make that good code so I tell you what
That phone is required what is it
To make good symbol codes
So I'll give you an excellent and it would be nice if I could just give you and you will make
Which has the property that its rate is
Bigger than or equal to it and it's our probability
That would be cold a constructive proof and polite and civil society that if you
You say something is true but it's true
I'm over now going to do is a rather outrageous thing which is we're going to have a non-constructive proof I'm going to show you the
This is true that there exists
But it looks like this let's have an analogy set in Iraq so let's say some Skeptics about
At World diplomacy say that Ashley in spite of all magnificent invented interventions in Iraq
Exist
A malnourished child in Iraq which we decide
And one way to do that is the constructive method that you identified a child whose weight is less than a kilogram
The definition of identify
Unless the street they live on
But Shannon's method is not chica he got his all the children in Iraq
Absolutely all of the mini weighing machine
Waze
All of them simultaneously and find the total weight
Permit you can deduce the average weight of all the children in Iraq
And if that average weight is less than 1 kilogram
Then
That establishes a positive way that must be at least one baby with weight loss
Almost all of them
At least half of them
Must be malnourished
Without ever identify any particular one of them rushed
And that's the way we're going to prove Santa's naughty teleporting through I'm not going to tell you
A particular way of making the partnership Matrix what we're going to do is a great big average overall party checkmate
I will say what is the average Premier Humira of all of these
Easiest answer that question
Identify one good coat
Will find that we can make the average probability of all the codes
Tiny
We can make this more as we like
Bethel there exist
Potassium actually making a good code is left as an exercise for the Rita and that what coding theory is all about
Another filled with Decades of work now under its belt
Okay so that's the plan of campaign we're going to use our lottery tickets
We're going to
Use them in conjunction with the set of all conceivable partnership matrices and we will prove the theorem
On the therm Hair Says
It said before
Reliable communication what's next
We will
Take a linear block code so we will pick a particular party techmatrix H which will actually end up pic
Looking at random will imagine that we have chosen that
We can then Define eye syndrome Dakota
Using
That particular code
Ascendant Dakota is not going to solve
This
Problem perfectly without going to find the most probable end
I'm going to the fine for you
Dakota based on the syndrome which is going to be good enough
And then
Having done that we will have defined
An encoder and decoder for that particular code
And then we're going to average overall coats and find what the average probability of era is
Just check what my next
Slightest so this is what we're going to do
Imagine that we have chosen a block length and
Will adjust that later on if need be to make it even larger then
We have gone to the bank coin Lottery and we won the bank Coin Laundry by buying a sufficiently large number of tickets in a roll in the back
Anderol to the nh2 of f
We not take all of those tickets
And instead of doing what we did a few weeks ago which was roseto we want to be systematic and right little short names on the river
And use that
Space
For the English or object namely we're going to write down syndrome
Of that noise vector
Which is on the front
We're going to write down it's syndrome using the package check Matrix age that we've just chosen another reverse
Write down the syndrome syndrome is h x n
And that's
Adult Jackfruit length is m
It's okay
So you take every ticket
On the front is not a possible noise actor
An SS is the flip right of the Channel with dealing with her that's what I'm assuming then you can be
That
Uo
The ticket but is going to have today's No Electronic when we use the channel and times in succession
The winning tickets every single ticket you write on the reverse of that ticket Walt the syndrome would be
Of the noise Factor
Okay
17 drive me just computed by multiplying h x no.2
Then
Then what we going to do
Is
Encode in the standard way the standard way of encoding is you let
The user
Set K of the bits
Then you set the remaining mbits
So the transmission we can think of a few MC to T3 up to TK
Which might not be in this order
But transmitted bit set by the user
Then the remaining ones TK plus one or the end
By using linear algebra
To figure out what value these guys need to have in order that all of these constraints h x t equals zero
Are indeed satisfied
All right but I think Cody and we send it over the Tamil we got the receipt Factory Witch
Is
Transmission plus noise syndrome
Which is 8 something
Then we reach into the big nothing back for the tickets we look at the back of all of them until we find one
Syndrome on it
Or maybe we find several that have that syndrome on it
Hopefully does anyone know which is all gas
That's not decoding method
This approach
Could fail in a couple of ways
It could be that we don't actually own the ticket that has the correct noise Vector on it
That possible
But it's very unlikely because we've already bought enough tickets have a 99.999999
9% chance of winning the lottery
Why we put enough nines into that 99.9 to get along
It's going to be so we're going to hit at salon
So
The probability of error
The probability of stalia is a sum of two possibilities as we might actually have the winning ticket
The one that has the correct noisette dramas
The other possibility is
We have got the winning ticket but was another ticket in the bet in the bag so we don't actually know
Which noise that just happened
So the Progressive Era is equal to the sum of two times
Uncle P Wong
Mp2
P1 is the probability
That
And is not in the bank
This is the Progressive Era of the entire and coding and CPT coding system is defined using a particular Matrix
H
Orvis
Code
With architect Matrix
H2O is the probability that depends on age
The first time is the Pro Bowl
I actually don't depend on the bag we just bought there's nothing to do with h when we both all those tickets
The best time is actually
Independence
The P2 is the other possibility explanation
And that says what I am is in the bag
But
And poodles
M&T Bank
Oops
I also in the bag
That satisfy h x and twiddle is equal to that
Or if you like eight times the difference between and and and twiddled is 0
Habitat Community but to see if you understanding me so far this is the most
Okay are there any questions about the
Commissions to the Progressive Era
Kevin on board
Okay so we can say the fan is not in the bag
That we can make the probability of that as small as we like
By picking
And Lodge
I'm being careful with this thing that I'm so fudging a little bit which is the size of a typical fats which is Tuesday and
H2 of f
That will come back to that. Fudge laundromat Edinburg we can make this place so small in the right sense
The first time is dealt with just by making an enormous
The second time is much more exciting this is the one that actually depends on eggs because if I picked some
The lights for example one with all the rows identical then maybe it's much more likely that you'll have identical syndrome
You can imagine all sorts of ways in which an H could be bad it is very easy to make vodka
Okay so let's write down the second time
That'll definition of it
P 2 of 8 is
It's a sum over all possible noise that cuz
Subject to them being in the bag
That we bought
Let Me Wait by the probability of that happening
I think that counts
Warm
If there's another End Portal in the bag
And 0 if not I'll give us the Progressive Era
Is warm if the thing in Brackets is true and it's zero otherwise
If there existed and twiddle
Such that
Anvil is not the same as an
And twiddle is in the bag
+ 8 * + - + twiddle
Is there a
So this is the function which is warm if the number of clashes that we've got
Illinois Vector that actually happens is bigger than or equal to one
Okay if and twiddle the question was why does it matter event riddles in the back
We only have a problem if when we're reaching into the bag and look at the back of each other
Because we found two noise that gives it a different from each other
So it has to be in the bag
Takoda's trouble
I think because then we don't know what that is
The Assumption we're going to be biting
Is
That
Yeah the way the Dakota what is if you find the Cinderella on the back
Then
Retarded iPhone
Exactly one ticket that has a tender lump on the back
That will fail if we haven't got the right noise if we have got the right one in the bag
Another one in the back with the same syndrome
Okay
All right this is slightly coming proof maybe because it's using this notion of a syndrome Dakota
Maybe not
In the book which is the preferred general channels and you can look at that you
Right
This proposition is saying but the number of classes is bigger or equal to one
If you think about that
Function
That is a function which other function of the number of classes
Stop being
And then increases when you hit warm to the body of warm and then it remains
Guam
How many classes are all screwed
Which means we got to Wong out of this expression so the function with that
As a function of the number of classes it looks like this
How's the property
Vantage is less than or equal to
Which is the number of flashes
Okay so in yellow off showing the number of classes
In white
We have the function
Number flashes
It's raining right now
Why am I leaving this I want you to be clear that the other function is bigger than the white function
Nah
What should we do next
Let's
Use an inequality
And
Let's do a bit of redefining
But I'll rewrite this as
Awesome a proposition which is going to be the yellow lot
So now let's do Daniela
I'm going to add up
The some overall and riddles
But I'm not able to the noise active it actually happened
Subject to the constraints and twiddle is in the bag
I'm going to ask
Hello is the end riddle
Is your syndrome the same as the syndrome
Which is
The function h m i n Central
Is equal to 0
All right so I've relaxed this thing I've made it bigger
I'm not saying a piece of its smaller than its functioning as long as I can
Then I've also established his time
That's why I was staring I'm trying to manipulate P2 into a form where we can say I have if I do this
I can make it tiny
Power
Just fine
Yes
So this is the number of any twiddle to clash with me is the number of them because I'm not coming over oil and twiddles
All right Services looking at every single one of them and has an enormous number
Place the simple comes to hair which is either 0 or 1
Buy a sum of two to the NH avesta a trillion times
If any of the match will get someone
So we just this relaxation
No
The next thing we're going to do
We made a little bit of progress we've simplified this a little b****
And still got an H dependents in it
What we end up we want to end up showing is that we can make this very small
And it's going to be difficult to do that with any particular right so get the average overall H's and show that the average
P2
Is very small
So when I get to look at average of P2
I'm going to average over
Ohsi when I say average overall they just I just mean literally take the set of all possible binary Pirates check
Matrices and pick completely independently around so every 0 or 1
Is 0 warm
Photography 50/50
Right
Suck the average ability to choose is the some overall h
Pfh
Somerville and
In the bag
See you then
Some event rental in the back
And with a lot equal to end
No justice no P event Ritalin half the recipe of n
It's just
How they act is working
And we have Wong
Types of ax equals there I would have to find a new thing
X is defined to be
+ - Central
All right
No
Let's reorder the summations little bit
We'll take the song over and in some of the French poodle
Outside and put some of H
On the inside
So have a sum of and
In the bag
Okay then
Summer Event riddle
In the bag
But not the same as an
Some / h h
Wang
If 8 * x equal 0
Inside by definition the difference between an event rental
All right
There was something overall
Typical noise actors
Waited by the overall typical noise that doesn't riddle
And then we look at the question if you take the difference between nose and hit it with the Matrix h
What's the probability
Averaging over old matrices age that you will get zero that's the meaning of this time in hat
Suck to answer that question
This thing here
Is
The probability that
Is it all given a particular f8x now would give an ax because once defined
And in this some event rental in this song we've got hostiles next
Now hair this is the probability for that given X
The probability that
The first row of the Matrix x x is equal to 0 times the second row of the
Is there a drug
Is Matrix x x is equal to 0 where H is this randomly-chosen Matrix who's Rosario
Guam
H2
Kh3
Dot-dot-dot on all of those accession
Texting a little Sideshow which is the exercise where we understand this problem
Forget everything you just been doing
I'm think about this extremely simple mathematical question
If I give you a fixed back to X which is non zero
It's nonzero because in fact is the difference between two noise actors and that's all different from each other
So that makes it non zero if I give you a fixed
Back to act which is non-binary in the spotlight stand
And then if I bring along a single row of this Matrix
Just one road and if I call it element H1 H2 H3 H4
What's the probability
The end of product between h
FedEx
Is there a
Habitat
Your neighbor
If it helps think about just this special case have it on the board with
Back to the blanks
Okay
The question is
What's the probability that one row of this Matrix
X x
Give zero
Would you like to
Any thoughts
Lockpicking the H's
Completely at random by flipping a Fair coin
Exit to fix Vector which has zeros in some places
And it's got some ones in other places
China special case here
The value
8 shot X is actually equal ch2
Lights for
Modulo 2
So let me ask the question another way if I take 3
Coins
And I say we're going to get her number
Which is either going to be all don't even I'm going to get it by adding up the outcomes of the coin tosses in the coin says what
On one side and 0 on the other
The question is if I add up
The number of ones and find out if it's old or even
If each of those coins is 50/50
If I add up all three of them what's the probability I got
An odd number
Okay yeah
It's 50/50
Does that depend on how many coins I had it up
No
Because I was just one of them or even if I give you any number whether it's a little
And now I flip another coin and I had that number is still 50/50
Okay
So the answer is
The probability that the top row x x gives you 0
Is a Hof
Not true
Feniex
So now the problem is that
All of these assertions are true the probability that you
When you go to give an act which is the difference between two noise that does as it happens
Okay that's the answer to question 1
Now the question is if I
Take a fixed X
Just as the 400m rows of this Matrix and I make them independently
By tossing coins
What's the probability of the first red contacts
Etc
How to talk to you later
Access fixed
I flip coins to seven letter that comes out or even
I'm a flip coin 7 comes out all the raven
It's 50-50 whether total revenue
How to flip coins for the next one Federal independent of each other so the probability even
Everything is
Hoffa Poweramp
Anyone think an alternative answer is 3
No
Anyone
I don't want to sleep or shy
Okay
So this is the correct answer
So we made a little progress cuz suddenly this is all disappeared
But it's just half the power and
And vanishes so up the next slide okay we don't want that
Average of p205h averaging overall h
Is
The song over the o n in the bag
Wasted by Pia van
Some overall length twiddle
Leather in the bag
And the time not the same as an
Then we do the Salvation / h
Listen time quantity half we just argued is off to the power 10
Which is the number
With no dependents
I just don't know Independence and interdependence either
Because it depends on X and the answer to that question we just answering didn't depend on X1
Just got out of the number
And the number is 1/2 of the m
X
The number of individuals that are in the bag
Left
Averaged
Over the distribution
And this thing doesn't have any dependents on an
So we can just say the some overall line in the bag will a maximum one isn't it
Time
The number things in the bag let's round up that -1 and say I was to to be to the end times entropy
Tuesday nh-27 size of a typical set
Little bit
That's the number things in the back
And then that multiplies aha
How to power amp
What are we done reviews Shannon's malnutrition detection scheme
To establish that if you average over absolutely all linear codes
The average performance of those codes
The probability of Mara if you use a slightly deranged syndrome Dakota with the lodge
I've been back for the tickets
The probability of error
Is
Progressive Era
Is lesser April therapy one which we can make tiny
Plus this all the time what you're coming this Saturday make time it depends on what nhu of F&M
Sorry
To the power
Let's put it downstairs so it'll be clear
What tiny looks like the one over
2 to the
Minus
And
H2off what's a little bit
Okay
I miss talking to him here
This time can be made arbitrarily small if well it vanishes is
Is much bigger than nh2 Avast
Rearranging that says if I move in
Is bigger than 8 to advance
Or rearranging again into terms
That we do like
1 - M / n
Is less than
One- H2O
I just run out of boards because that
It's saying
But this second time here vanishes
The right
His last
Van
The capacity
Guess the race
Is what channel this particular channel is 1 -
H2O
Thus we have proved noisy Channel coding for the binary symmetric Channel
Of s
And we did it by using sing Dustin bag
How do we already used to prove the source heading to proofs
The price of love
Are there any questions
American have questions about everything we've done in the first
Electra yes
Okay
So
Right
So the question is
What was this step from here
2 hair
Yeah alright why is it bigger. Hopefully that's going to be easy let's just make clear what we're doing here
At this point we were saying
I'm worried about the possibility this annoys back to Mike come along
Such that
There is another noise that cat in the bag with the same syndrome
On the probability of era
Is the probability
That
The number of such classes is he the one or two or three or four
That's a very complicated proposition to deal with if I tell you I want to know the probability that the number of classes
This is either one or two or three or four
And I don't care whether it's one or two or three or four
It turns out to be much much easier to say
Take this ticket out of the bag I want to know what the probability of clashing with this ticket
Then after that the provision flashing with this one
Then add the prophetic blessing with this one so I take every single ticket and separately book how was the probability of a classroom
Central
Then at all of those up
I'm not much easier because I answer a question about just
The original end and the end twiddle on this ticket that's much easier thing
Astrakhan we could answer that question then at least we could do the averaging
Easily
If we do that if we say what's the probability of a class with this one
And what's wrong with you besides for this and if we then add all those up Ashley over counting the probability of era
Because errors which may be rare is will occur when there is a clash Nick could be the Clash
Clumps
The wind there was a Clash
Revista Cara's
I'm so adding up the probability
Old individual crashes and adding those together gives you over estimate
Of the probability of era
Because you got only one IRA
When does the big car crash of clashing with each other
So we deliberately overestimating
The true probability of Ira
Bye
Taking a simpler thing to compute
Does a standard name for this cuz I forgot to note the type of mathematical operation we doing Harris
Union bound OK Google the union bound
All right
So you got a load of different possibilities that you're worried about
And if any of them happens it's bad news what's the probability of bad news happening
Well we're going to work out the probability of bad things happening
Then workout has a bad thing to them what kind of problems can Bad Thing 3 happening together
That will actually overestimate the true probability of a bad thing happening
That's the meaning of this inequality
Any other questions
It's a union that
But any questions about this proof
Any questions about
Let's just want to 8
Because we're now essentially done with information Theory
Not told you the whole of information Theory compression bit
Where's on the noisy Channel coding bit
That's all there any questions about
Great depression when was Utah County
Okay
Okay so the question is how do these tickets relate to pay which of
The sender and am which is the number of constraints the number of constrained
Find a code that way using
The tickets that we bought
Hypotheses written on them
Of what the noise vaxxine might be
And they all have the property that they got lots of zeros in a small number of 1
Because we know by typicality
That it's very likely that the actual number ones will be a Bath & F bus line
Flatter yourself
Find some little X Alpha to ensure that 99.9999%
Probability that the number of Long's
Looks like that
How does this relate to the sender is choosing to send
Well it's completely unrelated cuz he's noise actors added to the transmission
To the transmission itself
House just the same length
That will be a subset of those bits which conventionally often sits at the left hand side but don't have to
I'll be a subset of them
Numbering k
Which are set by the user so he's will be so that's one S2 S3 up to SK
And then the remaining ones will be sent by the constraints
Shelby these end of a bit
Tek plus one up to TN by the constraints
This is what we send it has
Nothing to do with the noise that goes it won't look like any of them it's very likely to be a dentist
These ones are very likely to look down as well
So that's what gets transmitted what's been received is the sum of these two
Then we hit that with the syndrome operation which is HJ bring on h u attacked people ascend
Which is received manga
Give you then
That value is that
Is 8 * 2 + 8 * n
Which is 8 times n
Which is completely independent of t
So yes the user was able to choose K if a bit since that them and then the constraints will use them
But the syndrome doesn't depend a******
It's completely independent
Whether we will achieve successful communication on this particular the use of the channel
Will depend on what end is because our success will be
Determined by the syndrome Dakota being able to identify and or not
Whether we succeed or not depends on
The center of Dakota identifying and that has nothing to do with T is completely independent
712 Harmon Cove we have the property that if you flip a bit
Then
You can detect that flip bit and it doesn't matter what the source
Choice Watson
Okay
So the 7 full having code is the analogy to use have to understand why
T doesn't matter at all
If we succeed
Then we will have identified an and we can add it back on to to some practice so sorry we could
Subtract it back off the receiver actor and did you steal again
That's how we actually would recover the transmission
Any more questions
Thank you for being here