Okay welcome to the lecture 10
When I tank Cambridge and study Physics I have the privilege of being taught by Steve Gall and I asked him
How to solve this exam question which I suspect he was the examiner for when it was originally set
We've got
Events with an exponential distribution we don't know Lambda
We can only see the events if they happen in a window that goes from one centimeter to 20 cm
Look at all the x coordinates of the points we want to infer Lambda
I like to start off by asking you what is
Before you heard about Bayesian inference
How would you have gone about solving this problem using
Classical statistics methods that you got stored during a Physics course or at High School
Seat of the pants
Method
So would you like to tell me
Approaches you might have used in general or specific approaches you would use to solve this
Task
Yeah
Gradient descent in what so you're going to maximize or minimize something
So the idea is optimized
Something something that you would optimize
5%
Okay so optimized a measure
All discrepancy
Between
Weather
Might look like that
And
The probability density
But you got if you pick up a particular value
Lambda
Okay
So that sounds a reason why do you some data
You have some summary of a data and then you adjust your model says to get a good fit
Let's go to a bit more detail how are we actually going to guess a measure of a discrepancy
What if there are three
Data points for example
If it's up for an hour wake up three points
Or there might be a hundred what did you have in mind and
Okay
So I got a window somewhere to collect Delta X
Chop up your day to world into little windows in size Delta racks
How many points are in each
Linda Grant
Okay
So we have Windows in the bins
So this is an example of how we get a measure of discrepancy
Preventive measure discrepancy and to do that we're going to put in bins
Which might look like
This webpage is not account then or if we are
Look like
Okay
I noticed something you have to choose was this
Had to be chosen
In order for this to work
Okay
Save-A-Lot School Ms
Well I'm at 2 at three of the count in each of these things
That we've got
So you compare that with what the model with parameter Lambda would have per day
I'm guessing
So
Let me check if you agree with this
You could work out given Lambda
What the expected value
Of asked in a particular bin would be
And
That would give you
Expected number two
Half half half
Like that
When you
Talk about him some sort of measure of how far apart they are was it the distance between
Mountain View expected in mind
Some sort of inner product Okay so
All
One measure of goodness of fit
Which I was suggesting is we some overall the bends
The distance between FB and expected value of FB
Giving Lambda
Repetitive taking absolute value
Call
Square or something like that that was some of the squares Maybe
Is a measure of how close they are old
To each other
So that was the thing I was
Guessing
How about adult product goodness-of-fit to is a measure of how similar these two vectors to each other
In a product of FB
With
Pats Peak
All right
Let's just have a quick think about that
If we spend the square
We got some of that be
We get some of that to be square
Minus
To some of FB
FB
Averaged
Plus
Son of a b
Average of S&P
Squid
So if I
Minimize this thing
With respect to Lambda and if you maximize this thing with respect to Lambda
We're going to get pretty similar answers only because
Actually this is just a constant as long as we use the same bin sizes each other
About to constant
Once the bins been chosen
I miss Lawton okay
Things are actually quite similar
Not exactly identical because of this difference
Okay so you got to measure goodness of fit
And something you might have the back of your mind is all these questions that we have friends
? how did you choose Delta Rex
How to choose
Between different measures of goodness of fit
I'm not saying either of these is a good
The first one
Has anyone got another approach to this method to
Optimize gradient descent with suggested as long as we find
When we've done the optimization it will spit out I guess Alondra the best fit
Does anyone have
Another approach because there are many approaches you got taught when you'll be into it
Ad hoc statistical methods
I'm sure some of you thought of methods that don't look like
Jesse Owens
So what's the price of gas in his approach to answering the question what is Lambda
Okay so
What dancing do you have in mind for this this problem
Okay the data points that that x-coordinates
Okay the x-coordinate solve these guys are exponentially distributed maybe I need to make Claire walk the assumption
Prxn
Given Lambda and
The window edges A&B
Is
Vanessa exponential one of these
82 -
Facts
Lambda
If x is
Between a and b
And it
Otherwise
All right
Whereas it is the integral from A to B
People minus X on Lambda
So the actual probability density of each acts if we knew Lambda is an exponential
There are possibly some gas stations running around in this for example
If I
Define a bin
And if we measure the count of how many points are I did not been
It may be true that the probability distribution of that count
Which is actually a distribution of integers it may be reasonably well approximated that's impossible
Direction you could go in that the definitely does involve
Calciums
Does anyone else have a completely different approach to this
Problem
Did anyone study Physics
No one else
Yeah ok Google
Isn't it the case that when
Little young physicists I told to do stuff with that data
Fat toad
Get the data
Rearrange the equation that predicts the data given the premises in such a way that got a straight line graph
Straight line isn't that one of the rules of had to do
Statistical inference
So let me run with that idea
Sir
Best wispy of xn
Given Lambda a + b
62 - x on Lambda
/ that
I said depends on Lambda AA on big
If we got a load of points Acts
How can we turn this love into some sort of straight line well
Let's
First X little window as we had before been size P of X and given Lambda AMV
X Delta X
That's now
The
Probability that the next point will fool in this particular been located at
Skibidi
Analysts think of this as a function of x
This is the probability that the next point will full in a bin of size X plus minus
I've been
Or would sell tax located on X approximately all right
So if I multiply that by the total number Vega points we got
Which is an
That's the expected
Number
In a bin
And that is equal to and on Zaid
A two- axon Lambda
We want some way of turning this
Expected number which will relate to that to measure number into some sort of straight line
Thing that would measuring his ex so that's
A variable list
Changes as you move the been around
Under the / Lambda
That's horrible but we physicists we know how to get rid of exponential to take the log
And
So you can have the log
Of the expected count
In
I've been at x with with Delta X
The log of expected count
Is log off and on Zed which is something the constant
Minus X
Lambda
That's not a straight line with an intercept of something-or-other and a slope of -1
Linda
All right
So if you've been subjected to the physics
Training the size of a high school thing to do is take the money and get a straight line
And everyone knows how to say so
I didn't number one was
Let's
Put the diaper to Ben's I got a histogram that doesn't solve the problem when I need to do something with a histogram
Things we could do with a histogram notice I've done it twice and it was fat beans one
Time to just emphasize the answer we end up with may depend on the size of a penis
His the
Physics education idea to take the log of your Instagram then fit a straight line
So the suggestion is
Take the actual data
The thing that is true is that the log of the expected number is
Some constant minus X on Lambda
But we're not going to do is take the actual beta
FB
Who can take the log of that
Unplug that against tax
And what I'm going to fit a straight line
Is a lot of extra questions getting raised by this approach when we say fit a straight line
How to fix a straight line to just use this straight line fitting thing that comes on your computer that's probably won't
To do
But something that could very easily be the case is when you define your bins
If you define them before you actually get today to it to the sort of correct way to do classical statistics you shouldn't change up
Best way to ask to look at it
It could well be the case that won bin might have their accounts in it
Not when you take the log of 0
You going to have and not been
Log of 0 you have an infinitely negative value to put into your straight line fishing method
So
It all sounds pretty good and it looks fairly good what if you get lucky
Up on the screen
With nice fat Benz and lots of data you can see a straight line
I was going to give you the rights
Universal method for answering problems
So just use to Benny's
Okay so here's another suggestion
Take the data
Put it in only two bins
I know we going to fix the bins before hunt or Willie set the boundary between the bins
What you wanting to do is make sure we got some points in each bin yeah and then do something
This is a number 3
You fit a straight line
I didn't number for is just used to bins but be smart about where you put the bin battery
Three points
What are the two bins going to be
Wicked
Well hello hello hello
I have two in one bed and one in the other or one in one and two in the other
It's a nice idea it's probably
It was probably something in it
But it still got pitfalls namely if you actually end up with two points you trying to struggle
Because of the loss of all between us now by the way you put your Ben batteries
Okay
Are there any other suggestions
Pat's exhausted a whole bunch of different laser
Making been putting it into Benz
And then doing something with those histograms
What other ideas
Okay so another suggestion suggestion number 5
It is
Could we look at
The cumulative distribution
So
His ID number five
If I give you some data like that you can deduce from it
Image of distribution which is nothing
She said
3/3
So that's the cumulative
Distribution function from any particular hypothesis
It says what Lavender is used to find the probability density
CDF
For that value of Lambda which will be
Something like that
Okay
And now we've got a thing that has little steps and it wherever they Point happened to come
And we could repeat now
Let's have a measure of how close this is to this
Now we need to decide what time is replacements
And where do we measure it so we can measure it here in here in here in San Antonio
Distances between
These two
CVS
How many topping way of measuring distances between the two differences of decision about
What's the density of points at which we measure the difference
Albuquerque
Well I only care about the TGIF in this weekend
Hawaii
Does an issue of
How do you measure
I need to come up with ways of measuring how close
Ccdf soft
And I do that is a problem because it means there's an infinite number of ways
But answering the question how do we fit
Lambda
2 States at what we think Landry's
So we could do things with TDS
That would get rid of Ben wittes but it still leaves some interesting questions leftover yes
Brilliant okay so how do we find the mean of a gaussian distribution
Well we just take snacks and we some of us it was right by Anne
I'm not giving us the number
Enfig options
New hot equals x bar
So that's something we can do with no bins at all we can take all of these days we can take some of that sand
Because the windows going to left hand side remember the left hand side of the window
Is at a
They don't have any points to less that I made it would be sensible to subtract a
Now that's an interesting thing about the me
Distance from
And that clearly has
Unexpected dependent on land of the big of a value Lambda has the more the Pine-Sol search to the
Right hand side and eventually The Middle on average
If you have a really large
Then you have a uniform distribution
So this isn't precisely related to Lambda
But in the case goes to Infinity
If the window is infinitely wide on the right hand side
Then
Something you might remember about exponential distributions is the meaning of this guy
Is Ethan mine effects on Lambda now
With no window
The mean of this distribution is Lambda
Okay expected value Max is Lambda
So I think that's a really good idea to say maybe there's something in the idea of computing to me
Absolutely we can
Let's have a measure discrepancy between the
And
The predicted me
Let's imagine doing that it is not a very difficult calculation to do
I will keep asking questions as well
Set
The expected value of x
For the real distribution is the integral from A to B
8 - x on Lambda
Text / Zedd
And you cancel that and it's a function all day being lined up so this is some sort of
Escort new off
Hey Atlanta
If this is a
This is B
How much is Lambda what Mew actually looks like his is roughly Linea down here
And then
It flattens out like that
So that's what you of
Baby in London actually looks like
Another suggestion is take all the title take your 1000.4 your message to enormous precision
The throw away all of the position of that and just out of mouth
Okay
Why did you compute the mean you're throwing it all away love information there
Information
But you can do it and then
You got to do something with this kind of hair
So you would come out what the actual datamine is
So you bring a long ax bar
Define the actual me
Which I'm not a defining to be the sum of X and Iran
You bring it along and use it through this line
Can you plop it downstairs and you said okay there is an estimator
Salamander
Not what you had in mind
I like that idea
Don't have any beans in it
But it didn't go very big step for saying I'm going to compute the me
And you could have said
I'm going to compute the variance or I'm going to compute V moment or you could have invented a whole load of other things to make
And then you could have plotted them
As a function of Lambda so another thing
Could have been plotted as a function of Lambda
And then you got to your day turn you come down and say or it could be anybody
Not an infinite family of things that you could do I think this is a brilliant idea and you'll see why in a moment
Does an infant number of things you could invent which depend on Lambda
And you could
Pick one of those and then measure it and use it to come back and get an estimate of Lambda
So that's another thing that is done in Costco statistics
And it
Can often be done well
And you can also get in trouble cuz what if the 3-day points is a is B
That could happen right
You got any free points
Rolls-Royce
The midpoint
So now you work out the mean and it's above the midpoint of a b
And now you don't know what to do because your methods head
Come across from the title value and read down
And I haven't got an answer anymore
Okay
There's lots of ways to solve problems the wrong way
I'm reminded of a Penn and Teller video at Penn and Teller studying a controversial topic
And
Hotnewhiphop
And they interview a guy who has also the reason for the engine UK and they say we believe in violence on our show so
We gave attempts to every part of you express from the idiot now let's hear from a guy who's right
Let's now so this inference problem using Bayes theorem and there will be a unique answer
He'll be one answer to the public in any case with any case with any amount of data 3 days
3000 data points
Angela National think
You got the right answer you don't need to choose being sizes you don't need to invent measures of goodness of fit
You don't need to invent interesting functions like the meaning of the data which in this case is a brilliant holiday
Put another problems
You might struggle to think of the brilliant idea
You don't actually need to think you need to know what you're doing
Need to get it right
But it is a mechanical
And it don't take yours
To get used to doing things the Basin way
So how does it work
All right
So here's a list of other ideas that people I can come up with I think we've gone through them
Open when I asked the question how would you solve this problem
People say Chi Squared
And that goes back to the bins story have to count in the bin
Many measure the difference between accountant expected
He's getting for chi-square
So that
We already had that roughly in methods 1 and 2
Images of Arrow between the fairy in the beta
Look at the day to me
And see how that very lined up or pick some other quantity and see how that varies with Lambda
Any ideas
That are out there and I will do it using Bass Down
That's right down again what's the probability of the data is
For single data point given Lambda
This distribution is 8 -
Text my mom.
Is that is the indigo
Thanks
Online de
I need to do the integral
It's not hot it is Lambda Eastman - aeon lender Finance
Reminder speed on Lambda
I really want to emphasize how easy and straightforward and simple with his
And
It's just a few lines of computer code cuz all you need to not put into your computer is this statement which Define
PMX giving Lunde
And then you put in this one which defines house that depends on Lambda
And now you're done because it says that you can infer Lambda
Given by just multiplying together
All these things are so you have
How late is 1 + 11
Angelo Devita - x 10
On
Lambda
Is that is a function of Lambda Lambda
Depends on x
Does Linda Pennington hair this length
Flying together
And that that is your likelihood so this is the only active
Honda
They multiply that by what Avenue about Lambda beforehand
Andino mice
And this is the uninteresting normalizing costumes that you don't care about if all you want to do is
Compatible scientific theories about Lambda
Let's look at the meeting yesterday too dependent best
And this is where the first time you see this
I find it just thrilling to automatically happens
You take this function
Let's stick with the slice
His the code you need to write down
I've written it and blue fault which is a language that you can use to define functions
Time Portland
It's hard to find a function P of X and Al which is
Dysfunction hat
X and Lambda Lambda sternadel on the bus
So the top line to find P the second line to find Zedge
Define said slightly differently put the one over Alan to the PA
But it's
That's a good one
Redefine a redefine B
And then
We can float these as a function of X which is the normal way of placing these things so you fix Lambda
Any plot of x given Lambda as a function of X and it looks like
Very normal
So that's what it looks like the three different values of Lambda
How to have a very smooth
Welcome to my time left
Happy big Lambda
Uniform distribution
But every one of these probabilities integrates to Wong and it's a little very normal
Find the area under
The Green Cove
Is also
That's all very standard and very simple in the chest exponential's
And then baystorm says like I know you want to know the line with the given actually just
Plot the same function
But look at it
How's the function of Lambda
Play take these innocent exponential functions I'm looking the other way around
And this is what they look like so this is the probability of x
Given
Lambda
Sorry it's not
Okay
Ind.vs to do this we need to fix that to a particular value so I'm showing you three different
Time for three different possible accessrx good bo3
This is what direction Lambda looks like for 3 Lite Luca
The five it's the blue one
12 it's the purple one
An amazing thing is just one of those functions
Take a Bow
If we fix x-23 and then plot of x given Lambda as a function of Lambda
The horizontal axis hair
And I put it on a log scale
It's got a pink
So a single data point
Is not giving you this nice PC function and saying
That
Just one datapoint that happened to arrive at
X = 3
That one day 2.90 tells dude
Tell Jason opinions you won't have about different values of Lambda
Extremely small values of Lambda close to zero
Essentially ruled out by us
Values of land initiative to also
Tiffany happy they did a good job before the dance
Matilija values
A slightly ruthann but nobody much they just slightly penalize compared to
Lambda is too also
So just one datapoint
Can tell you something about what language should be and as you piling more more data points
Multiply these functions by each other
The special case of a data point this out beyond the midpoint
Gives you the purple line here
Which STI can we can definitely rule out tiny bodies of Lambda there's no way Lambda could be Point 10.3 or something like that
I got a pint at 12 that's crazy so that's ruled out
But all values of Lambda from 10-20-30 100 day rule equally probable
Predictive estate appoint equally well
Because they will protect essentially uniform distribution so that equally unsurprised by saying evaluation
Okay
So we will play these together
When you multiply those functions together hair of X functions imagining that there are just three days points at three 5
5 and 12 * speak
We can
I think a bit more about what this function actually is how does the function depend on the data
Well this particular function depends on the writer MSY
Let's go eat in the minors
Suck it up staff Ethan Miner
Sum of x n
Atlanta
Is all you need to know in fact
So I'm rewriting the likelihood
So the brilliant intuition that said why don't you just compute the mean of the data is exactly right
Exponential then the only thing you need to know is the sum
And then you can work out the lights
So you don't actually need to know all the data points
You just need some of them
Because of this particular form
All of the probability density
If the model didn't look like this it wouldn't be in the meeting that is the thing you need to know
The lessons of the alphabet is not computer
What you need to do is look at the likelihood function under like its function will tell you what you want to do with your date and in this case
Find the mean
And then
Good function and on the screen we have a likely function math
And
I can
Recreate these cuz we're just looking at
Again
So
Here are
I'll just repeat the sequence I did
Here are three probability densities over data Space X
You could imagine getting data at Point such as 3 or 5 or 12
The predictions of these different models of different values of Lambda a simple exponential that's something you can know.
Is there a places for example the left-hand Blue Line
Where the red is above the oranges above the yellow
So the Red Wings it predicted that
The places where the yellow is above the oranges above the red
Under places where the oranges top
So there are outcomes
Such that any of those three can be the winner in terms of having
Predicted Betha
Then the other two
That's another way of saying
When then they will be at Peak
As a function
Lambda
So now we do that we put the likelihood function
And this is the likelihood multiplying together those three
Numbers
I'm not showing in red orange and yellow cat just three values of Lambda that we were considering remember that we looked at Landry's
25 + 10
This is when you get data
MP3
At the three points
I mentioned before
Okay
Step one more time
What's going on
Triangle
Okay
So just getting through the sequence again
His three places you could get data
I left on point points to the red hypothesis being the most probable
Datavant at 5
Prefers by publish The Landry something like five
And they Point inside prefer to be 10 or so
To the hypothesis that Landers 205
So this is what the likelihood look like if you got just one data point that is respectively at 3 or 5 or 12
And this is the product of x
Okay
That face serum
So finding a single parameter Lambda
Wasn't that easy because all you have to do
Was right
Essentially
Warm
Three lines
Define the function and now we've got this bump that tells us
The answer
What time does Walt how well
Predicted points
Another word for 3000 datapoints as well
Yeah
Okay who said anything about picking Lambda
The question said what is Lambda and I think the correct way to answer that
Is either do you really want me to take less Lambda if so tell me how
But if someone says what is Landry I think the correct way to answer that question is whether it's roughly this O+ o- this the way
Answer my question
How heavy is this book
I don't want to get a give me a number
I wanted to say well it could be
Do underground + -100 I'm not very good at estimating weight to books
So
Dumb question said what is Lambda it didn't say provide a single point estimate
If you want the point estimate guess what I might maximize the likelihood
But
I'm not addicted to maximizing like it's because you could get silly answers remember when we go we're looking in the gas industry
Division
I miss the gaussian with a single data point
Had infinitely big likelihood
Down here this is Mew
Are Swiss log Sigma Nu
Maximizing like it it doesn't have any fundamental status
It may well be better than a whole lot of other ways of doing things and principal
Can be dangerous
What would I say is answer I would return the likelihood and if someone wants a quick summary of rough
What the likelihood looks like
I would see if I can find a peek and I'd give some description of Hyrule Deepika
So
A very common thing you can do with a tail like this is if you got more than three datapoints
You can probably make a gassy and fit to that blue cup on the screen
What is the formula for it
A function that will compute the likelihood and here is a Galaxy an approximation to that it's called this mean in this standard deviation
So that the general method I'd I'd suggest
But often works well
You take your likelihood function
And your proxmate
The likelihood
Buy I got a chance baby
That isn't the rule but it's a suggestion
When you approximated by gas you need to describe what you need to decide what the variable on the horizontal axis is
Characters in have log Lambda
You could also have lemon womxn don't hold graphic looks excited
And I got an approximation in one space may not be as good as it can I send another
Okay the question is
Looking at these three
Likelihood for single data points on the top of the screen
Does the yellow one which is the probability of producing Mexico's 12
As a function of Lambda
Does it have a pika tool as Lambda goes to infinity and the answer is no always values of Lambda give identical
Prediction so it just asymptotes to
The value 1 - 19
Because the window is 19 wide
And so all of those in the limit
Put that probability density uniformly over 19 at space
19 centimeters wide
Yes it if you change the width of the window from being 19 centimeters wide
To being sad
Centimeters life then it would have a peek again just as for three and five at any point the left hand side of the midpoint
You got a pink
That that's the rough rule of thumb think I'm writing but I said that
Mythical aesthetic
Yes
Could the likelihood function have multiple Peaks
Definitely in general it could for this problem account
Mitsudomoe total for this problem but in general like food functions can go all over the place and we will come up with many examples of
Sebastian future elections
Okay what I want to do now is I want to move on or you can do this for any day just that says another day just
Chat with just three points and 1.7
That still only three data points but it is much more shot PP
So it depends on what the data actually turn out to be how sharp your likelihood will be
It is possible with three points old left hand side they can get quite a good estimate of of Lambda just from three days
An approach that use bins of a fixed size it was fixed before the date arrived
Will probably be hopeless at this sort of thing function
Don't the right thing for you when you can get a very precise answer for Lambda
Even given any three data points it gives you that
So we hate putting date went to Ben's and her off of the likely function because you'll never need to use Ben's ever again
Okay
I want to finish
The next 15 minutes
With another question
The topic for today it's like Shelton
But something for today is inference of parameters and models
And if I gave you something to like this and if I didn't just say they come from
I'm not actually sure if it's from one Lambda warm exponential maybe there's a mixture
Of exponentials
Please tell me what I should think about that
Is it credible given the state so that it comes from two guys Ian's rosin far to exponential
Robin just one
How do we solve that problem
Well
Let's write down
FaceTime again
Habitats your neighbor about how to solve this problem when I want to build
Okay
So what we going to do now is we're going to introduce two hypotheses
One is hypothesis wrong with your testing working on
Hypothesis wrong
Which is named after the number promises it's gone
The number of exponentials
Here it is
And this is how we fit H1 to the data
Phishing involves
Thinking what its Lambda it one parameter Lambda might be
And the prior
I didn't even specify what it was the sort of thing you might do
And this
If it were a real life problem you might think a little bit about
If you know anything about lavender already know if it was shorter then something or other then
The universe will explode if it was a bigger than we will be dad might be
A range of values a pretty shoalanda must be within if you really don't know anything about that
You might be tempted to have some sort of uniform prior
Petrino's values
It actually depends what the problem is what you should do about it think it is subjective and that's the way
I think
It has to be
And
Set the sort of thing that the prior might be is some beautiful mixed distribution over some broad range of
Vlog Lambda
Okay
I'm not saying I have to be that way that's just the way I often work if I have real inference problems
Positive quantity Lambda Decay length
I'll tend to think of the log of that variable is an actual way to work with it and then they put the product on the look of it
Robin directly on Lambert South
What this implies for the prior lender is that it may be a bit of a
Lopsided looking a bit like
This because this prior is saying that
Value such as .1 + 1 + 10 + 100
Parole just as likely as as each other
That means
Tobias if you liked it
Small veins
Okay
Stop I haven't obsessed about his prime but it's going to become slightly more important than the moving
When I went to DCFS a second hypothesis
And the second hypothesis
Says that the probability density of x if you knew Lambda want an alarm to 2
And if you knew quotes to let go and Pie one pie to which of the weights of the two exponential
To be the length scales in these a how much probability Masters in each of them
The public works
Given those promises and H2 is
8 + -6
Online level one
+ 8 - x 2 x weight
Taiwan
Simplicity
We could pretend to the left hand side of the window is it
Zero from now on
But
So that is
A mixture of two
Exponentials
And
Let's retract what I just said this is true parole activity 9B
I'm at 0 otherwise
Okay so H2 has two interesting promises Lambda Lambda to another couple of promises by one pipe
Switch off positive
And
To get on with it I'm going to declare so I'll
Cathedral by life inside
Half of the Masters in what exponential health is in the oven
And
I didn't have to do that it would just make it a bit easier to do what we're about to do so the motor will only have two parameters
Rather than three
End
We can do infants with both of them
So we can infer land of an alarm to 2
Given
Other than beta
Imagine gold controller
X
Given on the 1 alarm to 2
Which is the product of all of these things
I'm not suppressing the pies because I just arbitrarily decided that I wanted
We have a prior on the tool
So that's how we
To put it crudely fix model 2
To the beta
Robert Howey in full on the 111th to give me the date
I need to know that we don't care about because it's just analyzing constant if it were doing is thinking what we
Believeland should be
However if we know what to do model comparison
Then what we want to do is say how probably is I-81 given today
And he'll probably late to get in the beta
An answer to this question can also be found by based on the rules of probability
Starting from our assumptions of day to give an H1 times what have y'all probably fit h-11
/ normalizing customs
Unless one is the probability of the data
Multiply 5 equivalent to
/ the same
And if you like I'm suppressing hair
Some further assumptions it's all depends on
Wish we could cool
That's what I
Other assumptions severe is a Rolex
A key assumption here is the assumption that either there's two exponential's
Well this one exponential
And this assumption about the prize
Premises
So all of these things depend on
Is Romania
I'm not wanting to hide
So the beautiful things to know just ask is if you have Kathleen sold problem one which was please fit model 1
But if you have Kathy so probably too
Infidel and Wonderland tutu and if you have done that in a way that
Is normalizing constant if you didn't just ignore it but you computed it when you are solving
This inference are in fruits
If you got the normalizing constant
That is exactly what you need
In order to do this
Bayesian inference are the dates of dependent time and the other one
If you have ever had
Lost my green
So that's, that's pretty red
Vista life in constant
In Fridley rad
Is this one here
So we have
Parameter inference
How many done because if you did you promise her properly and you don't know why isn't Coulson you've already done model comparison
What you need in order to do mobile comparison
So let me step you through this and I'm going to
Do it in a slightly different way from what I wrote down here what I just described Haywood what just fine function of
Xlong Devon and Lambda 2
I'm about to / Zant right at all
The Wonder Woman lemon
So we put a function of X number 1 number 2
And you can just
Multiply dokodemo
And then normalize
But there's another way of thinking about what's going on here
Which is if you believe it was to exponentials
And you get a lot of data
You can imagine
Deja came out and some of them are colored White
And some of them
Red
And the color can be telling you which exponential that came from
The white was
I'm the one
Red
Islam the two
For example
And then
Someone was true of you and I rub that all the colors and just told you that coordinates
But you could imagine
Trying to infer what those missing colors wear
We could do an inference that involves naming those missing colors
So I'm going to rewrite now mobile 2
I'm going to say that my will has in it
Alarm 2
Next
XM
Cayenne
The van going from walk to end
I'm not the way that we
Get all of the data if we New London to is we first pick a color
And then we draw
The point
From
That
We draw the the next point
From
The distribution condition on McCullough
Sir
We can write this as
Probability with colors
Reminder 1 alarm to 2
Find the probability of x
Given the color
And
We can put a product
Product from 1 to n
Technicolor
Man
Pickaxe
Okay
Then we can do a variety of inferences we can
Still
Work out the probability of Lambda Lambda to if we want
But we can also do other things we could work out how probable is it the correct coloring of all these
Point is
KN from 1 to n given
And assuming that a 2 is true
We can ask questions like that
And what we think
Alarm 2 to give him the daytime
Which is the question we just
Does the range of
Of questions we can ask
And I'm going to
Enumerate
Listen to I talk to space off different hypotheses about Lando on Atlanta to
And
Cayenne
So what I'm going to show you now
Cuz I like the computer
To show us
How well the beta off predictive
As a function of time to warm to the colors
Likelihood function so I'm not increasing the number of parameters in my problem from 2 to 1/2
Whatever NSR event is
8 I'm getting myself a type of 10 parameters
Two real numbers
And then
10 * 8
Categorical variables which are either red or white
And we can look at the likelihood function
As a function of all of those
I'm going to imagine
Fat
Set of possible values of the land along
Eleven22
Which is k1 through Cayenne is living in a stack of pancakes
So
Every one of these pancakes has Atlanta won exatlon the two exits in this discrete pancakes for the number pancakes
2 to the power
And
The Boston pancake is the one that says that kawann
2 km is
One of Thee
Exponential's and his the top of the pancake or just pay one through K and his old zeros and then
Instead of
Wanted to
And in between we have all the other possible labelings of the puns
Temporary hypothesis about what the labeling is and what lender 111 we can count
What the value of
Tee off
Given
Lambda
In fact we can work out the probability of X and quantities together
Right
Let's do that
So here are some data points I'm going to repeat this exercise
The four different data sets
And what I'm going to do is show you
The inference of what we think
Lambda Lambda 2 and Chaos I'm going to show you the stack of pancakes
And I'm also going to run to the inference for the simple model that says that there is only one exponential
Go back to the T-Mobile one military the enforcement other one
What am I going to do I'm going to stop just by you doing the inferences from little warm again
And then we'll move on to doing more than one animal to
So here's our super simple dating site with just 4 points in it
Good function looks like as a function of Lambda
Or as a function of Lambda
So that's what we did in my with the guy
So I'm just showing you again on a slightly different style the things you familiar with
This is what you get if you take the maximum likelihood value of Lambda so you take a point estimate Lambda a new show
Density in data space alongside those four points
All right
So I'm introducing you to the sequence of things I'll show you I'll show you the the data
I show you a likelihood function and then I show you
Best fit
Distribution the fit that maximizes the likelihood
And then just for the sake of argument I'll show you what might have happened if we had chosen some beans to put the plants in
And counted how many where they spend so this to Blue bins in a histogram
I'm rich maybe food for thought
I got his motivator
So
Penny datapoints also
And you can
What kind of like a function
Landers quite well determined
Its characteristic in this sort of problem that typically the width of the peak
Shrinks as the square root
Drink has one of his Square each of the the number of data points youth golf
That's a useful rule of thumb
To have for this one problem
And that is the best fishing
That's the Green Cove that maximizes the likelihood for the model that says there is only one Lambda
But if you have very careful eyes and the skeptical mindset you might look at this clumping
Appoint elections items I need to sure about that
So you might be a skeptic about the warm Lambda hypothesis
That's what
The date it looks like if you shove it into Benz
Where to buy just invented
Data inventions
Not that we had about Benz
But just to remind you
Methods that when not using
Okay let's move on today step number three of slightly reduce the amount of data because I want to to the end
3 manageable
Talk of the dataset hair that I've deliberately chosen to have size eight points so Tuesday is 250
256 hypotheses about how the point we're actually colored in red and white before the colors were there
Raised to make a mold blue
So that's how we're going to fit model one in the same way as before
And we're also going to look at Model T
So here's the likelihood function from other one
Showing it as a function Lambda
And here it is I was going to Laughlin.
And that is the best fit
Green card for best single exponential
You got by maximizing likelihood
No
That's the histogram using a particular bin size
Just a few interesting things now what we're doing is going to Rattle through the pancakes so the 256 of them
Shuffle down to Pancake number 7
The labeling that k12k and is in buying Ray station on cake
And the likelihood function that any particular labeling K is beautifully simple because if you nuke a
Then you would know that the last three days but I told him from lime to two
And the first 5.0 came from the wall
And the likelihood function probability as a function of Lambda one
It's just the simple function that we had the full form of the metal one and the likelihood as much 11 to 2
Is it the same function
We had against a little Wang if you know which points go with which
Pasta is which exponential
So this is a super simple thing it's just a product of two of the two functions that we are already familiar with
When we are dealing with more than one
I love you through the pancake. Blob is a simple separable function just moves around because
Different wavelengths put the put the best gas alarm to 1 alarm to 2 in different places the finals
Back of the pancake
The final layer is one that says that rule from Lambda Wang in fact
Is the way round of Godly
The old ones hypothesis
Says they will be long till I'm the one which means land one is quite well determined don't have a clue about number two
Because
None of the bike that came from the second cluster
Okay so some of the pancake
Suffolk walks
Look I'm like this and many of them look like the globe and they're all in different locations
Blah blah blah blah blah blah
I'm this one iPad will be a just the same rotated 90 degrees
What can we do with all this information that we've accumulated we've run through a total number of hypotheses
Twitching of 256 times the number of points I looked at
Any I take the number of points that was such as you * 32 * 1.2 never take so I've come
Imputed
256000 numbers have switch off every one of those subtype policies
Go to 56000 Suffolk place where every one of those how we did that
Predict the day that she happened
When we know that we can then read anything we're interested in for example
We can read that
How probable alternative you got that essentially by summing all of the time
Pancakes on top of each other
That's what I look like
Sorry to bumps.on what that saying is yes this data which someone with a keen I might have thought
It's almost may have thought that there's evidence for to exponential's in that
The most benefit to the state about giving yourself
2 kilometers
And what that says about looks like with pretty colors is showing
What it looks like is a contour plot
As a function of
Landa Wonderland the two distinct bumps saying yes you can either fix slime
And the ones with small value and longitude value or vice versa
And those are by far more probable than other values of London Wonderland the two for example that that equal to
Which would lie along
Diagonal
We can also ask the question what's the poster distribution of the labels what we think all the khazar
And this 256 hypotheses and this is the sum is essentially the sum of every
Nothing in the pancake
All right
And
He has some that up
You find the different labeling labeling
Labelings which correspond to one
Purple Simon Reds and whites and the other opposite assignment symmetry about the middle because the
The binary representation type of property that if you take one labeling in your voice or the ones and zeros
You switch between integers that sum to 255 so that's why it looks white is that nursing
Symmetry
Okay so we can read out if we're interested in
The maximum likelihood value of philando 111
And that's shown hair
And the purple line showing one of the exponential's
And the gray line is showing the other exponential and the green line is the
Some of those those two exponentials
And
The green light is on top of the grey line NYC
Let me see a little bit of the Gray Line
Okay so that's the maximum likelihood
Hypothesis using two Lambos
Then
We can repeat this for another day to sat and what I wanted to show you before we do that
Is let's
Answer the final question the model comparison question you compare the models
By summing up
I'm getting the normalizing constant and the code I just ran as a rent through these examples
Did that
Unfold is 30%
This is what happened
V Wong
Is this consultation
Have been tense
Formula 1
Is that guy
Is this guy
Providence long came out 5.4 x 6 - 7
What what is predicting
A problem with a probability density overnight dimensional space
Weathers 8 data points will be so it's not surprising have an extremely small number for the evidence because
Predicting in a
Elijah space
A real valued
Atrial bankruptcies
Evidence number 2
I want to talk about comes to 1.4 * 20 - 5
And what that means is the evidence ratio which is what you need if you want to know the probability ratio but
These two
Number to evidence ratio is 26 to 1
20 blackout that evidence ratio I did need to make an assumption about what the prior online the walls and I've gone the Forgotten
What primer on laminate I actually chose
But it was uniform overload Lambda in some range I forgot from from Walter boxer
Four orders of magnitude or something like that
These answers do depend on that prior but nothing is super sensitive way
Obviously I have to depend on your assumptions but you shouldn't worry about that particular assumption be a terrible
ISO game-breaker
If it is a game-breaker you can find out you can explore the sensitivity of the answers to these questions
To those assumptions if you're worried about whether you thought happen enough about your assumptions
This particular
Prince takes too long in favor of mobile to so if they had equal prior probabilities
You got a stator and you end up saying it's 96% to 4% also in favor of
Little Texas
No
The final thing to emphasize is that it didn't have to come out that way
There are many ways on fishing models for example if someone doesn't maximum likelihood fish
How do you say I know how do I tell which model best will let's pick them up with the biggest blanket
If you do that
Belinda always choosing mobile to because trivially mobile 2 with an extra parameters can achieve a better
A bigger likelihood
But that isn't a Bayesian model comparison the books
It involves doing this summation nude with your compassion based on the normalizing constant so we don't look at what was
We looked at what state
Aggregate of how well you predicted the data coming over all the possible values for your hypotheses
That is not necessarily the case that mold to will always win
Indeed
They're all dataset switch model one wins and that's the final thing I'll now show you
So
The spinal dataset
Sharon hair
Is it ice that that really did come from a single exponential
I drew eight points from an exponential
If we go with the likelihood function fit model 1 unlock Style
Vince
And then we do model 2 and we run through all the pancakes
It looks just the same as before to a casual Observer
Have these bumps wobbling around as we
Run through the 256 assignments
And now
When we say What's the
Majin likelihood of laminate 1 alarm to 2
You find it's actually
It looks fairly
Uni Moodle it's not exactly in the middle
If you make a contour plot and if you go into the zoom into the peak of this and look super super super carefully
Beyonce's on the screen now
We could do that
You actually find
That you can get a slightly bigger likelihood
Bye
Having learned one very very similar to each other
All right so that's the likelihood of number 1 and number 2
And this is the posterior distribution of the labels just as last time some labelings are more probable than others
And we can work out the evidence ratio
And the answer for the evidence ratio is shown
It's .27
The other way so now the more probable model in this case hair is Mortal woman comes out
78% to 22% if they equally probable
In the beginning
So that is how mullican person works and what I take away from this is
Given that
Standard ways of fishing even model with just one parameter can run. Plagens problems unless you use Bayes theorem
I find it quite a compelling
Argument for saying yes let's use Bayes theorem
Running around that was an introduction to inference of promises and multiple
What we going to do next
Time
Is
We will move on to the topic of clustering
I'll discuss
Some quite popular algorithms for doing clustering which can be used for things like
Maybe I kind of recognition and speech recognition problems has an example from speech
You could take a single word utterance and take its spectrogram and the Olio
Objects on the left
Of the top
Are people saying the wood Witch is it one of those long and one of them 0
Israel
I guess the right angles of the zeros and then you train up on all of those training examples
Someone gives you some more words to recognize which they are and you could imagine that
Yeah so the ones on the left in the zeros on the right
So we'll talk about clustering and I'll describe a popular method to doing clustering then we'll give it a Bayesian interpretation and
Discuss how to make it a better using
Top Beijing
Interpretation
So that's the first thing we'll do next time
Are there any questions
Okay thanks very much
Okay the question is have Bayesian methods not being used frequently because I computer intensive
I think that's not really then it suddenly makes it easier
To use Bayesian methods if you brought the computer
But I think it's a strange accident of History really because
It's perfectly possible
Take a problem like this when we did hair
I with a single exponential it's respectful to work out a lot to the function and sketch it's by where I do
A method that we didn't need a computer to do it
And
So I think it is more an accident of some personalities and political fights between academic
That these other schools doing things otherwise I grew up
And
But it does this urge to have a circle the projective method labeled subjective
Can people deluded themselves into thinking booties other methods
Would actually a subjective as well
So
Having computers definitely makes its rightful to use off of Bayesian methods and what we're going to discuss
A whole bunch of ways of
Doing practical Bayesian methods on computers
But way back before computers Raven.
The earliest work on inference
With that being done by LaPlace
LaPlace
The correct name for Bayes theorem instantly it is with my sister because I used it in anger on real data
Update on the obit
And the way things to be inferred and he used
They start to do those inferences
He knew that it was the right way to do things and
That was the birth of of Bayesian inference
So it's not for like a computers
There are other exclamation exclamation that's probably social
Exclamation
Okay thanks see you next week