Welcome again
Today I'll recap what we've done in bass compression
And then we'll
Get back to
The central topic if you like if the information Theory course which is noisy Channel
Coding the tree looked at him
Let me start with a little
Question I set for you last time
The question is about this Ensemble ABCD with 458
And with the symbol code
Showing that
And the question is
If we are and Cody from this source and then we reach into the encoded string to put out one bit what's the problem
But it's a one please talk to your neighbor
How about your answer
To this question
Okay
What type of votes there are three options that you worked out P1 I hope you've talked to you in a
And
I'm going to ask you
Is your pee one lesson haha
Whole pig on a half
And you can also vote for the dead which is I don't know
Places that I don't know
Hey votes for a few on his less than 1/2
Okay
A few guys that
Votes of BP 1 is equal to
One vote for me but it's the cp1 is big enough
Everyone else except
The people who've
Okay we don't want that
No one voted for that so everyone else must be asleep already
Okay what we've got a range of advances that people from community
T a p 1 less than 1/2
Could a volunteer take us through the GOP one
What was your method for
Stop touching people
Since we're the majority
Okay who voted Ray
Alright what was what was Obi-Wan
What was the value
Anyone
Unknown
Well can I help at
Let's talk about
The fraction
Of
The code word that is made
Bald
Wong's and see what happens if we look at that
Coded a
The code for a which happens all the time
Has golf
Who won the next Kobe's Hawthorne security is 2/3 ones
Andy is 100%
Wangsa defined as the fraction of the code which is ones
So a lot of people are voting for a but you're being very shy about saying why
And I'm going to give a possible arguments that might give an answer this in the icon
Stop
With Pekka CO2 at first but then we pick a random bit to see if it's
I want or zero in these are the probabilities that being the one or zero
So here's a calculation probability of getting a warm
I'll put a? I like this
I want to check if I've got your reasoning right probability of getting a sum of
Letters in the alphabet
Probability of picking up letter
X the probability of it
Turning out to be a woman when you pick a random bit from the code word
Yeah
Is that the sort of reasoning that the I can meet you until your life to know that stalking is stiff
Have a good 1/2 * 0
Plus 1/4 times
Plus
1/8 * 2/3
8 * 1
Alright which gives us
Banh mi
Plus
All right
Tonight I'm 2/3
Which is
1/8 times 2 2/3
2 + 2/3 is
8 / 3
Which is giving us too long first
Okay
Does anyone who voted for a think that this is roughly why they voted for a thumbs up
But not everyone agreed we've got some bees and seeds does anyone want to
Challenge this since I know it's wrong has an argument why that's wrong
Anyone
The a side
Yeah
Okay. My son just said if you reach into the stream and some of the code was a
Long or short
When you reach in and pick a random bit you're more likely to hit one of the long code works
Alright so this isn't the correct way to pick a random bit from the stream we need to take into account the
Lengths
So that's a good argument okay so this is probably wrong
At least it's the wrong message it may not be the wrong answer
Set length
Length of
Code words
Any other argument
I know that answer
Okay let me give you one of the arguments of this and then we'll do the calculation again
What's the information content of this probability
Hair
I'm sorry one bit free bits and freeways
What's the ideal encoded lengths for probabilities
We are dealing Cody links the Shannon information content switch
From now on I will just call them the information contacts
What are the links of these lengths is one two three
The links masked information contents
So this is a case where
We have a symbol code
With perfectly matched
Curtain lengths
The probabilities
That means you can't compress any better than this
Because we have our souls cutting their lips as you can compress time to expect if the lights of your car
Information content
Hi this is a valid code is a prefix code
This this will work
No
If we use this code and code stuff from the source
And if it were the case that the bits coming out after encoding
We're not 50/50 zeros in 1 completely random independent unlicensed which are
If if I would not 50/50
Then
We could compress it some more
Because Simon says if the probabilities are 50/50
We can make coach and I would
Stopping bags for the lottery tickets and we could do for the compression
But you can't compress anymore cuz we've already got it down.
Vessel without doing any calculation of total it must be the case
51 is 1/2
Savvy is the right answer
Because it's perfectly compressed and uncompressed it will look random
Okay so the right answer
Is B so what went wrong with this calculation
Well that's a free do it and
Do the calculation in a way that takes into length
Let's think about it this way we really great big bucket we're going to
Put
Bits into the bucket
Each time you pick a code with some more
It's got in the bucket and some of those are ones we're interested in the ratio in this bucket what fractional
Wong's
Let's give ourselves an extra column in hair which is not the fraction that's all ones but have phone number
For the number
Of warm denisco dresses 02
10 - 1 is 3
So on average when I
Pick another code word
How many new bits go into the code but will put that downstairs
Mansur is samurai
PTI
Ally
And on average how many ones go into the bucket
Last summer i t i
Ann.
Okay
How does that differ from what we did over here
Well f i is the ratio of and I
Nova
Ally so you can see
Will using a different thing upstairs and to compensate for that while using something
Different dances
Okay so this is the average number of ones that go in the bucket whenever you pick a new code with this is the average number of
The gummy the ratio of those is going to be the fraction
Offbits that I want spliff we do that
We have
The
Upstairs thing is
Hahaha * 0
Across X
Wong
+ 1/8
X 2 X 3 I'm downstairs it's our old friend.
Banks
Which is the entry fee
Of this probability distribution
Which is
7 / 4
I'm doing this memory
And what's upstairs
That's a quarter
Free
So in Eighth Street.
2 + 2 + 3 which is 7 / 8
I wish I might
Wichita
So that's a long way to get the answer for the sneaky information Theory based on certain is just to say especially
Breast
Case Closed its 50/50
It's not any 50/50 it's got no correlations and is it electric can be no correlations
Indian Kodi
Stream it's otherwise we could use the information Theory arguments and say all those correlations could be
Splash hit those dependencies
Any questions
So we love information. Provide you with very powerful they brief arguments the things that means
You don't need to do calculations anymore
Last time let me just recap what we did we introduced symbol codes
Or rather the time before last. She symbol codes
And
Symbol codes are widely used we have a Huffman algorithm that gives you upload symbol codes and that expected length Within
1 bit per character
Off the entropy
But we argued in the previous lecture
We could go that
Doesn't actually wrap up compression we don't like symbol code because being within one bit of a character is not very good
Enter people character is something small like 0.1 bits and we argued that often that will be the
Kasich say with compressing English
We play the game that gave us the idea that you could use identical twins at the sender and the receiver in order to make a
Compressor
And then we looked at at MIT coding
Decoding is this way of thinking about her binary file as defining a single
Real number between 0 and Wong to an extremely large precision
And any
Source file can be represented in the same way as in
Responding to an interval on the real line between 0 and 1
And
I argued that when you do ask me coding
You will get compression down to within two bits all the information content of the entire file so this is
In terms of its overhead this + 2
Is potentially about a plant from M smaller than the overhead you got
If you use symbol code so coating is in almost all cases
Far far better than symbol codes
And
I just wanted to flush out how you'd use out of plastic coating in practice I told by the idea of an oracle
Hold that being a piece of software which uses some procedures to predict the next Carta given all the time
Does x 1/2 x 2 - 1 that have been seen
I don't want to just
Give you an example of how this works in Rio state-of-the-art compressors
So here is a fragment of Jane Austen's Emma
This is the last fifty or so characters and the context is along.
Pro and the question is what comes next so how do real compression algorithms work well
Feleena state-of-the-art compressor that's very widely used is a compressor Co PPM and
His her PPI mean what
Atsko prediction by partial match
And it's slightly I talked but this a bunch of theoretical justifications and improvements we can make sure
Let me describe the I talk my head
We look at the context
That's the last five characters of the document
Define the context for the next character
Then we look at the entire file of everything that we've seen so far and we say
Have we seen that contacts before in the entire file
So this is how we're going to then predict what happens next to go and find
All of those occurrences in here they all showed in blue
Sorry space pro has happened 1 2 3 4
Five times already in Jane Austen's Emma
And this shows what happened next Was A V A V and o a p and the nest
So
A first stop would be to say let's use these six grams to tistics the rules 6 crime statistics
260-211-2345
56 chance of getting a v next
There's a 1/5 chance of
I want V transfer p and 1/5 chance
You better allow some other things happening
How to allow for other things happening well the PPM approaches to say let's back off to
Shoulder-length contacts as well and say what happened in contacts space Pro
Roo and in any context tutorial
Unfolding those other
1 2 3 4 5 possibilities in addition to the six crime statistics
And wait them together in a small fish weigh
And that's a PPM works
And it gives you extremely good compression state-of-the-art
On most files it doesn't do as well as humans do human audiences like yourself can predict English
A lot better until it doesn't understand grammar and diction recent insightful but it does a lot of learning
Avril statistics and that's
I got you a long way towards
Good compression
So that's PPM
Okay so the question was does it learn the 6 crime statistics of the document of the entire document
Compressor what does it do it on the Fly and the important answer is it's just like you guys it
Identical twin audiences
It does things on the fly so when were asked to predict in this contact Revenge site how often has
Has East Bass Pro happened already before now we don't look ahead into the future
So the predictions are based only on what we have already seen
Okay
Any other questions
Does a couple more things I want to mention about coding one is as I showed you last time we can
Make other uses of arithmetic coding we can make an extremely efficient ranking system
The one I showed you was kielbasa that's based on the idea that
Writing involves making gestures of some sort maybe wiggling fingers or scribbling with a stick
And you want to turn those gestures into text as efficiently as possible
And compression is all about taking text and turning it into a bit string which in North Dakota is used
Does a real member
And so we can make a very good writing system by saying okay let's have the gesture just defining a real number by staring
Spaceship
In a two-dimensional world and that will make us if we turned on its head a very efficient writing system so you make
So that's the best concept
And I showed you that and it's free software and help is always welcome to make
Basa Basa
Another application for arithmetic coding I wanted to mention
And this is the idea of efficiently generating
Random samples
Let me give you an example let's say I asked you to simulate
A bent
Coin and I said okay
Let's fix PA
0.01
Honey PB is the rest
Please simulate
10 million tosses of this bent coin
And I will provide you with random bits a random number generator the question is how many bits would you need to use
To generate
10 million
Tuffy's of this coin
Let's say an from now on instead of 10 million
A standard way of solving a problem is to say oh well I'll use the random bits you can provide me with
How to make
Real numbers between 0 and Wang so I'll generate things that I'll think
Real numbers
Uniformly distributed between 0 and 1
That will double up 32 bit
Real number
If it's a standard
Random number generator so we're eating first few bits and separate them is defining a number between 0 and 1
Then we look to see if you is less than PA
And if it is then we split a tonight and otherwise
This method will cost you 32 bits
The character
All right
Can we do better on Dewey cat
The answer is yes
And maybe
So yes we can do much better because we could take a nice medic coda
And think about it this way let's wipe the board
Imagine sticking a pin
Into the world of an arithmetic Kota
What happens if you stick a pin
Uniformly at random into this line that goes from 0 to 2 1
Or into
Into one of those lines what comes out
Of what comes out if you sticking a pin and use it to select
A string of text
Habitat Geneva
Okay well I'm drawn on the bull terriers a couple of different coating wheels that run from zero
Tawam
This is one for some Source within alphabet with cartridges ABCD with a few probabilities
And what we noticed last time was
They are somatic coding method gives you
Intervals between 0 and 1 whose size is the probability of the string equaling that
Particular strength probability of X is
Is the size of this
Clintonville hair
Herobrine the one for the coin this is
99%
This is 1%
And then we
Reticent subdivide this
In the same way and we got this is a little bit baby in half
And
And his Buffet a b
All right if we come along and sticking up in the probability that it will land inside this interval here
Is this
So the probability that if you've been read out the storm we've got the probability it will begin a c is the
Random
Is a way of taking a string from the probability distribution of your language model
Okay
So what we can do with the coins is make the arithmetic Dakota
Encoder and decoder
For the mankind
Then bring along random bits
Random Nelson Wong
Supposed to Define where pain goes in
The pin is sticking up in between 0 and you do that by having an Infinite Source
All zeros and ones to Define
Where we are on the line
And
So you stop doubling up those zeros and ones find out where the pain is
To the first
Bit stupid lyrics
Install reading out bits video decoder
Raquel Dakota
How many bits is that going to need well on average
It's just like compression
What happened to Binary entropy of newpointe warm is
.1
That's on average how many bits you will need certain contrast to needing 32 bits
Coin toss
The arithmetic coding method
For generating random samples
For the band coin
Is going to need
Spider-Man 4 .01 bits
Calling
Which is smaller than one quite a lot smaller than once
It's going to be
More than a factor 32 times more efficient with your random bits
And if random bits are valuable thing
You may want to do this so it may strike his elegant but it may actually save you money and I want to close
Close this
Discussion
Giving you a little bit of evidence
That we do actually care about saving running bits riding bits on all free if you want run a bit you have to get me
From somewhere
And if
What you doing has any so principal purpose you need to verify that good random base
And so here's a CD that I received in the post
A few years ago
And the CD came with a message saying that this CD contains random bits and they being generated
Thanks for the financial support of a couple of
US government grants and then distributed
Underground from Florida State University to academics around the world who want random bits
So Random bits of valuable and this is proof that
Serious for such as and Thunders Feud random bits as being important enough to spend US government money on
Not wanting to waste
Random bits
Any questions
Okay we have not available
Russian make
Numbers I lost
Yes so the question is are there other ways of thinking why this is a bad idea to do with the purse
Decision of the numbers you need to make this decision about is it an A or a B
Often you only need the first b**** to already tell you're okay
We don't need to look at the next 31 that's the first bit was already made the decision about wasting b**** that
Conversely
Actually if you look in detail that other probability that this will spit out
I want it's not going to be exactly 1% is it it'll be some ratio roll and
I'm over
232 Miami some integer
It's actually going to
Perfectly nice
Pay directly with any one person to give you the right
Exactly the right answer
So yes it is wasteful because it's using loads of it to make a decision about his
Single bit
A&R Medical
Another questions
Okay so go to move on to the topic of noisy channels and noisy channels have inputs and output
Put some one of the things we want to do with noisy channels his info what the input mahjabeen
Given the output of the channel
So
A theme of noisy channels is going to be we need to understand inference
I want the clear on how to do inference
Will also be talking about how to measure information content
In the context of noisy channels
So we know how to measure information content for a single random variable like posting a been drawing around them
English it's all about
La Guadalupe and that's it
Let me know your channel it's all a little bit more interesting because we input speaker outputs were interested in questions like
How much information does seeing this output convey about the input
I want to learn how to do that
Instead of with I just want to give you a little puzzle to think about
And it doesn't involve it just involves three cops
And here are the three times and I'll introduce you to them one at a time
His account which is
White
And white on the front
And the rest
Hezekiah Brown
On the front and reverse
And there's a cop it's brown on one side and blank on the other
So I know what I'm going to do is I'll shuffle them and send them over randomly
Unhide them
I draw one card at random
Unplugged it down in front of me so I can see it
And then I'm going to ask you about the other side of a cop Alright by shuffling randomize
I don't think any magic tricks I think has just everything you say is
What's happening
So we shut them up and then
I randomly grab a cart on Plunkett down
All right
And I show you
They
Front
One side of the car
It's what the question is
What's on the other side
The question is
Given that you and I are seeing a white face
What the probability of a face card
Is what
Please turn to neighbor and have a chance
Well I question
Okay
Boats for Zedge which means I don't know
Can't got a few dinos
Votes for the probability is less than 1/2
Netflix
It's bigger than 1/2
I fear
7 ish
I'd like to say it's off it's 50/50
1 2 3 4 5 6 crying like except we have some clear uncertainty
I like it when I haven't
So let's have an argument from the second Community why is it 50
P50
Anyone
Yeah
Good so I just said was by Logic it's either this card or that car
And that on the desk
And we don't have any additional information so must be 50/50
Like a lot of people who disagree with you so I would one of them like to give an argument wife that
Compelling argument of logic
Wrong
Yes
Okay so what I just said was the three possible ways of getting a white thing facing up here either looking at that side or that side
Midol that side in all three of those possibilities are equally likely
So either this hypothesis or that one or that one
Find
One we will find out
Whether the other side is this all the other side is this or is that
So that means it's 2/3
2/3 Champs
It's what
That argument
Stertorous
Good
Does anyone want to add anything change your mind
Give another argument
Lecrae
Okay that's a nice argument so the argument said think about the other side of the card
Which is either going to end up being white or brown
I'm right at the beginning before I bought the car I could have asked you please play some bad
Is the concert going to be white O'Brien and we definitely 50/50
Okay
And now the question is
We see the front
Will not make a change I batter tool
Surely it must make a difference
And that's a very credible argument that there is a dependence between the front and the back
So surely you shouldn't be betting 50/50 anymore doesn't but it does
Not 50/50 because we just let something
We know something that we didn't know and there is a dependence
And that's a good argument to
All right
So let me give you a suggestion always write down the probability
All everything
I miss is copyright Steve go
Here is a professor over in me
Building next door
Write down the probability of everything
All the variables in the problem then you can condition on what has happened and you will be able to deduce by the symbol
The answer to your question is
So in this case
Everything is
The front face
Underverse face
And before I did the shuffling through the car.
The probability of the front face being
White or black and their birthdays being white or black
The probability of this pair of variables
Being white and white with long fast
The probability of it being
Brown & Brown
The probability of P
Other two things are fed cuz she had that by
Call the black white cop coming along
50/50
Which one yoga
That is the joint probability of everything
An owl with a strong probability we can
Condition
On data and anything else you want to throw in
And data is what we're given and what was given is there in this world
So today the white face came up
Sorry condition on front being white
And we can then work out the probability that the
Is
White example by Renown 5 English probability distribution
This may not convince people who still really think it's 50 50 50 50 how can you say it
That's rubbish until I've got one final argument
That I hope will help
And then once the document has been accepted
Maybe it will compel you to agree that it's a good idea to write down the probability of everything
So here's the final argument and it's not that they reverse was indeed white happened to be true but it didn't have to be
Imagine we play this game lots of times and instead of asking
What's the probability the other face is why I always ask you to question what's the probability that the other faces
The same as the one you'll see now
Okay so
This long of us think this was another thing is when they not the same so two-thirds of the time
The face will be the same on the back cuz it is on the front
So when you say white and when you say Brian does it
Okay
So that's
Not based on probability Theory and I think it's a fairly compelling argument
Hopefully that's convinced you
That we should use probability Theory because if you cannot sleep reliably solve this exercising
Involving just
One random variable which is which card and another on the Bible which is which way up Event Source of to run
A problem of graduates from Cambridge
Can reliably solve this problem
That really shows you
Yeah entrance is a little bit tricky
Inference isn't turkey straightforward humans are often very good at inference but if you want to be sure you're getting it right
Beautiful very very beautiful real history will always get you the right answer
Okay
Alright so let's not talk some more about Noida channels
And let me just remind myself what comes up through this
Weber heading is a bit more about inference
And we're all thinking took that information measures phonology Channel
A classic noisy channel is the binary symmetric Channel up that top right
Which is obscured by
Water cycle
Okay the binders metric Channel with input 0 and 1 and it flips a fraction as of the bits
We want to understand coding theory for any noisy Channel
And whenever dealing with noisy tenants we need to know how to do in France that I used to introduce people to inference for the different puzzle
Frecons I would show people the three doors
Problem
Where the game show host says
His the rules of the game I got to hide a very desirable price here a National Rail Pass
Behind one of these three doors
The guys I was always explains the rules first before the game happens when the rules are I will hide the prize behind one of these doors
Then I will ask you the player to choose the door or you have a free choice and you choose it by naming it and we don't open
Then I began to host guarantee that I will open another of the doors not the one you chose
And I guarantee when I do that promise me promise you trust me
That the prize will not be revealed in that stage
So then the price will either behind dual 102 in this example
The other door that he didn't open and then the play I got the chance to stay
Take off switch if you want
And then you'll get what kind the final door you end up at
Either sticking or switching
And the options
For this puzzle van
What like that that was the rules being played tonight and now you go ahead and play the game
The player treated Obama The Host
Says in the rules I will not open these little two little three and will not reveal
The ugly little snowflake
It doesn't have a price
And the question is
Should you stick
Should you switch
How does it make no difference
I used to use this as my
Introductory example of a theory because people would argue very hotly about inside where it's either behind or one
Don't want it's 50/50
It is indeed oldest make any difference is 50/50
Another
Used to be contentious but unfortunately most people have heard of this puzzle
And so it doesn't really work anymore
Mitsubishi switch
They say it makes no difference so you say it's a useless educational device
Is being ruined because I was going to talk about it
And the really annoying thing is they talk about it in a way such that no one has actually nothing
And you are my proof of that because I'm going with ago you voted for a lot of you
Controversy hair between B and C
Cruise
Add educational disaster has happened to 3 Doors puzzle which is a fantastic puzzle it's really education
Being ruined because I know the answer but I don't understand it
ABC has these are exactly equivalent to each other the three Cubs and the three doors they all the same
Same problem as each other
And
Yet I showed you the same problem and you didn't get a ride even though you'd allegedly the answer
Learning isn't about memorizing things is my understanding
That's my little rant on the three doors
Stop
The message people should be getting from the three doors problem is don't memorize the answer to a stupid puzzle because then you'll be
Useless is holding featuring French problems instead learn the message that you should use probability Theory and then you will be
Equipsa solve any puzzle of the time in the future
Rent-A-Wreck
So what do we do now let's talk about
Noisy channels
What we're going to do with noisy channels is there always going to have an input and output
And a channel
Define recessive conditional distributions if you condition on an input
The channel to find the probability of the output is going to be the channel doesn't Define a joint distribution
Adjust Define unconditional
Distribution
And we can only have to do inference that the probability of everything so we need to Joint distribution
I'm going to run through
A very simple example wet
Assume I brought a joint distribution
Write down the joint distribution
And I'll Define some information measures
Pull that joint distribution
Then we move onto channels will have to guess a joint distribution by
Adding to the conditional distributions defined by the title
Add Distribution on the inputs to join up
I'll start with a joint distribution or a joint
Ensemble
Ant is an example of one
And I'll Define all the different information measures we can
Hot
Make for the joint Ensemble I'm going to tell you the joint probability of two random variables X and Y which are
Pendant
Random variables a bit like the front in the back of the three cups
So the first variable X can take on values 1 2 3 or 4
Why can't I combine use one two three or four
On the joint probabilities are
181 6152
168 132
All lacrosse
Hyundai Azera
And there
From a joint distribution you can always Define marginals
Imaginal prophecies
All written in the margins
And they are trained by adding up until we have a quota quota
As it happens
For the probability of Y
And then in the boxing match and we have a
1/4 1/8
No
We already defined for a single random variable
How to measure entropy
And so when we go to join, so there's a bunch of straightforward things we can do with that entropy
Definition
We can write down what the
Marshall entropy of excess and we can write down what the marginal
Entropy of Y is for example
Some defining for youth by example
What muscle atrophy means
Muscle and relax is the entropy of this distribution here is 7 / 4
The most expensive why is the entropy of this distribution
And that's two bits
And we can find the entropy of the path XY so you could think of
The Pact why is being a single random variable that takes on these
16 possible values with the 16 probability swishing hair
How do you say what the entropy
Of this
Distribution
So we just do a normal some overall path X Y XY
Log base 2
I'll never see if X and Y
And that comes out to 27/8
Bits for this
Joint distribution
And
Those numbers I've just written down these three numbers have the property that if you show them
Graphically
Android select start way
An age of X and Y best way
I know you trying to make Hy
No jump against this Ryan side hair
Define they don't quite match up so late to vaccinate added together
Then h of X and Y
For this example
And this is actually always true that these guys will always have a laugh or they might just up
Up against each other and exactly add up to
The Joint entropy
They only have to do that if X and Y are independent
Random variables
So the size of this overlap hair
Is a measure of how much dependents there is between
The random variables
Let me Define a few more things we can do with a joint distribution we can Define conditional probability
For example payoff x given Y is
Define to be the joint probability of x + y / y
And
We can write it out
Parole 16
Values of X and Y
So here is Thanksgiving why
4y going from one to three
And ask I want to be free
. what condition on why being one then we can read that that top row probability
And normalize it
We got a 1/2 1/4 1/8 1/8
The next rogo's 1/4 or 1/8 1/8 when we normalize it
Let me know like I said right that really cool so we get the quota quota quota
Why we don't like the bottom row we got one
So there's full probability vectors all the full possible conditional distributions
And for every one of those probability distributions we can write down its entropy so we can write down the entropy off
Given that Y is equal to 1
We can write a review of x given that y equals 2 and so forth
Identify this guy here
This distribution it's Valley Familia at 7 or before this one before as well
This one
Entry of the uniform distribution is two bits
The entropy of one and three zeros
Is there a bit cuz it's a certain distribution we know
Conditional why being attacked is definitely one
So what do we think about that well we noticed that
It possible
For the conditional entropy of
X
Given a particular value of y
To be
The same as what we started with 7/4
All the same
Omega
Osmolar
So you when you get data
About why
It's possible for your uncertainty by X3 the go up stay the same or get less
So that's an interesting observation
On Sunday we can do it all of these is rickettsiae tall and average when we learn why
How much information content will ask then have
So what's the average entropy of x
Kevin Weiss I'm not defining for you I think old the conditional entropy
All of these were conditional antifreeze as well
Dua for particular condition in particular values of Y and then this is the really important on the conditional entropy
Which is the average averaging over all possible values of Y waiting together
Kayavax given that value of y no just I'm Catholic consistently using little lie to me
Thinking about you and Capitol why is the name of
The random variable itself
Okay I'm not adds up to 11/8
Bets
Similarly we can work out what the entropy of Y given X is
Similarly
Go to calculation I need at 13/8
Specs
No
In this case I pointed out that the entropy of Acts when you learn while I could stay the same could go up
Could go down
When we went. The conditional entropy Wego 11/8 bits
And that is smaller than 7/4
And let me know tell you I serum
Which is that it is always the case
That the conditional entropy with capital letters is less than or equal to 2 module entropy
And finally it can all be glued together like this in a single diagram
So this is nothing. Yes but it's true
But h of Y given X
8tracks
Kevin why
Unless we have Robin icewood stories that we can tell which is the total information that you got when you learn X and Y
Is the some of the information you get when you learn why plus the amount of information you then at when having already
Why can't you then go on to the next
Or information about the backs of why on average is intuition
Explaining why
Okay but some of these two
I'm disabled iPad dependence between these variables
Relationship I just said about this publicity clean that some people call it the chain rule
For entropy
The final thing I want to do is Define this creature half
This measure of dependence between X and Y is going to be a lot of fun
When we play with channels
The most important thing we want to know and it's called the mutual information
Between
The random variables X and Y
Waco of X semicolon
Why
And
It's what it shows in the picture so you can pick any way of
Obtaining this from the picture examples the difference between a touch of Acts and a Chevette
NY
Or it's the difference between
Hrvy
And make the volume max
That's 3 transformation
What we're going to do in the next election
Is glue this together with a channel
A channel
Is a set of conditional distributions
Sorry for the binary symmetric Channel
It doesn't specify how often you should use the zero and the one it just says if you send a zero
If you send a 1
For the child to find conditional distributions
And then we can turn those conditional distributions if we want to enjoy joint Distribution on input and output
By inventing a probability distribution for the input
Then you can compute all of these information measures for the joint distribution you've to find
Remind me about the theory of how to communicate reliably
Urbanology Channel
Are there any questions
Okay thanks very much for coming and see you next week