Thank you all for coming
Let me recap what we did last time
We've started talking about sore skirting Alternatives data compression
We've been looking at toy examples
One example of a redundant file for us to say something is mainly zeros with just a few ones
Scattered at random are we cool at the bent coin
How should we can compress a file like that
Well when we think about compression to claims with examining Shannon's assertions that
If you take log
Bass tooth
Of 1 over the probability of an outcome that tells you
, information content that outcome has Galt how long the message or to be associate
Chicken piccata outcome in bits as well as the ideal message length
The entropy which is the average of the Shannon information content is claimed to be the right way to measure average information
Content
And
The third is session that we've got time that we have sort of proof last time is the source coating Theron which says that
If you got a very long string around comes from a random Source identically distributed
Then those outcomes can be compressed into roughly end times the entropy bits
So we sort of proof that last time we did this proof by counting the
Typical said we didn't have to do a general proof that's in the book
But what we did was we looked at a special case of the bent coin
Where are you I'll sit and times and get mainly zeros in a few ones
And that we all know what the typical sat is you expect to get roughly if it was
I've been calling me to buy September 7th at 10% and the typical set of strings is old
Things that have roughly 10% 107 general what the typical set means
Define concept
Is
If you got the string of an independent outcomes from a source that string
Is very likely to be in a typical set
Typical set elements all have roughly the same probability as each other
And
There are two to the end times and repeat
All of them
So the rough proof of the source coding thermostat to each of these guys the number
Names of your meat has two Phantoms the entropy so the length of all the names Weeknd X the entropy
The old got roughly the same probability of each other which must that will be to the minus and times
The
Very rough outline of the proof of the souls cutting tempura General Tso
And we did it for the bent coin looking at a long string of and
Outcomes and the way we found ourselves at the proof was reimagined playing the band Korn lost
We wanted to win the lottery for the mafia boss how much of his money did we need to spend which tickets
It would be by we found a big sack full of tickets and then we imagined writing a new name
Increase ticket on the robust of a ticket we counted the number of tickets in the bag and had to to the end times the entropy
So that's what we did last time I was out proof of the source coding theorem at least for the band coin
When I said the number of tickets in the bag is 2 to the end times end
2 to the Anton phanpy plus a little bit
And that little bit is to the fluctuations around the the mean of the typical number
Of Wands those fluctuations goes √ and where and is the length of the
The strength they get relatively small compared to the main term and H2
And his just a picture reminding you want to go see him distribution looks like and you can get the probability
State Farm down
As small as you like the probability of failure as small as you like just by adding a few extra √ Anton's
A few extra standard deviations
To your typical fast
All right so that was a ridiculous way to do compression with an older very large bean bag full of tickets
What you wrote things on the two signs off that was out compression on done compression algorithm
We're going to discuss
Practical
Data compression how would we compress a bent coin
Practically well that's actually a home of exercise I sent for you so I'd like you to work on that
But we'll carry on working on other approaches to related problems I'm going to talk today about
A method of being data compression code symbol codes
I'm out here with symbol code is it something you could apply for example to English
Or to any language that involves an alphabet of characters West some characters
Probable than others
And to make life especially simple to start with I'm going to pretend that the probability distribution for every character
The same every time I'm that we know that distribution
And will usually assume that it's non-uniform distribution could look like his
Alphabet of 26 + 27 + oil and a probability distribution
Overdose nicotine space is the most probable time to ETA oan
RSI HDL will that sort of stuff this is like an English language distribution
And the task now is
To give
A code word to each of these
Symbols in the alphabet which which of these
Elements of the alphabet example of binary
And we've given a yacoba at four zeros and we can set the code of 11012
Walnuts basically 01
The last example of a code and the way you use a symbol code is you take the source file
Replace it by the corresponding codewords in order concatenated
With no punctuation at all so the receiver won't be able to see where the boundaries between the code webs
Sir
A symbol code is going to be a map
From each symbol
Acts in your alphabet
To will collect see all apps and see if x is a binary string
That's consejeria can be of any length and set notation
01 IS300 Wong set with a plus mean
The strings of any length made up of zeros and ones
Not may be familiar to those of you who hang out with computer scientists
Let me give you another example 01
^ 2 is the same as the set of strings
I'm going to walk like I said that's just a little bit of station
Assemble code is
A map from symbols to find restrings and then
The way sample code works is we encode
String of outcomes X1 X2 X3
Send biking caffeinating without punctuation
Tacoma glass racks wall
Makoto
Sorry
I'll just give you the example
If we gave
A recorder
See the code
I'm c1011 then
The file containing c a b b with zinc coated as long as ra1100
Sarah
Okay
That's a very simple idea but not many tickets are head round assemble Coast understand them theoretically
And understanding practically and these are quite important that quite widely used especially in
History
So the questions you want to ask today all the theoretical question
How well might a symbol code before
I'm over on fizzle biting here is maybe the answer will have something to do with
With the entropy and Shannon information content
And I would again reinforce the claims we being
Assessing
Question is hey stuff. I just want to know how to make a good one how do you make
Good symbol codes
Let me say good or optimal
We need to Define what we mean by
So let's do that
Suck
What do you mean by optional well after compression a short expected
Like stomach so we'll use that was our main objective function so that maybe others
Define the expected length
All
Barcode
See
For an ensemble
Axe The Ensemble being the alphabet with all its probability
Will Define it to be LLC and X is some over all the elements in
Alphabet
I'm applying for the city of
The outcome
By the links that you have assigned with l i is the length in
Solve
The codes that you've assigned to the eye
I don't think nothing profound defining expected length
And it's probably a good idea to immediately
Here's an example
Alphabet alphabets going to be
And let's have a probability distribution
Quota 1818
This is a toy property distribution with uneven probabilities
I think we might want to know about this
I'm so humble is what is it
2 + 1/8 * 3 + 8
X
Phase 1 2 3 and 3 being respectively the logs base to office this
Cannot is one of the
So
Let's give ourselves a symbol code and then try and make it better and we need
Depend on what the rules of the game are actually done trying to be half
So what do we want let's let's defiantly
The rules
First and then look at some examples
Restoril is it had better work when someone codes of this and then someone else and decodes the better get back
What we first put must be
We wanted to decode correctly
We wanted to guarantee to decode correctly not just have a 99.9%
Fight Goods in a slightly silly approach of last time
We wanted to always decode correctly
Let's just run around the rules and then I'll say a bit more precisely what we what we mean by 5's
Ideally we'd like it to be easy to decode as well so we don't want to have
The recipient having test
Spend hours staring at the code book trying to figure out where the punctuation where the missing punctuation
In the in this receive string
So easy to decode would be nice to have
But it's not essential if if we can get a big win on this final objective which is
Small owl
Okay
Let's just be precise about what we mean by it's gone to the code right we want the code to be
Uniquely decodable
So when you receive an encoded string there should be no ambiguity about what was sent
Stop
Annie
String X
And any other string why
Such that
X is not the same as why
We want the encoding
All facts not equal
Man cutting
Have life
That's the definition of unique dakotabilities
Okay
Just to check my no texting is clear
City of AI is the way we encode a particular element of the alphabet and then you have see all the
Spring-like acts that just a concatenation of X1 X2
Overloading the symbol C to me neither
The way that you encode a single symbol or it could be the encoding of an entire string
Alright okay let's define
Some symbol codes and have a think about these objectives what does it mean to say
What does that imply how do we catch a small expected length
Is this a good start for English
Could it be my best is it uniquely decodable
Let's look at these simple example s Define a code code C1 and it's code
Weather going to be
1 and 3 zeros
Is there a 100
Please Arizona
Not deliberately made them oil for characters long cuz now we know the recipient will be able to put the punctuation
Expected length
All right
Can we improve on this is this is this the best
Possible
Code for this
Ensemble
Any suggestions
Should we get rid of some of those arrows
Would that work
Who have been shot today
Get rid of the trailing zeros brilliant thank you
Okay so we remove all the trailing zeros
Then the recipient will still be able to figure out where the punctuation marks or to be
Because I can just look for the Wang Wang comes at the end of any code what
Right but it's still sell punctuating and it's easy to decode cuz it just read along to the Head
It must have been a sea or whatever whenever I have got to
Expected length of this while I would do that for you in advance its 1.875
1 + 7/8
That's a nice idea
Can we get the expected length on a shorter how about
How about this one how about
That code
What the expected length of this song
It's like you like this one
Okay
Is eating edible
Maybe not because
Even very short strings may have the same encodings each other is not negotiable
The goal is to get the expected length very short
Oso
Can we do any better than than this one well
How about this we need to have have a bit more like they're going to be a bit different from each other
That's one of the road tax deduction from the rule 800
Photos must be different
And that's the consequence of
You need to go to Boise
Different 0 1 0
+ 1/0
The
Expected length of this is one on 5/8
Expected length is there's a chance of a ha of
Akula for this 808
Where do they come from expected length is
There's a half chance of getting a length of 1
Lacrosse chance of Atlanta 2
Plus I want a chance of 3 + 1/8 chance of
Food
And then I added that it up
All right
What's the average length of a given that the lynx are going to be
Length
I want to free
Huntik
Questions
So what do you think of this guy
Encode something
Chauffeur expected length
Example who flipped out so far
Batman code something with it c a a b
Encoded with
Code number 3
My man Courvoisier baby we dance
Guam
Wang
Mom
So is C4
Easy to decode
Is it uniquely decodable
What we're trying to do here is so sale close to the wind we want to make or Cobra the shortest possible
We don't want to close
Have problems of unique dakotabilities
What's up
Is this uniquely decodable
I could stare hard at this and I'm trying to figure out
Is this a mother interpretation so you read along a 01 how could you get zero
Has to be a c doesn't say so thank God
This one
Bong
There a what could be that I was thinking I'll look in the code book Maybe
Who looked at it could be an A and an a
And then
Baby
But it could have been
Maybe it was a
Hey Ya
And the one is there a d
Mendoza's zero
From somewhere
So it's difficult to decode cuz I am not quite sure it is especially if we haven't
Reached the end yet
Don't play what's going on
Can anyone give us a proof
Preferred mini find two strings that have exactly the same
BC I got so if you
Encode
DC
That gives u0103
DC-10
010 ik and
It had got another string that also includes house
A b c d e f
Well I'm there at 12 okay sorry if you're cool with x
And that's why the difference between encoding
This is useless no bootable
So what's going on
Let's get ourselves one more example
She finds
His C5
Is there a long
1 0
On what
Expected length of this is
Sarah Lancaster
So that's not as good as this one
I found it to be a few more
So don't go any further ideas
Any ways we can improve yeah
Haha
So you're suggesting take C2
And treat the last word so I got C6
Using wang Vera Wang
Is there a Vera Wang but you're saying you don't actually need that final punctuation time won't you sing
3 zeros
If you're using C2 you know a woman is coming next
They can get rid of it
Write a text of the length of 1 2 3 on 3
Which incidentally
All the same as the Shannon information contents let's go Shi
One bit two bits leave it simply this
So expected length
Which is average of blank is going to be the same as the average of the contents
Class 1 and 3/4 which is Santa Fe
Right that's a fun idea we got a symbol code who's expected length is the entropy
If we encode c a a b
This
Then we got
Girls hair long
Wall
Guam
Interesting thing to notice that this
Set a Cota has lots of zeros in a few Wong to make it any better
Visit unit 2 decodable
Can I don't give an argument why it must be you need to be to go to bowl
What's up already set at
You're being shy how the receiver can read along
And look at the code code book
Once they reach the end of
About as well as in the cookbook nothing else would have happened you can reach you can't get through
A different code word on the way to the Cobra the are actually fixing off
No code way to the prefix of any other
Code word
So this code this is a prefix
Code is the
Name against this no
Code realize
Is a prefix of a Nyala
We don't have to use
Prefix codes but it makes them easy to decode
Another property of a prefix code is you can arrange the code Woods in a tree
The branches in the tree of the decision is the next Doctor going to be a 0 or 1 and
Each step in the tree really keep going or you stopped because you found a code word so in this one
Go down to one branch and you start when you found the code with a which is
Go this way 0.10 followed by 1 then you can be
Which is included with Vera Wang
The symbols we soar as we went along those branches we keep going down here
Chrissy
This is d
All right
I'm going to give you just one
Call code enforcement board
What's protection
Whatever
Let me Define
Another code C7
It look like a swamp 10100
I've deliberately chosen this one
Because it's not a prefix for a is a prefix
4B and 4C
Right
That's not a prefix code which means it may be a bit of a headache to decode
If you receive a Wong and you know some more stuff is coming and he was Evil Zero what was going on
Play the Beav we stopped to eat another zero you still there
I still don't know what's going on
Maybe when a woman comes along then maybe you can figure out whether the first and goal was and I a b or c
Okay
So we don't like this cuz it's not the code
Is it actually you need to decodable
Yes why
Okay so if you reverse these full code words they all the same as the code was a C6
Is uniquely decodable
If this one will not uniquely decodable that would mean it has got to code Words which
Sorry to strings x and y whose encodings are identical to each other
Hand
You would have found yourself a pair of
Strings
What type of sign code would I wear for this code
And we know that's impossible because this one is uniquely decodable
But we don't like it cuz it's not the prefix code
This is
Edible
Rut so one of the ideas with floating now is easy to the code
Could mean for example that we'd like a prefix code please
But we really do want small expected length
Let me suggest that I did now about how we get small expected length
We found a coat hair which was speculating could be the best you can do
For this Ensemble with a symbol code
Because I already heard some serums about not being able to do better than that
And it has the property
Here's a key intuition about symbol codes and is over all of their commercial property
Short code words to the probable outcomes and longer code words
To the last probable once that's what it's all about
I'm not supposable guess about how we might get the smallest possible
Expected life
We could say hello you give me a list of them and I'll give
The shortest possible code word
Handle and steadily longer covert as we go down the list
How to chat to your neighbor and see what you think of that idea
Stop suggested and I did the right spirit is giving short
Code words
The probable outcomes
Some long ones the last purple ones
Is that going to work or can anyone
Criticize that for us
If you got a huge number symbols fan watch
It might not be good
It's definitely not good
Probably not okay
I might agree with you
Let me give you some backup for your intuition there
We found a case where this
Proposed algorithm is getting us to the interface that would be too critical of it but maybe we can find a counterexample
It doesn't it doesn't work it doesn't need to be among stuff example
Can give the mole a probability of a quota except just to make life interesting will add Absalom
One of them and I that Sloan Iowa to Towanda subtract Epsilon able to from this one
A billion
Feather all essentially they will have a probability of 1/4
All right
And now we apply this
Suggested algorithm end up with
And the rest
C6
All right
So is that a new probability distribution
When you use code 6 which is proposed planets other than expected length
Fat is
The length of a 1/2
Three-on-three is the last one in the list
And the average of those since the Rolex the Pro Bowl
9/4 riches to
And 1/4 bits is that the optimal symbol code
How are you better how
Dc5 and expected length will be to
QED
Suck
But the length of C5
Repeat
Right
So we can just use that simple rulers got the right Spirit we need to identify some so
The trade-off of
When do you give
Short code words to the most purple guy recognizing
But when we decide to not give him or length two words
If one of them. Select one then some others longer
But like when you put a glove glove for the watering squeeze of your the fingers
The other ones have to get together some sort of conserved quantity looking in there
And that can conserve has to do with unique dakotabilities if we allowed ourselves to shorts and some of
The words and didn't like the others longer it looks like we lose unique unique dakotabilities
I've lost bored as well that's why I missed
I think the time has come for me to reveal how this rubber glove work
The constraint of you need to coat ability
What's
Siletz rifle through a way of thinking about this
If
I only use code words of a particular length how many of them can I have
Well
If all my code was
Have length
Al
2 then
I can have
Evo my CO2 at a blank free I can have a h
Schumacher sc11 can have two today
Open
That I was changing the size of the alphabet and noticing that I have long words
I can have more of an exponentially more often
And
Here is the idea that raps this up and is consistent with everything we've seen so far
You can think of each code word
At some length l
Have a Costless course
To Salina South
I'm overdoing it's going to the symbol coating supermarket
Are all the different styles of a supermarket you can pick any code with you want
Is the entire set of all conceivable coconuts
Annie's choice because it might not be uniquely decodable
And I've arranged to denial for a child has which of the same length
Choices and the size of the package for each cobras in heading how much it'll cost you
So you can budget of one which is in light of the supermarket you can buy
These two cobras if you want to sit on the wall and then you're done you can't add any more code words of any length because they'd be
Or you can have these people
Y8
We've seen a bunch of things you can also have
You can pay those thought I was code number one
And you haven't exceeded your budget and that's uniquely decodable the fact that you haven't exceeded your but it doesn't guarantee the
It's uniquely decodable
Definitely if you go over your budget of Wong then it wouldn't be uniquely decodable so what we
Is the following assertion
That's right
If a code is uniquely decodable
Then
The Constable code words has to be less than your budget some of us Ally must be less than or equal to
Wall these are the costs of goods
That's your budget
I miss is called the crafting equality
And it's true
Haven't proved it I just told you it and the proof is in the book
So if you're interested in a proof
It's in the textbook
So this is what you didn't dakotabilities implies you got to stay within your budget
So that was code Wong and we have some other ideas
It was code number five
That was the selection that we made
With
Code
Play I want it
CO2
Re-stuffing of everybody but it didn't quite you that the whole budget cuts on noticed we could
Make a change instead of buying the there is everyone
Code Red Rock.
We could love find a Woman by The 000 next door instead I'm not made the expected like shorter which is good
And then we looked at this guy was my silly idea
Sorry I buy that 100 * 1
Budget
And it was a great Labor to find a proof it went that it didn't work and have to think about strength
No point even trying this thing it's violated Unity decodable
All right in blue that we have the optimal code
And here is
C7 which I want golf which is why we reverse told him so this is also uniquely decodable
The difference between the prefix code in blue which is little sense with walkthrough
Buying code with that you wouldn't confuse with each other
Flatout facility back to front one
C61 10100 which are prefixes of each other and their own
Y coordinates in this in this picture
All right
So that's the question coffee and
A code that
Step right up to the budget that uses the full budget
We will call a complete
Code
I complete code is one that has sum of 2 - lite2
Wow
If you haven't chosen yourself a complete code the advice is you can probably go back to the supermarket makes me switches
I got yourself shorter
Code there's a bit silly not to use a complete card
All right
I love you too easy to decode codes off prefix codes
So
Let's address the Practical question
Very first practice
Next 5 minutes
The theoretical question is how well can we do
With
Symbol codes
So if I give you any ensemble
Axe and if you come up with the best symbol code by whatever method
How small can expected length
Are the definition of expected length is Samurai GI
L i
We're not going to show that whatever you do
Where the symbol code you can't beat the entropy I'm willing to identify what you need to do in order to get
Close to the edge people all the way to the entropy of
Figure out what these expected length should be
Like me to give us a clue
Define
The ideal
Length
Spokeo glad to be one of the prophecy
I'm going to
Introduce a definition
So I say let's assume the civil code or to be using those
Making a definition and then we'll end up with a proof
What's the ideal length
Now if you rearrange this
And if you imagine that someone has picked
Some light L I may or may not be the ideal length you can use those simile to Define
Some implicit probabilities
So which those
Chosen lights would be the ideal length
But thanks though we've defined our relationship to relax and probabilities in this way and I'm going to pull the implicit problem
Implicit probiotic you that you can get from whatever lengths you have come up with
Will B22 - l i
Except
You maybe didn't choose a complete code so maybe the sum of all of these isn't warm which would be
So I'm going to / the appropriate Zedd
Where
That is
Sum of 2 to the - Al
Which will be worn if it is a complete code one if you've made a sensible
A trip to the supermarket
But it could be smaller than wall
Note
That will be less than or equal to 1 for any
And that equals 1/4 a complete code
Right
What does that mean
Well it means lii the links that you chosen a low base to war mode
Qi - locations vent
I know I can plug this into out
Sal is summer i p i
Where's. Lovelace tooth
Wonton qi
Minus log base 2 of
Then
Sorry my board hygiene isn't very good today
Okay wouldn't it be great if it said some of P log 1 / p
So let's do that sound like log base 2
That's not true anymore so we need to add on the appropriate things that is true
Log p over Q
Looking at the end some of Pi is warm so we can
Suck the dog
That out of a summation
Right
We've got somewhere
If you pick any symbol code to Tool
Then it's expected length will equal the entry
Plus something
Plus something else
Let's give it a name for colace kullback leibler Divergence between p and Q
And
His little theorem
Some of the log P / 222 distribution of p and Q
Is Greg Hunter
And it's one of the most important inequalities of information Theory
With the quality
Only
2 is equal to
I love that we already know
Is less is less than or equal to 1/2 lug that
Is less than or equal to zero and minus logs that is greater than or equal to 0 with a quality
Only if the code
Is
Completes
Straighten wrinkled if the code is uniquely decodable
With equality only if it's complete
So this is true
For any code
For any symbol code
So what we have just proved is that the expected length
Not the best we've shown what you need to do in or
Go to to get to the entropy you need your PT equal York you so you should be using
Implicit probabilities
Equal to probability
So your length should be the information content
So you got a quality
The lengths you're using
Persona in formation Campana
And you got the complete code
Which will happen for free when you do that
Okay
So what are we done we still have proved a source coding theorem for symbol codes we're showing that you should be
Using the Shannon information code contents to set to code websites if you want to get to the end of pee and then you will get
And you can't get any further
Hey that was the
Theoretical bottom line for symbol codes
So the ideal code links information contents
He's like the probabilities we have to English base 2 of them
So in practice for any real probability distribution typically contacts
We got exactly to the entropy
So there's a missing result which is well how close can you get
And his fiance
And I'm not going to prove this put it in the textbook
If these ideal length l i * which all the time and information
Not integers
How close can you get
Answer well you can still always cat
Within one bit
Avanta p
So
There exists
Optimal single code
For which
Pacific
So I can get with it one bit
Which sounds pretty good
Come back next week
To hear whether this is good enough or whether in fact we still want to do better
So that's very what about practice wouldn't it be great to be able to just take a probability distribution
Optimal symbol code for that property distribution
Let me tell you how to do this
How to make optimal symbol codes
I'm looking to prove it you can read the book
The method for making multiple symbol codes cuz I will show you his cold the Huffman algorithm
Highness very elegant
And it's not completely obvious why it should actually be off the mold and why it should get you any of the optimal
The ideal Shannon information count
Content
Codelynx
So is a summary of how it works
Remember how prefix code could be related to a binary tree is Bill that binary tree
Starting from the leaves we're going to start from the smallest most remote
Leaves build a binary tree
Stopping
From
Farthest
Leaves of the tree
And that's essentially the album let me show you what I mean
I'll see you with an example that's usually the easiest way
Let me
Invent a probability distribution
My cat hair is a 6 element probability event
And his
Statement of the algorithm
Combine
The
Two symbols
With smallest probability
Into a new single symbol
Android
Alabama
Okay so we look at our list of probabilities and we say these are the two smallest so we will combine them Define
A little bit of a binary tree we combine them 0.21
Inari repeat on the set of five
We got 0.2
Fife
Now we have to be foolproof smallest witch
14 + 521
Recombine them
We got zero point
I was the
First iteration of a second iteration of a Nation
And then
We've got
25 and 35 smaller than 40
So I can buy them at 0.6 in the fourth step
Then we can buy mace at 1
How about tonight
And now we've made a binary tree and so we have made prefix code because we can just slap label 0 1 0 1
Anyway you like Vera Wang 01
Sarawak
And that defines a code words reading from the root back out
The leaves just as an example 100 to the code word you'll get to this one is
Unfeeling
Feliz
Optimal
Cool
Suck
Let me
Summarize what we've said
Reviews gets in equality
We talked about unique dakotabilities
We've introduced the idea of prefix codes
Binary trees and symbol codes that are really all about building nice binary trees
Whenever you get a code but does a TV entropy
The code links are equipped with information contents that's the ideal code length
And with a symbol code you can always get within one bit of entropy
And you can do that with the Huffman algorithm
Here are the results we stated without proof the book has
Proofs of photos
Results
I've got a few more slides just to keep things moving with some
Things you can be doing for next time I already encouraged you to do a project
Namely invent a compressor and on compressor resourceful 10000 prevent coin
Whose probability of warm is
.01 Implement and estimate how it works and the screen is God's mother
Recommended exercises and recommended
Reading
Thanks for coming see you next week