Okay welcome to lecture number 9 today on main topic is going to be inference inference
Parameters for example you do a science experiment
And you want to infer the promises
Put on the LIE
Happy data you've got
But before we do that I want to
Point to a little gem of information Siri
You may not have noticed
I'd like us to start by thinking about
The binary Erasure Channel
What we did in the last couple of lectures was re-established Shannon's noisy Channel coding theorem that says
Any channel you can work out his capacity by maximizing Mutual information
And then it possible to make an encode and decode of it communicate reliably over.
Channel
Reliably meaning you can get the error probability as close as you like to zero but you can always communication anyway
Right up to the capacity
What's the capacity of the binary AirAsia
Channel please
Have a quick chat to your neighbor
Here's a question
And I'll go sold it over here in just one minute
So there's only two ways you can solve these questions
You can either work out the mutual information this way around
Or
People around
And often one way is easier than the other
So let's do this
Binary Erasure Channel both ways round
I'll generalize a little bit
So that we're putting in
P0 and P1 because I'll pretend we don't know that the optimal optimal input distribution
Coolest have to be symmetric
And I'll call these probabilities
If we do it this way the first time is binary entropy of Tino's
And then the second time we need to think through all the different ways that could happen not quite a lot of what we need to think
Free things
Figure out how probable they are then look at what the entropy of x given Y is
That's quite a lot of work except almost all of it is easy if you got a zero you know that
Input was a zero so
There's no entry in that case
Simulate if apple is a Wong
Send input doesn't have any entropy anymore it's only if the? Comes out which happens with Provera
By hooker by crook
Then you still don't know what the input was any information at all about football
Posterior distribution of Empire is still
The same as it was when we started
So
Which is
Take 15 off
-1 -
Maximize that with respect to Pinos
You end up with Pinot equals 1/2
If you want X
Okay
So usually doing it this way around is a bit hard cuz you have to think about lots of
Inferences but in this case those three inferences were fairly easy so this was a nice route
For solving this
Open early we could have worked out the entropy of why that means you need to work out the identity of the probability
Why
Being zero why being?
And why she ain't
One and you could lavoris a workout those three
Numbers the probability of getting a 0 out
Is
0 *
One nice ass
Etc so you could work out those three numbers then you have a big massive stuff to put into the entropy company
3 *
So that looks like a turbo to work
Then secondly we want the ad field why
Given X
That's easier because if you condition on a particular
X coming in
Then the entry why is was just a choice between 0 or?? And the entropy of that distribution
Is the same either way around it's just H2O that was an easy thing this is looking horrendous but I want
To introduce you
To a little of property of entropy which recover decomposability
This is not virgin sorry we're getting to the gym in a moment
I think a possibility
You can if you want work out the entropy of a distribution over several
Characters in alphabet
Fight
Imagining that you learned the character in a sequence of steps and add up how much xp you get on average at 8
Each of those steps
You could imagine finding out
Is
The character that came out a? Or not
I'm Reno
That the fraction of question marks coming out is always f
Doesn't matter what input distribution you vote for
We can say first
What's the?
And then
If not
What was it
And
Then and fee of Y
Is the sum of the amount event for you guys to teach with her stepfather first you got the entropy
Ask
Stefania is a? Or something else
Then
With probability 1 - at it's something else
And then you got the entropy
Of finding out whether it's a zero or one given that you know that it's not a?
The probability of 0 or 1 if you know it's not a? That's coming out
Is just the same as Pinot who he wants the same
Bryce Sheffer to the entry of that is
H-2a peanut
Okay sorry that
In the textbook as well if you want to read up on
Clarify what I just told you
You can make life easy for yourself by being smart about high computer interface
So this was looking hairy but it's not too hairy when we did it that way
Answer the answer comes out to be useful information is equal to
This wall switch is HVAC
Prefer
+ 1 - at
Translate Filipino
Minus this thing which is a true that
We have a grand cancellation of H20
I molested by myself h2p note as we had before when you maximize at the capacity
Is
Who am I
What time does the capacity I want to go back to this diagram everything we talked about
Annoy Channel coding said let them out then we go to noisy Channel
I'm going to slap a clever and coder on the front
Looking to add a clip of Dakota that does inference during the input balls
How fast can we communicate
For this particular channel the answer is you can communicate at a rate
One- at Paris
That's achievable
Nah
Imagine that we had introduced a completely different topic
Cooled
Noisy Channel coding with feedback so I'm going to change Instagram now I'm going to mention the completely different diagram
Where everything that comes out of the channel
Get back
And is available
To the encoder
Why are the different diagram
He's got an extra communication link
Back from the end of the channel to the encoder exactly what's going on
So if the encoder
Send
For example 10010
And what comes after the channel Mike
Happy
?
There's a rug?
Is there a
11?
No
What's the answer to the question how fast can you communicate over this channel given that you've got feedback available
Am I completely change the game right
Because the sort of encoding trait you could not use is you could just say while I'm going to listen to my output
?
I will retransmit it was just lost
Cuz I know that I didn't receive anything
So I'll just Ricans match
So you wouldn't
Use
First story
If you had the? You're trying to send one
What you would send would be
So
This is original
Sure
And then your transmission
Would be assuming that a question mark happened at the fourth
What were you trying to make
You would transmit
100 again because?
And then
Okay I think that the next one is a Wong
So that gets
Lost is not a?
Insight transmit again
Satan would just clear the manager at on the bus
Okay you keep on
Transmission symbol until it is correctly received
What's the rate you're going to be able to achieve with that clever scheme is making use of this feedback
Habitats your neighbor
Anyone
What rate can you communicate.
If you ain't used to the red tape I think
On average
So
If you just imagine how much of the time you spend successfully communicating it's whenever the wrong? You have
Channel
That was a?
Coming out
You want a cheap and reliable communication atoll
And the fraction of time?
So the rate at which all communicating using the steam link is
Any questions anyone
Not clear on this
Yes so
When are the possible question marks in a row you just keep on retransmitting until what comes after the channel is nothing
?
Retransmitting
Doesn't affect this argument the argument is if this is time
But if you send
Symbols on the some of them
Got time to the question marks
Then you're going to be successful in communicating in all of these
Vincent's hair
Whether or not?
Every time does not a? You will have thought the next bit across
Does not relevant
Whether the? Cluster together every time there is any? The next bit will humping
Next one in the file
All right
When you see back you all communication on averages race 1 -
Woman's that Bit Spur
Units of time
Use of the channel
Oh my goodness that's the time
So we added feedback which made life much easier for us but it hasn't actually increase the rate at which we can
Communicate
And Shawna is saying
Should we redo all of information Theory to include feedback I'm answer is no
You don't need feedback just use around them code just use a really small writing to make an appropriate
Dakota and you don't need to buy feedback doesn't actually help you communicate
Antipasto
So that's a gym for me
And there are araiza correcting codeschool Fountain codes
Cuz a lot of you to communicate
Almost at the capacity of Arabia channels and finding codes are
In chapter 50 of
The textbook
Any questions
Okay question is what if you had errors in the feedback Channel sometimes
Then what would you do
Enchanted looks like I'm not going to use a feedback anyway cuz he's not helping so it could make things with us if
You trusted the feedback and it wasn't trustworthy
We don't need it
Okay
On Riverside
Let's not talk about inference
And I'm going to
In this lecture look at
A very simple
Inference problem
People often work with gasoline distribution
We'll look at the gasoline distribution for this lecture but I will rapidly moves on to other morning
Distribution
For gas station
It doesn't really change your life to say I now I'm going to learn how to do in France right because
The extended methods of dealing with thousands are already fine
But I'm going to talk to you
In the next lecture but when you look at other problems apart from inferring the mean and standard deviation of the Galaxy
It can transform your life when you learn how to actually do things right instead of using ad hoc Curry's
Stop
The general topic were discussing now
Is inference
Amazon motivations you might have for doing inference
Maybe we'll doing
Cosmology
Android unknown cosmological parameters used some nice big expensive
Telescopes and
Stop lights and things
And those underlying political private has like Hubble constant in the matzav
Dark matter in this month give rise to Cosmic microwave background radiation fluctuations
And you measure those measurements
Open imperfect noisy measurements
I may be upset stupid IV as well
Oops I should have gone half that cools by the same as long as a new measure
Properties of a supernova
And then having made over those measurements
We want to infer okay what do we believe about
Infer
Is another motivation maybe you still use email
And when you receive emails is email wrong email to insightful
There is an underlying variable that you might care about which is actually a piece of spam or not
This is a variable cold-weather this particular item is spam
9022 email
And to save your time
How to save the OS infinite amounts of time
Delete this time yourself you'd like to have an automated method of just looking at the email
And inferring
This spam variable
So you might want to spam filter
What's the matter examples
We might be wanting to do
Image recognition
Speech recognition
Character recognition
Image Direct
Speech Rec
Character
Recognition printed or handwritten
Characters
On the general pattern is
Does something on the left hand side which is the underlying
Message I think we care about and what comes out on the right is sensitive data that depends on that we want to turn the air around
And then further thing
On the left hand side on the line cordless
Okay
Just getting back to spawn example
DeSoto way you might imagine handling spam
As you might imagine
Females living in a Face-Off email and real emails to you that you do want to read
My thoughts before Linda cluster
Emails about
Wind power emails about
Bayesian inference
Emails about spam clusters
And I need to golf spam about
Russian lessons nigerians and insightful
Different colors of pills
And we want to
Infer
These clusters and
Reliably identify
The stuff in the Clusters that we do care about
So you think of spam as maybe being clustering problem and string
I'm next time all the time after
Kevin Hogan
And given how prevalent
Videos of dancing distributions is
Let's chat a little bit of a problem
Where what going on is that the mean and the standard deviation
An outcrop some data
X1
Through
At 10
My notation that I'll try and use consistently
Is in general ends going to be the amount of data we get
Little and is always going to run from warm to end whenever you see a suffix you can usually info it goes up to
Without me saying
Also animals and try to use the same
Latha
Fairly consistently
All right
And this is a gaussian distribution started to be completely explicit P of X and given you an Sigma
1 / square root of 2
8 - x - news
Scrap OVA
Two Sigma squared
Hummus
And the test is we want to infer and sigma
Kevin
Are they tough
Right
Let's do that
So let's walk through
The world looking in
And it's good to always distinguish Two Worlds one is hypoxia space where parameters live
And another is the weather Wednesday to lift and in this case confusingly they both look kind of similar to each other
Because the unknown mean could be anywhere on the real line and the day to come on the real line
But
I'll try to keep track of when we talk about a date axis label acts and when are we talkin about
A hypothesis actress that might be labeled mute
All of the data points come along the stage right
Stigma
I mentioned to her as well the one way of telling the difference
Is sometimes will show of you I just found the cigarettes at 62 dimensions
Is a one-dimensional picture and it shows
Poor 6 possible different settings of Mew and sigma
All of which happen to have the same but he was Sigma the prediction about the data would be so Visa
Send it down c&n citiz
But different values
Of Mew and sigma
Diesel half and half
Different
And the same better Sigma named Eliza Griswold
Okay next
Here are another six possible hypotheses about
Where
The news all happen to be the same
On the standard deviations vary from .5
Up to
So what did I do that I just stumbled around in the hypothesis space
And showed you one two three four five six points in this two-dimensional space here
Maybe I'll quickly get rid of Vegas Facebook
So I showed you six
6 hypotheses
Like this in data space
What each of those products or any particular one of these makes its own production in the database
Which looks
Besides that's what I'd expect today to be like if I am true
Okay here are
Another different from each other
And you and sigma slice each one of them are shown it
Predictions
And
Thai Spice
Okay
How to do inference
Mew and sigma
This is the correct way to do inference you get your data
Hey I'm telling you want to go 5
Datapoints
Which will arrive at these horizontal
Coordinates Hannah I just slept
Above
The line
Coventry Y coordinates
Right
What does Bayes theorem say you should do
Well you should update
Your beliefs
About me at Sigma in proportion to how well each of those bodies of Mew and sigma
Predicted
FaceTime says how provolone
Is
How well they predicting today Utah
X how profitable
Before you.
Normalize
Mets normalizing constant is
Integral
Simi
Two Sigma
Hope to stop sex
No
I'm taking
For the next few lectures quite a Hardline position that I think when does a well posed question does the correct answer to it
And this is in contrast to the way I love people think about statistical inference
Does another way of doing inference why there's lots of ways of answering those questions and I think that's extraordinary
Thing to believe I think there is
A correct way of answering Lopez problems
I don't think infants should be an exception from it
Something to make real explicit is that
Only difference is depend on the assumptions
Some people sometimes you don't have to make assumptions
But how could it be otherwise
So every one of these things is conditioned on H
HSV assumption that the data come from a gaussian distribution and it's whatever
If you want to make about what we believe me to take my might be
Beforehand
And I think it's on the schedule that you do have to make a
Photos options
All right
What does it actually look like
Well this is saying how well did you predict the date this is the
The meat of it
Y'all sleep if we haven't got any particular
Strong interesting prior knowledge about me to take my dependent
On-base arm says
You don't need to know how well they were predicting things that didn't happen
Tile probabilities on not relevant is no such thing as tails in the correct way of doing in Prince
All you need to do is look at the values
Oh
The predictive densities the 5-day two values that have actually occurred so if we wanted to compare
Just the six hypotheses that I've identified on the screen the rainbow
Six different colors the only numbers you need to know to answer that question
The number is highlighted by the point at which the probability density assigned to the
Six different hypotheses
Of course the full-face hypotheses is
The Infinite Space the whole book value
But if we just wanted to keep a V6 that's what you need to know
What you do with them while you want to come out and you multiply them together because
The probability if you're coming independently
This is just a product from 1 to end
All vaccines given mean and sigma
Which we already wrote down
Overhead door just need to multiply two numbers together
And that gives us a lot to his riches how well you predicted
What happened
Okay
So those numbers are always relevant to the inference
So what does that look like what does one of those numbers look like
I'm going to
Reduce the size of a Titus at down from 5
To just warm
And now I'm going to wonder around the hypothesis-based muessigmann looking at what happens
The value of P of x n
Given to you and sigma as we wander around and you and signifies
This is what it looks like
So I'm going to slide across at Six Sigma
And then different values of Six Sigma
Total for his example
Here's a value of Mew and sigma
And a grown little spiked hair whose length is the same as the height
From
The y-axis to the yellow Cafe
All right
I'm going to wander around adding spikes
I'm hopefully you can see the eclipse in lines that show
How high is the orange star wars about the y-axis for each of those possible values of
And it's not very surprising that what that looks like is it going to be in with the same width as the standard deviation we just picked
1.2 as I told all three of those Levi's let's switch to another body or Sigma
It's the small things
Shutting how well
Today's predicted the same day tomorrow
Repeat Sargon even firespike
Adam purple
We can make a surface plot
I want some of those look like
And here they are
Any particular value Sigma it looks like a bump that goes up and down
As you come to smaller and smaller values
The high for that guy seems getting higher and higher
So the console port is actually a slightly scary looking thing there
Sofra Singleton
Stupid my wifey
Acanto fluff
Has consoles
It look something like that with these two hypotheses
Tan have extremely small Weiser signal that just happened to nail the
Really precisely
So that's the likelihood function
In the case of 1 datapoint showing how well
Every purple Valley from U and sigma
Predicted
Hot what happened
Okay
Let's repeat that and I will multiply together five of those things are going to look at the product of five of these functions if you
How's your wonder and immune Sigma space and it's for these fine face points
When you take
The five numbers showing there
And multiply them all together
The product is this little orange stick shown on the right hand side
Very small number phone number
Lance Morgan
Change Sigma to a small value
And it went up and came down
And pick up my multiplying lcdc please scan the Crossville multiplying things with our galaxy and functions
With each other either the galaxy of the scented on different values the product of a rose is still a gaussian integer
Replacing at
And that woman has to be higher this one with Sigma as we went across to look at
Values of singer equals no .6
We got a high peak
95 signal point five
Purple we find out we can even hire a peek
And I forgot to an even small about your semen
Roughly a quarter
Not when you multiply together these five
Purple numbers
Some of them are quite close to zero
And so we're not doing quite so well anymore so I made the Redskin that
Iris pahatsi
Redskin the highest 8.2 isn't as high as
Mr. purple
Okay
Suck what has happened
Now if we do a contour plot of the products
This was for just one like
How to make a Funko Pop
Steven Yeun
It looks like this
It looks
A bit like that
Oodles and it doesn't have a scary bizarre place where are Infinities happen
Tyme hair anymore
All right
And we can ask the question what is the best type of this in the sense of the highest
Likelihood
So this point
Nothing's got any special status at all this is not an essential thing to
The focus song but people sometimes
You can go find the menu and the sigma
When does a simple homework exercise to work out the formula
So that if you want
And
The night seemed like no promises Usher and after the stages at the green line
Density looks like when you sent me when signature
Right
So
Want to go to like a good you can if you want to go and find
The promises that have the biggest value of the function
Positive that's not
Fundamental the fundamental thing you want to do when you're doing inference is you want to know the whole Buster distribution
Not just
Professional music music system
All right so that's the maximum like it promise
Going back to the entire like a function this is what it looks like when we spin it round
South China on the bottom
Uppababy
A log scale surface
Right
So if you do the homework exercise and you work out what the maximum likelihood value of
Mu and sigma is
You may not be surprised to find that
Mew maximum likelihood
Is
Xbox
Hannity does you slide across to any
Possible values Sigma
The maximum
Value of the likelihood there any slicing volume Sigma is
Xbox being by definition
Iran
Xn
I'm not something you can derive wouldn't have to guess let's think of an estimate from you you just write down the light YouTube
Function is a simple homework exercise
Define
The maximum of that function is at this location in contrast the standard statistics when think that
Difficult and you need to make S Tomatoes you end up scratching
Hair the likely function
Is a way of coming out with estimate is if you want to point a point value
What about Sigma well
The maximum likelihood value Sigma is what you get when you press the stigma and button on your calculator
So
Your calculator has two Sigma buttons you shoved in the day turn to a live load calculator
10 - 1 button in the maximum likelihood
Is what you get when you press Sigma
No
Discount applied hair isn't so the symmetric it it doesn't have concentric circles that that's what
Lopsided getting wider as you go up
And the reason for that is fairly intuitive
If it were actually the case that the me
Is not equal to
Did Asa mean
It will be okay something you the true underlying mean isn't exactly the station mean
For example the true value is
Hey a little bit away
From
Potato mean
Then
Think of
What the battery probably is given that
All the lights are off of the coast around here Bass
The average distance the mean Square distance to one of those
Because we moved away from the day to me
Then it was when we were out today to me
That means our estimate of how big do there is probably is
Is a bit bigger than what you would think the variances if you knew that the true mean really is equal to the day
Say to me
So that's why
Peak Vista
Why did function hat
Is off that little bit upwards away from the value house
If we assume you is actually both of the day to me
Sidedness
And if we take into account now the fact that we don't know
New
And if someone told I don't care. I want to know how big the noise
Level is because I'm interested in noise
Please tell me what I should believe about the noise give Anastasia
And given that we haven't got a clue what we do is accept what they show is telling us
If we now put that request into mathematics
What the requester is telling us
I'm going to clear about what Miu is and I don't care
They saying I've got a very broad prior on me
Okay let's just use an unspecified
Uniform distribution of some with that we don't care anymore
And then it saying please tell me what I should believe about Sigma
The way you answer that question
Is
We can work out
We could imagine receding into steps we could say
What would you be she doesn't want to know me but let's imagine inferi it anyway
Let's imagine when you Sigma Delta Zeta
How advanced insurance work
Well we need to know the date I given U and sigma
X the prior probability
Have you
Normalize by the productivity
Sorry
Talk to myself a self inference number 1
Where where we imagine answering the thing that we don't care about
So you need to pry which I said is going to be some rules distribution one of a Delta Museum
Secondary Brule disrespect
And then this probability is the likelihood function
But we're assuming that we no Stigma
What does normalizing constant while this is
The integral theme
Kayavax
X
Normalizing constant
Often we ignore no more than constant speakers are they just know there's no dependents
All the thing on the left hand side
A little magic constant
But around the beautiful pass and often occurs in a serving for the normalizing constant one person doesn't care
90 + anybody wants to know
Is exactly the answer to the question someone else wants to know inference number two
Inference number two
The first player casters for
Was he said I just want to know what I should believe about Sigma
Given the data
And if you decide to come to my house
Cast
I'm not 580sm is the purpose of people today to give him Sigma sign for probably
/ normalizing he doesn't care
The date of dependent time but he does care about is the probability of all the data
Kevin Sigma
And that is
Personalizing constant
That is a very common pattern that when you just follow the rules of probability to work out what you want to know
Normalizing constants
That one person or unimportant for the next level of inference
So hey we need to do an integral with respect in view of this likelihood function
Assuming a flat
Prana hat
That's a simple homework exercise
When you do that inference
You can work out
What
The likelihood
Study of data
Given Sigma is as a function of Sigma so I'm going to show you my little grass
The likelihood
As a function of stigma and what it looks like is
That sort of thing
Is that the garbage day for the gamma distribution and it's going to Pink
And the peak is at
Sigma - 1
So that's what you think is for on the couch like that in this
Probability
View of inferences probability-based or Bayesian View
Okay
So what I've done here is I
Reintroduce you to familiar things that you've known since you were 15 years old you've had a calculator
Annex Barber I have a cigarette in Boston
How to say more n -1 button
And now we know a meaning for these buttons that they always of finding peaks of various
Likelihood functions of model likelihood
This thing we do here so the likelihood function is the likelihood all new and
Sigma
This is the correct use of the word likelihood by the way
The likelihood is
Imma talk about the probability of some data conditioned on the thing that we call it the likelihood of
Many people sadly used would like it improbability interchangeably
What is the likelihood of this is a probability of that and that Exchange.
When doing statistics I think it's a good idea to be absolutely rigorous about these are the times we use
Only when it's that correct usage which is in this context
This thing here is emotional like to hit
It's the motto of likelihood
Call Sigma
Which means it's the probability of all the data
Kevin Sigler
This thing way down here
Is the mountain like the hood
Alpha hypothesis
Which is the hypothesis that says
What did Isaac came from
I think I've seen with me and you and
IMDb action Sigma with
Prior distribution is described by P of Maryland
Sigma
There is another name that is sometimes given to this thing because it's such an important quality
I'm not going to like it is a bit of a mouthful
And sounds may be too technical perception important to take
I was going to see in the next election
This is the important if you want to do model comparison if you have if you had an alternative theory for weather station came from
This is how well this quantity measures
How well the theory age predicted the date of the happened
So this is what we need in order to model comparison
The evidence
4 model X that's not a universal
Notation of universal name but like a lot of people use this name as an alternative
Name for module likelihood
Okay
So that was
A familiar Beast dancing distribution
Answering the question
When you use Bayesian inference
What what
I got a question was is the evidence of Prior on the prior address I didn't eat in the next election we're going to do it
Mobile comparison
And what the evidence is is how well the theory
Predicted
The date of the happened
You when you want to do inferences how probable this theory is compared with other theories you need to put your own prior
On those those hypotheses the prior probability of hypothesis is not
All right just as here this is a likelihood
How much is the price
So the role that we haven't played in model comparison
Is the role that the body that the likelihood is playing
Endless Runner face there
So
Will do it again in the next election hopefully he'll become
Clara
In the next election we're going to start off with the following exercise
This is an exercise that I took from the exam paper in the Cambridge physics
Past exams
From the 1980s also
I'm the same question sad
Imagine that a source is emitting particles and IDK locations which we measure those location
Exponentially distributed in the length Skylander missile picture shows what that might look like if your
It was axes the horizontal coordinates
And the y-coordinate is just
Spacing points away from each other
The taser can only be observed however if location Fulton the window in the window goes from X-Men X-Men
220 centimeters
Now and decays are observed and their locations Xbox Rex and what do you think Lambda is
That's exam question and I want you to think about that for the next lecture
And I'd like you especially to cast your mind back
Before you ever heard of bass them as being the right way to do in Prince
How would you have solved this problem
Before you knew about base 10
And I'm hoping that you'll find it interesting to see how easy it is to solve this problem
Replaced them and how this contrasts with
Perhaps the difficulty of solving this problem
With all the ways you might have come across beforehand
So that's what we'll do next time
Thank you very much for listening just as a question
Yes absolutely so the question is
In the statistics literature and standard textbooks people talk about number of degrees of freedom
When you go from Aunt and might as well and you've lost one degree of freedom
And that absolutely is a helpful way to think about these things what we've done when we did this
Integral hair which we didn't actually do I said do that integral as I will question you integrated
That one parameter
Anat Goebbels up one degree of freedom of the noise if you actually knew
Un datapoints
Then you would have an independent measurements of how big the variances
But
If we don't know Mew and we integrated that we've lost one of those
Degrees of freedom if you like
Of measurement of noise so the number is that the number of independent measurements because of the noise
Has been reduced to a 10-1 it's definitely a helpful way to think about these things
It's all so you don't need to understand that concept to get the right answer
If you just write down the likelihood do the integral
Closest Ralph's
And say I'm interested in knowing which type of this
Did the best job of putting the day that you will find Sigma and -1 and you don't even need to understand
Degrees of freedom
But definitely degrees of freedom is an interesting and useful concept
Questions
Okay thank you