Welcome to lecture 14
Today's lecture is about variational methods
We've been talked about methods for dealing with complication probability distributions we made have
Nasty probability distributions because we are doing inference and a posterior distribution is nasty
We may also have nasty probability distributions for other reasons maybe we work on physics
And
In the lectures we've discussed Monte Carlo methods
And now go to the methods which are two possible ways of dealing with nasty but someone
Tractable distributions
His the overview of all the chapters in The Textbook that we've been looking at for the election so far
I should emphasize that there's some additional reading I'd encourage you to do is very short chapter on laplace's method
Which is another way of dealing with nasty distributions while you approximate the nasty distribution
Does a piece of reading for you
And from time to time I will refer to icing models as a good idea to have Radley chapter on icing bottles as well
Turn off the central
Websites for the book and for the course
And the other variational message looks like this assumption just as in Monte Carlo methods
There's a nasty red distribution
Kulfi
And
It's something that we can compute within a normalizing constant
Search for me to the -3 of X and we are able to compute e of x
And in very committed our assumption is the T-Rex is a fairly simple function but not quite simple
Enough for us to be able to actually answer the questions of Interest which all things like expected values of functions on the
Thought the idea of variational method well we introduced a simpler green distribution the record
And we parametrize that simply distribution in some way so Q is intended to be
Simple enough that we can evaluate expectations on interesting things on the Q
We make it adjustable and then we adjust the parameters of Q so that it is as close as possible by some
Metric to pee so we just leave promises
Pizza
To get the best approximation
And a very important question is going to be how do we Define best
Once we found that best approximation
Wilco Optimus Prime and his he just off
Then we can
Approximate the expected value of a function fire that we are interested in by the expected value
Right. See the big picture you can think of this is getting away from introducing random numbers it would
Message reset Opie's difficult but let's use some random numbers and some clever ideas and jump around index
Space in some way and you might have thought why do I need to have extra random numbers in addition to
To the date of that I've gathered for my infant's problem it doesn't seem logical to need
Random numbers to
Answer my inference question
Answer variational method or an approach that says yes actually need random numbers
You can do this instead
Well
Whether it works well is is an open question
How we do this
So we need an objective function that measures how close Q is to pee
And
This various ideas for how to measure closeness of distributions to each other
To that we have already come across the cool white lie blood divergences between p and Q which you can ride
Like two different ways right so you can have the average on the Q of log2 of a p
Vlog beer with you and these are both measures of distance between p and Q
That have the property that when
Pnqi equal becomes I-30
And it can't get any smaller than that minimized if you cannot sleep perfectly matched
No we must remember that the extra talking about is a very high dimensional thing so these sums of x
That we have hair
Not necessarily easy to do I'm able to go we already agreed that P is difficult we come
Accurately
Represent averages
I'm for example for somebody who acts of 5x * 10x is a difficult thing so why should we think that we can
Can do anything with these
These K else
Before I
Continue with that thought let's just look at an example so you understand how these Kayo's work
A very very simple nasty read distribution which is non-uniform it's got a photo
Probability
Discrete functions
I'm in a spaceship and Q is a simpler distribution which is uniform across wrong
Opal prices
I would like you to
Quickly work out and discuss with each other
What's the
Kuba Kuba Divergence
Each way around so if you workout first one and the second one which of them is biggest and roughly how big are they
Please
Talk to you later.
Okay
Let's have some votes ISO On the Border
QP first and then PQ second
So
Let's have votes for which one is bigger
Is the first one bigger or is it smaller
Or do you not know if I swear I don't know I haven't had enough time
Okay
Votes for the first one is bigger than the second
Lots of folks that voted for its Moore ok
That is correct Sir William
I'll bring them in Delaware around for no particular reason healthy
Distance
Measure this way around
Is about log 4/3
Whereas if you have q on the outside Q goes in Columbus in and puts foot of its probability Macon
Play swipeys has no way that's Tonya Tonya probability and it gets strongly penalized for there in that
So
When you talk up
When you talk to your lucky repeat you got this one over at Salon which is very large
And
Bad news if you like if this is your measure of closeness and not says cute
Here is a very long way from p
I'll put quotes on that kiss is it bad news
Depends on what we're trying to do
But
At least big
So something to be aware of if we use this source of objective function
Is if p is a complicated thing
Sorry
Complicated
Thing that in some places goes to zero and if we approximated by
A green thing
That is none 0 in places where p
Is actually zero or very very close to zero
This will be deemed a bad approximation
You got a very strong penalty
So if we optimize this
Objective function
The sort of thing you might expect to have happened
In this case would be that the green thing says I mustn't put a foot wrong
I'll make sure
Put any mass in places where p is 0 so you'll end up with a proximation that look
Like this
That's the sort of thing that happens
If you use
Some cute
Slug
2 / 30
On the other hand if you use something with Q as your objective function
Then
It's the other way around that you don't want to make the mistake of
Failing to put
Mass in the place where I pee has got Max and so if you use
This objective
Assuming you could compute it
This would lead to you
Taking a message of solution like this and maybe approximating it was something extremely broilers to make sure you kept it a little
Little blips
Okay
So it's good to understand injective functions we're talking about
No
The first one
Summerfield p over Q
Involves
Plumbing
Immoderately nasty thing
Under anesthesia distribution pay let's just rewrite it
With color
I have a stomach relaxer p
Log
Kiev
I'm giving that finding the expected value of a function on the pee is difficult it seems very unlikely that we
Going to be able to find the expected value of this function on the p
All right so even if we want to evaluate this one
It's for real song
We won't be able to evaluation
So let's give up on that straight away
And look at the other one so if we look at dkl
This involves the sum of q log Q
All of which is nice is nice and is under our control and then we have the one little bit of nastiness the red bit
His hair
And everything else is
Green or white
We could
Write this as
Assam / X
Qfx support during this time
Times the energy
Using the definition of t e of X is 8 - DMX
On that where that is an interesting number that we don't know
So if pulled out the E from here
What else do we have will have a zed please
Service log
They say of
Red LED
And then what leftover is the entropy of Q
Which alkyl HQ off apps
I can give as a greeting
Tinge
So is this hopeless as well is it impossible to evaluate this well this is the average
Of a function under Q
And maybe that is on maybe we can do it it's easy but
Brunch
So maybe that's okay
Best we would love to know
But from the point of view of adjusting to try and make this thing as small as possible
Play Slugs at adjust a constant it doesn't have any Q dependents so
We don't know this but it doesn't matter
In fact
Love I need is it not mess up but maybe by minimizing this thing we might be able to find out what it is
I'm finally this thing isn't I'll agreeing it's the entropy of a distribution q that we can control on weekends
Who is allowed to have the following form only
I maybe we can constrain Q so that we can about the right this
So for the green cake tonight
So this objective function out all of the two I've listed
It's promising maybe we can evaluate it
And if we rearrange it's on the board
And focus on the two tons of ticks
So this one here
And this one here
We can define an objective function that's made up of those two and that's what I put on the computer screen
Variation free energy
It depends on the adjustable parameters
Do and it by definition is the average of
The interesting energy function on the Keurig
Minus
Sub-Q locator
The entropy
All cute and the fisa defendants in hair is
This distribution Q
Depends on Peter Peter is a description of
How are you justice
Right on this thing has a name it's called variational free energy
And because of where this came from
And because of the fact that this thing here
Is
Positive
It is a true statement.
Astalavista
Is love a bounded by
- log Zed
So if we succeed in minimizing the variational free energy we will have also minimized
The KL between q and P and the objective function that pops out of that minimisation if we can evaluate the variational friends
Is abound unlock said so will for free be getting something interesting
Out
Okay
So the variational method to talk to you about today
Are entirely based on this objective functions there are other variation methods as well but that's all I'm going to say
Do today
So let's look at some examples now so you can see how this works
Can we evaluate its variation free energy
Well for some problems for some red energy
The answer is yes you can as long as you can straighten cue to have an appropriately simple form
So let's go through two examples
The first example dude is the good old gaussian distribution
Inference aveiro
So hopefully you remember this distribution
End
All discussions of inference problem
So the assumption is that there's a normal distribution with parameters muessigmann Squad
Indata X
We don't want to infer new and sigma
So the red distribution
Is the inference of
And the variance
And we look at that before
And if this is the new actress and if this is the sigma
Square taxes
What the nasty read distribution looks like
It's something right like that
A distribution that has the property that any slice through it in this direction
Is a normal distribution
Sorry I didn't realize very well
And all of those I'll send it on the same place in spite of what it looks like the rules sent it on Xbox
Sample me
So
My sweetheart
Okay so we'll three slices through normal distributions
I'm slices in this direction are gamma distributions
The
Maximum of the posterior
Under the assumptions that we had earlier in the course
Is out of place called
Sigma is
SEPTA Sigma an Instagram button on your calculator
However if we marginalized over all of these gamma distribution
The projection of all of those onto
The taxes
Is a gamma distribution
That has a peak
Larger value of Sigma
Cold like my last one
Okay so this is a very simple distribution
And
We're going to Pretend We're
Challenge Enough by it that we want the variational method so what we will not do is introduce
Severe reaction approximation
Where the
In fruits which is a partner Distribution on the UNC glad Haven today
It's going to be approximated by a similar distribution to
How much we want to constrain it what form so we can spray it have
Well I'm going to constrain it very little indeed I'm just going to constrain it to be
Separable distribution a function of Mew a function
About the constraints apply
And then we can ask the question now if we write down a little
I minimize it what happens
Suck his what happens
We have temporarily lost on display
So that's the red distribution that's an accurate account Roblox I love it
And
If you don't kick off with any distribution to of this separable form
And then you say let's alternately update
Bermuda pendant
Function
And then the sigma dependent function
Ultimately update them and see what happens the answer is straight away when you optimize the music
Kind of warm the new dependent thing says I want to be a gaussian please
And
So you can do that and then if you update the sigma dependent one it'll say I want to be a gamma distribution
Place
Americans Aspen you depending on what you want to do now and it says of course I want to be a gas yet but he will
Changes Prime
And then you ask what you want to do so we can do this.
Alternating update approach to the optimization of that what I'm doing is
Optimizing
Acquittal the variation free energy with respect to the distribution and then with aesthetically Sigma and then
Ultimatum this right
And when you run that to convergence
You end up with
Optimize Q distribution that isn't normal
And an uprising a distribution that is a gamma
Optimized distribution
Open Mew isn't normal distribution send it on Xbox of course what else could it possibly be
But it went isn't the same as this slice through hair it's a bit faster
Optimize distribution for Sigma
Doesn't have its maximum that cigarette it's a cigarette
So this is the case where are we
Constrain the distribution to be wrong in a fairly simple way making it separable is a fairly standard
And then you end up with built-in ice distribution
Having DeSoto properties. We kind of want
It's not the case if you marginalize out knew that you got the correct posterior the true posterior
Mu student distribution is a mixture of all of those calcium soap
We haven't magically
Go around the fundamental problem the truth is it is a slightly nasty mixture of gases
Nevertheless
It's got the right sort of properties so if you ask what what's it mean what's its characteristic with
It's got the right contrast it with
Okay so that was example number one any questions about
But let
Example number two is the spin system which we've discussed on and off
In the past
So
Aspen system has couplings
J between the spins which a binary variables
Find
Open systems display all sorts of exciting properties
7sd red distribution
Is
Activate reminders
Reset science and energy
Naan bread
Notice the addition because we doing physics
All the temperature promise I will a coldness brown with a betta
Which multiplies the energy upstairs
And
It makes the Zedge Visa dependents
The way the free energy response to that
Is we shoving
Ibiza hair
And then the free energy depends both on theater
And pizza
Okay and then the free energy is always abandoned on
Zelda Peterson I can pick any betta and do the virtual free energy minimization for that
Particular problem
Okay
And the spring system is energy of X is mine
Some Avril pettus pins
XM xn
Weighted by
Jmn
And then the maybe local Fields applying for each of the things
Libras and The Exodus live in
-1 + 1
The power and so the ex lives on the corners of a
Hypercube
And the reason this is a nasty problem is because of this system had the fact that
That all couplings between pass pints is what makes it a nasty red thing
If only it were the case that we didn't have these coupling tons then it would be a simple distribution
Dinasty this just says the energy is a sum of x one free Spin and that means when you
How to be independent from each other if we only had this time
Play wouldn't it be nice if the distribution look like that
Not much like saying well let's go ahead and declare our proximation distribution
Doobie simple let's declare it have the form
Cube root of x is a normalized version of Eataly
Come over and a and
Xn
So now in this approximation distribution each of the spins has just got its own personal applied field that favors
Being up or down depending on me
Sign of a n
So this is a distribution and very easy to work with
Just emphasize that is separable I can write this is a product from 1 to end all of an individual
Distribution for the nth spin alone
Just like a moment ago we said let's pretend the distribution of mu and sigma squared
Get support to make it by separable
A product of distributions
So the parameters in this case all these ANS this is
The thing I was generally calling feature is the set of all of these
Hey ants
And just write this one of the weight
This is Ethan Ethan
Suck because it's a separable distribution it's easy to evaluate its entropy
And it's not
AAA office but we can
Easily evaluate the expected value of the energy even though the energy couplings in it
Let's go to the screen now to
Talk through this
The screen shows the approximate distribution in green on the second equation
What's that equation right side Beach astrallana colors old green and red so we can keep track of what what
And you see
We're going to simple entropy that's just the enthalpy of acceptable distribution so that right-hand green time is easy
Barely nastiness comes in the from the Reds terms
Why we look at the average value of the couplings
Under the distribution Q
So we not go down
To the next equation in parentheses who got the expected value of the energy
And
To get the coupling
Tums contribution we just need to know that some over Willamette Dental of jmn times
The average value of x Bar M
Average value of x Bar n
Because two is separable
That
Simpleset is true
So now all you need to know to evaluate the energy is well what's the mean value if each of the spins
On the Q
Right
American
Pop-up all of your ends grad contributions reach of it
So we can evaluate the variational free energy
And when you look at this and you say how do I adjust it with respect to fisa remember these are here is the second
Biases a
For the individual spins
And what effect do those have will they change what the probability of a spin being up
Which changes the mean value of that Spencer Q in hair
Is my name for the probability of one of those things being up the end spending up and X bar and
Is the mean value of the spin
They are truly related to each other
Strong and rough
So
Is
Cure for being a mistake plus one
His cue for being in the State minus 1
And
X
Is just the sum of Q + 1
+ -1 * 3 - 1
So xbar is linearly related to
The Q
Florida gun packing right pieces
Minus
Which is
Too cute
French
Okay
So the adjustable promises are a 4q or Xbox
Ways of describing what we're going to do just if you minimize with respect to that set of an adjustable thing
The end degrees of freedom The Cure
You find that the optimum satisfies these two equations which you can again sold by its rating them
The first equation says
That you can work out a by looking at all the main states of your neighbors so if you are the
Spin
You going to look
All your neighbors stations I want to assure you you talk a lot and that tells you what you
Will a should be
And then your a is related to your Xbox through Xbox stench of a
Yet another relationship I could have written down as of this time
Ham comes from having an Easter + 1 + 8 + -1
Consciousness comes from
Okay
So I didn't want to Labour through the derivation of this on on the board it's all in the book if you want to
Look at it will Catholic
What Gabriel message
We can take a recently Nestea distribution that has properties
We can approximated by separable distribution
Then we can minimize the variation free energy update equations look like this
Your local average field
From your neighbors and set yourself into a state that spits out your your average response to that
Applied trailer
When you got oil spins to do that
And
If you it's right those equations you got to a minimum of the reaction free energy let's do this no
An example of a tooth pain
System
So on the board I'll just talk through
I was to spend systemworks
Okay
So here is the incredibly nasty distribution
The spin system has two spins X1 and X2
I need two of them is a mistake + -1
The energy is minus
X1
X x x
All right
That's it
The connection to what we've just been doing is it's the spin system with just two spins x y and x 2
I know a couple with a coupling of strength J that is equal to 1
Prince princesses don't get much simpler than this
Sobe variational free energy
Repeating the derivation we're just being through so that General pay civilians men's is Vita X
X1 X2
- 151 - Santa Fe
To Tunisia entropies base
Okay
What's the equation what does this actually look like let's just drawer it's a space with X1 being - 1
Next to being
- 101 the real distribution assuming J is positive
Favors them both being in the same state with each other so the real distribution red
Has
Maybe a bit more mass
+ 1 + 1 + -1 - 1
On the elf Agonist that's the real distribution is nasty and complicated
Umbrella
Coping with this terrible complexity of this nasty thing
Which athlete in treats just requires two numbers to describe it how much must have and how much is that
Approximation distribution by green thing and the green thing says oh I want to separate
Approximation please song going to have a Q Wang
That puts a mask on
SMS on maybe a few to the put some nice on here
I'm here I'm just too adjustable promises which is
What's the bias of q1 and Q2
And if you multiply together Accu distribution. For example could put more weight on plus one
But each of them
Came up by those two with by each other then the Q distribution you'll end up with will put most of its mass on this corner
A very small amount on this corner and a middling amount on this one
You with me
And with free to wander around in to Wong
Cuties face
Wacky Wong is say the value of this thing
How much mass is getting on + 1/2 + Q2 is how much mass does the Second Spin
It's being in the first one
And as we wander around in q1 and Q2 weekend flaws
The variation of free energy
And I will now
Do that for you
And I'm doing this as we bury betta so
The sequence of plots
Starting with b to very small which means high temperature
I'm going to Lodge between is very cold temperatures
Dog got to a vehicle temperature betta is now to
And you can see what the free energy looks like and the answer is
That it's got
Two Minima
These two axes are q1 Q2 I'm going exactly the same function twice over but different views into the clinic
Monkeys with the Contours projected onto the base on the right hand side
So hopefully can see what's going off
Suck
What's happening
Jaivita which means
High coldness or low temperature
The free energy
Adult Minnie Mouse
Hair
Pentair
So that's when the teacher is to
At The Other Extreme
Let's go back again
Lights on please
I'm halfway here and I'll grab it further
Cut his the high temperature and the things so they can beat it down to four
I receive that
The minimum of Today Show free energy
Its hair
All right
And as we go between those two extremes
SeaTac going from Mill Point Pool
Optive to there's a place where a transition
Happens in
Looks like
Ready 3 2 1
Well that's aggravate Contour Abyss
Alright one more time
Don't say it again
Sorry start with a single minimum and then beats are equals one the Figure 8
We have to minimize
All right coming back down
As a figure of 8 and it vanishes Vera Beecher equals 1
Okay
So if I summarize where the minima by showing the value of both
Q1 and Q2
On this access and I'll put a star on it
At 3
High temperature
The optimum
Is
At
Do you want Auntie to both equal to 1/2
And then the transition happens when Beach was one
I got his pop
And then we have something like this have a choice you can go either way to the top or the bottom left
Minimum
What do you think of that
Some people
Get distracted by the concept of
Chinese transitions
And whenever they see a bifurcation a transition from Vallejo
And I think that's a
Mistaken way of responding to the world
The truth is we're trying to approximate this red distribution as we change the temperature
Between very high temperatures
At high temperatures the distribution looks like this and you can hardly see
That these two guys have a little bit
And a very low temperatures
You end up with a well that looks like this
With all the masks on the diagonal and vertical
I thought you go
Through different bodies of Beka from this world of high temperature today supposed low temperature
The true red system doesn't have a phase transition it just its distribution just changes from being missed
Is completely continuous
And the fact that this approximation that we've introduced
Has a transition it has a bifurcation
Shouldn't I think vehicles for excitement is I always not wonderful that it's not a phase transition is no
Bifurcation
And it happens to happen at a temperature of wall which might look a bit like this
What is a transition
From
Insisting on the approximation distributions it look a bit like this by saying while I'm just going to buy a uniform
And then once you get above that point then it goes but it says I'm going to approximation distribution that looks rather like this
By that distribution that puts almost over Macon hair and little bit on hair little bit on hair
I'm almost nothing at all
So I feel fairly sanguine about whether this is a useful approximation or not it's mathematically
Nice and it's good to be familiar with it because it's something crops up a lot
But I'd like to emphasise but real system and read it doesn't have a phase transition and this transition that the green system has
Compass point hair
Yes it's a bifurcation
But it's not a phase transition a phase transition is a much more interesting phenomenon where the various
The energy diverges and all sorts of exciting phenomena occur
Now we could go through another example which is
This pain system with a coupling between lots of Neighbors
And if a couple and girl identical
If they're all equal to say plus one between Aspen and its neighbors and it has been said the same number of Neighbors
Then actually reaches down the entire calculation hair
It comes out exactly the same there any change would be if you've got to neighbors then you put a 2in hair if you don't fool Neighbors
The factory floor in half of this whole calculation we're just going through that we're just telling you what
What will happen first system with n spins as well
I'm missing that just emphasize it the real in the real world
Welchol available in the world of systems with lots and lots of things were then spins
Wet and is very large you can get phase Transitions and the ising model for example is a cyst
Where are you couple to go full Neighbors
And the icing mobile as we saw the last time does have a phase transition
This is what happens when you use the variational method to approximate it I just emphasized the what has happened was not
And it didn't happen because the underlying system had a face from the very should be very skeptical about people who say oh look at my
Variational method applied to the ice T-Mobile and look at how the phase transition because it hasn't
Okay
Why am I saying a list well I think there's a
This Methodist variational method
It's quite widely used to name and this is a question for a physicist
In the audience in these equations before
Down again the equations that I drive for the general spin system
And what we've gone through here is a special case where all the days are equal to a single number
Have you seen these equations before and what was it called yes
It's cold mean field Theory with all the mean field approximation
And often when it's derived people I'm not clear on the derivation it's just well let's do this
Take the mean of this if your luck it may be well explain but
The first time I encountered mean field Theory
It just seemed like a a sequence of arbitrary
Approximation
It also goes by various other names at sometime Schuylkill device Theory at least in the Cambridge
Thermodynamics course
And occasionally you may have people calling about talk about the fireman trick Caswell
All the fun run
Approximation
So these are all names for the same thing and what I've shown your hair is
Derivation of mean field Theory
By writing down a variational free energy
And then minimizing it
I like this way of deriving mean field Theory because it's very clear what the objective function is it clear what you're doing
And it don't motivate other generalizations so just to finish this little 7
Why do I like
The variational free energy review
All Mint Hill Perry
I love it
Because it's going to clear objective function from which you can derive
The equations
So that's nice cuz maybe you need to memorize less you just memorize objective function and everything can be
It is generalizable you could in principle shoes
More complex approximating distributions cute
And then you could
Generalize your
Flash on message
As long as you can evaluate and optimize
Petrol
And the third reason for loving this beauty is it shows that when you do mean field Theory you are actually getting a biome
On that
That shows that these mean field methods
Give
Abound
I'm glad which is an interesting thing to be able to compute
Okay that's
Mean field Theory not variational methods
And that is the end of the lecture
My plan is the next lecture will be an introduction to neural networks
And then
Will probably spend to lectures on neural networks and maybe the second lecture also wrap up for a little discussion of State
Erich fend coats
All there any questions on
Dyslexia
Okay thanks so much