Coming last time we discussed reliable communication over unreliable channels
I know I did want that we were taking noisy channels and imagining
Fixing up those unreliable channels by putting in and coding system in front of a decoding system
After the channel
And
We discussed
A toy example of a noisy Channel 92 binary symmetric Channel which flips a fraction f
And we discussed a couple of simple ways of encoding a couple of simple ways of adding redundancy
Maybe repetition codes on Van the 7400 code which is a more sophisticated way
Finding redundancy
And we discussed how to decode both and so the ideas Demco deciding redundancy and then
Dakota is using inference to try and figure out what happened and cleanup fiera's
Allergies to to result that we will prove in due course which is adding one of the most room
Century maybe Shannon's noisy Channel coding theorem which says that
If you add redundancy in a cunning way you don't actually need to add very much redundancy
To be able to achieve arbitrarily low-probability Avera so for the
Funniest metric channel that slipping 10% of the bits the boundary between achievable and nanachi food places
I'm on this diagram of right and final error probability
Great see the capacity which is about 0.53 I'm not saying you only need two
Use a rate 1/2 kojo need to 100% redundancy
And then you can have a smaller probability that you want so that's amazing I will prove it in a few
Adjust time
The first let's discuss where this fits into the the big picture
Real data sources are usually redundant themselves so this picture that I
Richard you last time we take this awesome we add some redundancy
May not be quite the right thing to do if the source we started with already have some redundancy
Sorry for example in English text if what we're compressing is English vowels and consonants
With particular frequency to talk on text dependent or not something that we could learn about and exploit
And let me show you an example of this here's a piece of English with Progressive
Simply increasing fractions of a raised and volunteer projects could help us
Read this and if anyone can read it successfully so we can cope with severe Asia
Evidence of the original text had redundancy in it so some Jane Austen
Navigate reading it for us
Condom shopping
Musicians Unite
Nearly 20 years in the world with very little
She was the youngest of the two daughters of a
Most affectionate Belgian father and head
Mistress of this house
Very early.
Her mother had died too long ago for her
Do you have
Decimated thank you so
Raise your rates go up to that about one-third of the Conchas are racing this row so
Very early. Her mother had died too long ago for her to have more than on
Indistinct remembrance of her caresses
Aunt
And I was getting a bit hot is an illustration just using a human expert
The redundancy that you can cope with some arrays it's a rule English text has redundancy so how did
Fit in the the big picture
Oops
Here's the correct decoding
Oh well then
The big picture
In a standard Communication System what we want to do is exploit that redundancies already exists
In a real sore and get rid of it and shrink the file so we can press it first and making ID
He lies to us that we can then put into the channel coding method that we're discussing last time I had the right sort of her.
Tennessee for the channel and coda
I thought we discussed last time but we're going to wrap that whole thing inside a compressor and then an uncompressed
So going to provide data compression and will spend a few lectures on this topic the conventional way of
Doing things it's not essential that you have to do Channel coding those are upside down
Ignore ignore it should say
Swift coding
So how about compressor
Uncompressed
And then we'll have the channel code Bianco.
That's designed. The rights of redundancy telecommunicator to the noisy Channel
Atlanta how to decode up a channel as long as that does a perfect job then
Which have what's coming out of
So that's the game plan
So we call list so coding or data compression and we want to understand how to do that
In order to discuss compression
It may be helpful to think about idealized sources of redundant
Data so I can think about confessing things at the idealized and simple and the fish
Best example and go to talk about is the bent coin
And been calling is going to have an outcome and who can forget looked around comes
The outcome lived in an alphabet and the alphabet has to
Characters in it wonderful Tales Uncle Ted's and the probabilities
All those two outcomes
Nuggets in San Mateo and a 10% chance
Of a hat
And my notation is alcool a random variable
X
On the provisional actiontiles is 0.9 the notation I use in the
Facebook
4 random variables
Answer the question we want to ask about this redundant source is redundant because
We want to understand better if we get
File made up of say 1000 outcomes from this source
So we talked about going to passing times
How much information
Does that string of outcomes half and
How should we go about compressing that string of outcomes
And finally
What is the smallest possible compressed file size that we should be aiming for
I would like to answer this question for any
Random variable is just a simple example in general I'll use this notation
I'm on some bull which will have a capital f x
Three things it's a random variable and alphabet on the pole roof
Fusion
A random variable which I'll share with a load
Pace weather
A set of possible outcomes
Electrical the alphabet A1 A2 A3
Hey I will rise the number of the alphabet
A set of probabilities
B complex made up of P1 P2
K i
The probability that X is a
I understand the perversities have the properties of them
And the Republic was there a
So that's
A general sort of random outcomes in which the band coin is one example
And
We're going to discuss
I've been calling and some other examples
And as we discussed the motor to examine explain this is Shannon's claim
That's the right way to measure information content and the right way
To say how much should we expect to go to compress things is as follows
We're going to define a thing called the Shannon information content
The sound information compound open outcome
They're all talk about just a single outcome for this General ensemble
Why we get the random variable and send that to be the son information content
Is it tolls
To run over the probability
And we measure that in bits
Okay love will never fade Simon says that's the right way
Dementia information content when something happens you can say I have gained wrist motion
Summation that measure of information content by looking at the probability
Log 1 over it what does that look like so if you tell me what the probability of your
The outcome was P Shannon is same
Is biggest for the really improbable outcomes
I'm small list the things that was sitting about in fact if something was definitely going to happen if a
Zero information content if it has a probability of 1/2
Information content of one b****
If something happens that has a progressive 0.9
Like for example getting a tail from a coin
Fat Scott
That's kind of information content of Love vase to 107.9 which is now
Northpoint 15 so Shannon says whenever you got a telephone event calling you've gained 15
Hundreds events
We got Love by to want over there
Bits which is 3.3
Fix
Okay so he says every had everyone in this file on the screen
Three and a bit bits of information content
So he's cleaning this is the right way to measure information content it's the compressed file
Length that we should aspire to someone we invent compression systems
H
All facts is
Chicken breast
Find the lengths to which we should aspire
Okay so that Shannon's playing and I'll carry on Cooling
The Shannon information content until you're convinced of that and then I'll stop
I noticed the information content because it really is the right way to measure
Information
Okay let's not give ourselves
What should we do
Let's just make some observations about the
Shannon information content
Notice
Front wall
The Shannon information content is additive
For independent random variables
Okay
At your asking
What do I mean by this okay this was really short on for an outcome so I put it on
Clash of the said H equals something
I'll try and be fairly familiar with notation but if you get two broke down in
Innovation that it's no fun anymore so I hope that will clear enough without being too
Okay suck
This mission content information content is additive for independent random variables
For example if I ask why
Come from a single girl is a pair of random variables x y
What's the probability distribution for X Y is p of x x t r y
For all apps on Weinbach the definition of independent
Temperature Townsend content of the Ryman
Umberto's take your own particular values and I'll use a short time until age of X and Y that means the outcome
Whatever exes and why being whatever it is is love ways to want over the phone
Palessi
Hope
Outcome which is low base 2
Plus no pictures by substituting
Independent property in half and using the way loved what
A cat
So for example if I get time I've been calling on.
That acts and if Y is open the door and find out if it's raining or not
And I tell you the past that's why I tell you stay to be calling on whether it's raining
32 variables that you probably believe are independent on this so it makes sense that the amount of information
And I'm getting you if I tell you that I'm single famously
Title. It's not raining
Is the same as the information you would have got it separately I told you about one random variable and the other one
Bible which already skipped over that
Is that the information content Shannon information content is biggest for improbable outcomes
Okay let's not Define
Another quantity
You have improved this is the right way to measure information yet we'll get some examples in about 1
But let's just assume it is
I'm looking for him then to find another another quantity which is going to be
Pickled the entropy this is a property of neon
What is the average Shannon
Information content
I'm going to like it like this Consul h x
We got it by summing over all possible values of the random variable x p of x
Log base 2 x
And like the X Nation content with cool the units is measured in
Bits
Okay
So
Let's have a think about an example to think about these assertions that this is a good. Goodbye
These qualities are sensible connotation let's look
Dwayne from which I gave you last time to think about and
Let's think about
Strategies for solving the waiting problem so please turn to your neighbor now
Have a chat about your solutions to the weighing problem
Okay so the goal is given
12 one of which is known to be a heavy or light
Can use this balance as few times as possible and guarantee that we're going to find the old Bull and others have you alive
So who's got a strategy that will do.
Solving this problem
I want you to answer this question my methods needs at most how many Wayans have
I think about your method if you are sure that after you use the balance seven times then definitely you will have
Guarantee you would have identified double then please answer 7 Etc
Hands up if your method is at most 15 or bigger number of Wayne okay
Both
Hey Brother 7
I Can't Go For That
Apologies we had a technical glitch at this point the number of people who could
Do
Displaying problem in three rings
Was three
Well then moved onto was I asked everyone what that strategy was for the first weighing
And choices are that you can weigh six against six leaving none of the balls on the table
One-person show started first playing
Or you can have five against five leaving two on the table that wasn't
Said you could wait full bolt against for leaving for on the table 20 people chose
Both of you can have three against 306 on the table one person shows that
Two against two leaving tables on the table for One Bowl against one
Ben 10 balls on the table
How to identify the possible options as the first playing
I didn't ask the question what would be today
If you want to get the most information
On average how have your first wedding
Maybe you should put take the first weighing
Search for the outcome of that way has the biggest possible entropy
I'm up we're about to do now is go through each of those six possible cases and work out what the entropy
Is the outcome
If you choose
Two example way
Six against six masopust Casino Disco
Let's backtrack and let's imagine that we weigh six against six
Then the possible outcomes when weighing six against six
Rest
Best
Miss
So that's an alphabet probabilities of these three outcomes anyone
Hasta Raha
Okay
I'm up the entropy of that provoking distribution
Entropy is Anthony Omaha and you get warm
Let's make a little nicer that somewhere
If we do six against six
Then the first outcome is this
Wonlex
Okay
5ft 5 wasn't very popular
But if we hadn't gone with five against five
Then what's the probability that it would have balance
552 on the table
What's the probability that have come
1:6
One sec y16
Okay so
It will balance if one of these balls on the table is field goal and got two of the Bulls out of a total of 12
2/12 * which is 1/6
And by symmetry the remaining probability the shed out there any 10:12
His equally between ac512
Red high tops
Find the entropy of the outcome in this case
If we write five against five
I have worked out for you in advance is 1.48 bits
Curious that no one went for that
But
What else could we do well we could weigh four against four
If we weigh
4 against 4
Then what's the probability that it will balance
Somewhere else
15 McCants for 12 because of a balance if one of the four bowls on the table
Table is the audible
An intervening 8/12 to split
Okay so full vs 4
Gives you the entropy all
Which is log base 2 or 3 which is 1.5
5/8
If we were a three against three
Then what's the probability that
Left 6 on the table
What's the preventative Sr cam
Huh
Okay I'm sorry I must be across a chance of each of these
When you work out the entropy
You got 1/2 * 2 + 1/2 * 1
Which is 1.5
I'm so let me fill in the remaining for girls easy way to get to the Indians be as 1.25
Life bits if you a 1 against Plum and Sparrow 0.8
So something you could have done
If we believed in Shannon was just pay for these different possible
Take
Let's just go with the one that maximizes the information content and that would have sent us to
Best choice rich
Maybe after some Court
Many of you have
Erotica
Good
Alright let's go ahead and go with that choice
And so we've got some balls now which we could say I'll probably like supposed to be like those who like
Dfsr come here cuz
What should we call lease
He's a good Bulls G
Okay
So
That's one possible thing that could happen the Buffalo out, assuming away four against four
Left side goes up
Right side goes down
I will go full bolt on the table which mean I know a good bull
So if you'd like to make a suggestion let's go bunch of suggestions of what we would do next if this
Hair
Webbie outcome of a CNA
And
Let's get some suggestions what we do next
Okay
He'd like to suggest
Something
Golf
We're a walk against the other group
Okay
Okay so you could wave full Goods against
The fool possibly lights
Okay so Justin number 2
Tell tell me again what's your suggestion now
Okay
Okay let's not leave to get to all the reasoning we're going to have to work with that that's a nice suggestion about any other suggestion
Think about it
Probabilities in due course
Yeah
How many
201 lights
I'm outside and then
BMO Harris Android
A light okay
Right side in this case we're leaving on the table I possibly light and full possibly heavy dudes
Here you'll suggesting leaving both lights on the table
How long will it be
The goods
Okay
That's a nice suggestion let's now have I think about me and think about the possible
Things that could happen
Suck
If we were together this strategy as a second way
All the goods on one side and all the puppy light on the other
Then
What could happen
Could it look like that
Could that happen
Could the right hand side go down
No
Why not
So these ones are all possible allies
Are there any way that's like your go down giving it the left hand
Bulldog good is it
One of these people is
Noble I'm heavy but we already know that snow
Possible pizza guys can only be available at the light
This has probability 0
Is it possible they could balance
Hernia
It's one of the heavy heavy guys
What the probability of that being the case
Haha okay
What's the probability of
What happening
Haha
Okay
So that the probability distribution whose entropy is wrong with it
Okay let's talk through this one app
Okay
It's an isometric situation isn't it let's talk about the symmetric outcome
Havit balancing
Dakota
What you ate
Because if you'll believe on these two then it will balance
Okay
So by 7 treat the remaining probability has to be
Split between the oven.
Create
3x
For example
This could happen
This guy is y'all bull
Under the light of the normal
If one of the either of those is
Pitbull
And the heavy
Hi-Tech
So that's another
Possible action and its Provo distribution
We could
Y33 lights
What's the probability that this will
Balance
Phyllite
They cost us 550 old balls
Nobody left on the table and if any of them is killed or and it's kind of balance
What's the probability that
It will do
Vest
Turn on left and right
What's half of 5/8
I got is 3/8 and 0 is the probability of getting this
How to come here
Big house there's no way that the guys could be heavier than the good
Guys
Right so did a whole bunch of personal things we can do and every one of them is leading to a different
Probability distribution
His Wang prolifics mission
Head and
I miss long as I don't repeat that is actually a little bit less than one bit
This one has an entropy
Bigger than wombats
And I wonder if I can
What it is
I've mislaid the actual value or it
But it's actually a little bit bigger
Find 1.5
Fitz
Do you have any other suggestions of
Possible things you could do at this stage given that this was with us out come up with
Any other suggestions
Yeah
OK Google
Against
Three like I'm heavy
Set
That could balance it could
That way I could guy
This way
Right we left on the table a life dude on three possibly heavy duty
So what's the probability that it's going to balance
Temperature
Because if any of these full possibly old guys is the other guy and it's going to be
All right
What's the probability
That is all day
The right hand side down
Landslide on left side up
1/8
Because the only way that could happen
Is it available is this
Ridiculizar put in
3/8
But as yet another
Do you think this is.
The biggest entropy sofa
Will these options
So we can just
Imagine trusting Shannon if I give you
An alphabet of size I
And I asked you do you want me to up to Pi you got a free choice
All those probabilities
And your goal is to maximize
Hfx
What
Rudy Maxa
Maximizes
Banfi
I'll talk to you later
Okay
That's what math problem
What's the answer how do you maximize sum of p i
Log base 2 of Pi with respect to the probability that Caffey
What to do with B
Goats
Uniform place at all of the vehicle to Wong over
Hi
Okay so if I give you
Some cake
And I say
This cake consists of eight pieces
I need three children
And you've got to share out the cake as bad as a brother become between the three children
Cut up the pieces
What's the best way to do that you give zero
Tuan Child full pieces of Honor for $20 which is what we'll be doing here
Yeah well that's the rule if you do have to give all the cake to children
So
Is that the most beautiful way of showing the cake I know
3 to 3.
Looking quite beautiful isn't it
Long peaceful on 403 for Nova
Unknown suggested a strategy but it's a very common
Things for people to suggest that you weigh something against something that gives rise to the probabilities
42828 sets of 8
Popular thing to do and my guess would be
Quite a few of you who chose for Against full
How's your first way
Maybe you'll next that had
Hey choice of Wang
That she gives rise to this soda distribution
Should I give an example
What's an example
Maybe I should have asked for another all the tests just something
Someone suggested we just see if it was
Hhll
2 inches on one side to alchemilla
Brilliant
Santana
Okay
I'm going to slightly change your suggestion actually
Cuz I think if we put old we have even once I know the puppy lights on the other side then one outcome definitely
Lang leav if I do it
All right I'm like 2 inches in 2 hours on the table so balancing
Has a probability of
All right
And then by symmetry fill the time comes
Have a problem tablecloth reach full
I'm too for another that's very fair isn't it
How can I activate 1.5 bits
His Bonita ID
How about we trust Shannon
I wish I'd not going to do that because that has uniform and Channing says he should go for a uniform probability distribution
I think this is short-circuiting having to think huh you just say let's use the entropy
Do this
So do anyway that maximizes the entropy
This one doesn't perfectly maximize the entropy
Cuz you can't exactly got a uniform distribution when things come in 8
Personifies
Right
And if you do go ahead and do that and then use the same method your next wedding
Pick an action that still gives you
The most possible expected information
He'll be done in three ways
Side
This is our first success of using
Shannon's Hardware
I want prove it to you but feel free to go ahead and find you can find break it and put bandage on it for this
If you want you can go to this this post have you doing this
What you find is Shannon will get you that in three ways
All right
Christian death
Hi
Good sir the comment is
You could imagine a world in which you could do an experiment that tells you all about the colors of the bulls and that's irrelevant
Finding which one is the the the heavy one
And so this tragedy
Isn't necessarily going to work
Because in not so the world race I hope choose the option that gives you met some information content what you going to do
Grab one of those old televisions and switch it on instead of whole black and white stuff
Is Eagle Eye on the screen because I have a lot of information, so you're right it's going to be relevant information
I didn't this particular case the only information you can generate is relevant information
We were lucky
So
Yes
This is a strategy for solving problem puzzles like this
You really do need information about what's relevant and that's the real
Real message
Okay any other questions yes
Okay that's a very good question so you could imagine choosing a first weighing that shining says brilliant
You got lots of information from that but it got you into some sort of dead-end so have a greedy strategy
That isn't the best overall strategy because your first choice
May it be nice and informative but then you're stuck
Yes very just puzzles with I like that so
I'm not telling you to always use a greedy specialty I'm not saying always make your first measurement
It's just an interesting
This puzzle I got you that a three-ring
So a beautiful thing about information theory is it can make your life much easier just have
A well-defined objective function that can be a very helpful guide
Do what you do me right
In general problems like this can have difficulties if you go through a greedy
Strategy
So do take care
All right I never questions
Sorry
Let's now go back to our idealized
Source that we
Talked about at the beginning of coin
The Bank coin comes up heads
10% of the time
Entails 90% of the time
And
I'm going to give you a
Possible to think about
But next time
So
I could have been declining Lottery on his way to Ben Cohen Lottery which is rather like the national lottery
About to get the winning ticket instead of using a little Bulls
Android symbol that we just take a single been calling on we talk that a thousand times
So the outcome of that thousand long sequence of Tulsa is is a string
X1 X2 upto XN
I'm sorry as an example of a possible outcomes at my house earlier ones or
Know before they draw that out come by tossing the coin you kind of go to the
Lottery
Hot and buy tickets
An H Ticket available to you each ticket is a great long string of
Zeros and ones ordered
Okay so you can buy the old zeros ticket if you want
You can buy any of the truth The Impossible tickets
One once I want has decided tickets that buying
If you own the tickets
Has x on it where X is the outcome that actually happened then with a million times a billion times
Inflation
You got a million pounds
And anyone who has that ticket gets a billion times right so it's not sad you don't need to worry about sharing with
A lot of people
Sup
The question of why you think about the next time is
If a mafia boss said haha we are going to take advantage of this Lottery we're going to ensure that we get a large amount of
We're going to get a billion times
I will give you Matthew funds
You must go in by 11 tickets
To ensure that we win a billion
Which
Tickets
Would you buy so the rule from a Mafia Boss is
I have a 99% chance
Of winning
The lottery
A minimizing talk to the mafia boss cuz you don't want to rip it off
Which tickets would you buy from the ticket
Selling
Hot
Take that question one way ticket to buy your lunch at 9% chance of winning
And secondly how many tickets would you then have board
Alright please express your answer in the form 2 to the power something
So that's a task for you to do before the next lecture
And
I'd also like to mention purple homework you could be doing if
This world a course for real with your Visions on the game since I thought I would be recommending the following exercise
I hope you'll find them fun
The first exercise we would do for supervision is please invent your own error-correcting code for the
Binary symmetric Channel this is going back to the previous left turn now
Remember the binary symmetric Channel
Which looked at representing codes we looked at the Hamming code
I'd like you to invent
Another code for the binary symmetric Channel
And invented decoding algorithm for your code
And estimate the probability of era of the decoding
Encoding system that you define that
And if you don't like the binary symmetric Channel
Feel free to invent your own channel and invent a code for that channel make a problem and be creative
Come up with some solutions
I'm in the book there some more exercises wish you might want to do which I listed up that
I'm finally I'd like you to read no honey chapter one which was last week's lecture notes
But chapters 2 and full
Next time we'll look at a few more examples and we will try and RAM home
The View that the Shannon information content really is the right way to measure information content
Thanks for coming see you next week