Last time
We discussed
Inference
And information measures for a pair of Random
Fables is pear pendant
Random variables let me just recap
Those two topics
Fairly quickly
Inference
One of the examples I mentioned was the three doors
Problem where the rules of the game out of the game show host
Hides the prize behind one of the three doors at random
Player
Chooses one of the doors
For example I might choose to a Woman Soon by the Blue Cycle
Then the host promises that he will open another door
In such a way as to reveal the prize
Then the play I will be given the chance to stake for switch
On display switch to me
Get what's behind the other closed-door
In this case would be fine.
So the rules explained then play the game the player chooses a one-horse open
3 revealing nothing as promised should you sticks with towards it make no difference and last time
Budget on this everyone knows now because that you should switch
And what I want you to know is hard to answer this sort of problem in general because
Maybe people have memorized that they should switch but I still don't actually know
How to answer inference
The general rule for how to solve inference problems is right down the joint probability of everything
Then condition on what you know
And then you'll have the right answer and that that's a universal rule for solving probability problems
That have any inference element to them often when you do that when you
Write down the probability of everything then condition on some data what you'll end up doing how's a particular phone
How much is home base theorem
So in general
The Joint probability of everything can often be written as shown in the top right-hand side of the Top Line
How's the prior probability of some hypotheses which could account for the X
Turn hypothesis
And then when you condition on a particular date outcome
You got the thing on the left hand side the posterior probability
Off your hypotheses candidate
Is that joint probability
Normalized / the data that actually happened
So let's illustrate how this works for the three the three doors
We got three doors the price could be behind any of them
And in this particular situation but player has
Chosen dong before the date or is going to be which door
Does the game show host go and open so we actually know that
The positive could be he might open till 2 or he might open till 3
Papa sees that the prize is behind door 1 go to
Endur3
Federal my notation
The hypotheses are there is one two or three that prior probabilities are
Because the price could be anywhere
Now what's the likelihood what's the probability
If H is true that you got D equals 3y let's go through the the three cases if the prices
Between behind
The one then the car free choice of opening door to order three so these two days outcomes
Play likely how
Are the hosts picks the door when he has a free choice. Hahaha
So the probability of the day can being free given. Believe H is a half
Egg surprises behind door then he's obliged to open till 3
So the probability is warm of keeping 3
It surprises behind all three then he's not allowed to open.
So the probability of that happening
Is there a
So that's the probability of a data under the three hypotheses a way of thinking about doing is the price
How probable hypotheses where
Before we go
When the likelihood is is measuring how well did the results predict what actually happened and you reward
Things that predict well do that
And then you had you can work out of foot x 1/2
And we add those up together normalizing constants and adds up to
So now when we multiply those two across
We got normalize by dividing by half
2 / 1/2
I got two phones
Incidentally what is this normalizing well that's how well you would predict the dates that happened given
State of prior knowledge we don't actually know which hypothesis is true I asked you okay then
The players chosen to a warm you hung up a clue where the prize is what do you think's going to happen
Peanuts
Open is a half if you don't know where
Take away the prizes
Okay so that's what we normalized with and posterior probability is popping out
Right inside
2/3
Therefore you should switch get you a chance of winning
If you switch
Okay so that is Bayes theorem and
We will need to use that one with letting with channels as well if we have a
I want to infer what the input of a channel was
When we see the output
Unless time we Define how to measure information
For a joint Ensemble with two random variables in it so trivially we re
Able to define the joint and feed because that's just the same as interview with many with redefine the muslin
PH of Aksum
That we Define things called conditional entropy sites of x given y
Head fi given X I need to find a single the mutual information
If your right eye of X semicolon y
And
The mutual information is a measure of how much dependents that is between the two random variables
Okay so that's what we did last time and now we're going to talk about noisy channels and we're building up to
The Pinnacle of this bit of the cost which is the assertion that if you got yourself a noisy Channel
Like the binary symmetric Channel which flips the function f of the best
It is possible even though it's an unreliable going to channel to communicate reliably over that channel by the
Coming construction of an appropriate encoding and decoding scheme
Communication arbitrarily close to perfect reliability
So what we're going to do now is repeat what we did in the last batch Oregon today
For the case of noisy channels how does inference work and what are the information measures for noisy Channel
This works
Is a channel itself only to find a set of conditional probability distribution
We have to invent some input distribution then we can talk about the joint distribution of the input and the output
And we can also talk about information messages
So
Once we
Take the channel which has in green
A set of conditional distribution the probability of the output given the input
If we then
Bring along
I didn't put distribution that's under our control we can invent the info distribution is there vaccine purple you multiply those
Two together and you get to Joint distribution
With that distribution you can do in fruits
You can also compute the mutual information between the input and the output
In the way we Define last week
So that's the game plan
Throw play with channels a little bit will do some inference will compute some information measures
And then we'll talk about how that relates to be noisy Channel coding serum that says you can actually communicate reliably over these things
Let me tell you some channels
Set a favorite channel is already up there on the screen
The binary symmetric Channel
Which flips a fraction F of the bits we can represent that channel if we want
Buy a transition probability Matrix sorry I'm Matrix of conditional distributions
And I'll write it this way around with Ulta and his values of the input across the top
An alternative
Outfits
Abound
Aside
So if x is
Sarah Wong
The progressive output p01 is respectively
So that's one channel
Has another one
His one instantly is called binary because it's got two inputs into outputs it's called symmetric B cost
There is a symmetry if you interchange their own Walnut the inputs and outputs
Got the same
Channel
Here's another one it's cool binary
Eraser Channel
And this is a great toy model of another another phenomenon that happens in communication
Which is sometimes
Your message doesn't come out of the other end correctly and the receiving who's that
They still don't know what you actually sent so they have a symbol cold?
And the probability say f
Off a? Coming out
All right
Saturday
7 conditional probabilities for that Channel with my kids 4-0
Channels don't have to be symmetric you can have asymmetric channels
Lisette Channel
Islam whenever you send the zero
It's received perfectly I whenever you send a wall
Maybe got a 100 Maybe
Okay so in general set of conditional distributions is
Represented by matrix QJ given I is the probability that the output
Is element BJ and output alphabet given that the input force
I
Hindi alphabets
And I've got one more favorite example which is the noisy typewriter which is up on the screen of the noisy typewriter
Is a channel where the inputs of the
27 keys
On a typewriter but what actually comes out isn't necessarily the key that you did
It may be the one
Either side left or right there is a probability of 1/3
Each when you hit the see that you got to see a b or a d and so forth with
Circular symmetry I'm imagining a circular keyboard if you like
Text so that's the note the typewriter
And what we going to do with these channels his we're going to the first imagine that we spray some random data from
An input distribution that we got to Define into the channel
And we're going to the
As it says on the screen to find a joint ensemble
BMX X people like an X we're going to do and I'm going to compete how much information is conveyed
Let's stop
Where is the binary symmetric Channel
And
Will pick a particular time over the particular
Probability so let's say it flips 10% of its
And then
So what I mean
Okay then we need to pick an input distribution
So let's pick this
This input distribution
Probability of a 0.92 probability of a long
Can I be .1 Oregon to
Send I have been coin sequence with lots of zeros in a few ones
Into the channel
So it's praying in these bits and out of coming outputs
Why
I don't want you to assume
Then we look at a particular moment and we observe
For the output of a channel is
How many question is given this
I put
What we think the infamous
Okay please work this out what's the probability
Fat
Ex was one
How is it with Sarah please change your neighbor and
Let's workout enhancer
Okay
Time to vote
If you're still looking at sorry you can vote for the sandwiches I don't know if you want
Can a few to choose from hair
Vote for that I don't know what the probability is that X is one
Reverse
Votes for a 0.1
Votes for be
502c
Free
Look for something else
Is lost shoes from
Right through this
What's the probability that the
Water bong
The right time bass there and we need to Joint probability on the right hand side
As is normal with a sediment and looks like this you got your priorities
On the inputs and Hood
Hyundai minivan normalizing constant which is the probability that you see the
Data that you've actually seen and that's a song over all possible values of a
X
All the things we have upset the normalizing constant given
PAX Prime
VFX Prime
Sir
I need the probability of
If you put a woman chance of getting a woman out the answer to that his point nine because the flip is Tempest
Send .9
The lights hit the prior probability of having a Wong
Is there is no point one
100 / the normalizing constant which is the sum of all the times roll a different X4
Donations of what we saw by the first exclamation we got swept out is that
It was a warm and it didn't get flipped but the other explanation is it wasn't too warm
And it did Netflix
And the probability of it
Not being alone
8.9
The probability of it
Being flipped is .1 I just said
And made sense
Any questions or eclair
So these are the two 2 explanations
When you talk them up
We can make a note of what the program that have a y equaling warm is
Which is not .1
Thanks
And it just happens when we looking at but it will consoles have a nice day we get off
So the correct answer
There's a huff
Any questions
If we observe the output why
Is 0 instead
Then
What's the probability that x equals 1
I don't want to
How's it guess what the answer to this is
If you see a zero the chance to Texas Bon
Just like us
Huff
An advance on Hoffner
What do you think
Muffler
Yeah less than Point Mall
Set upstairs
All the prior probability of getting a
The probability of a flip happening
Stop says we have point 19.1
Probably about one being put in his only 10%
His 10% then downstairs
We have
That
Plus
The other way
Getting
Azera out
Which is what was put in
Wasn't there I didn't get flipped
So that's .9 spread fishes .81
Find the probability of seeing white cuz there is no
How about we go upstairs is 1 what week is 8200
Swan
Nova
Okay
So we find out
Two interesting things along the way
Weave
Workout for each of these cases
Not only what the probability of the input is now that we've seen the output how long the way
What the probability
I'm guessing that
Output Wieck was wrong
It's all the publicity cutting like was there something wrong
8218 has to be the case
Today's episode of fantasy checks you can apply if your account
DeSoto questions
Very good we've done inference
And in this particular case if you see a zero coming out it's very unlikely the input walls
I want
No having done inference
We are very well equipped
To talk about information messages
So we can for example ask a question in General on average given this
Functions that we just chose that for the channel and the input distribution
How much information
Does the input convey about the output or actually more interesting around how much
Information that the output convey about the input
That we're interested in how much information is conveyed
How about
Input
Bye
The output
Mutual information and it is x - 8y
And it also is a y - 8
Why give an ex
Pictures of slightly remarkable
I got to see what this one is saying is the amount of information you gain on average is how much information
Text had
Intrinsically without knowing output
- how much information can it is still has when you have seen them
Okay
A message saying you can do it the other way around you can just ask what's the information content of the output
And how much information does the output still have
If you know the input
Whenever you want to compute the mutual information for a channel you're free to do it either way
But that it is that quite often
This way of doing the calculation is a little bit easier found this way
Play less
What
Not always nice
But
Let's do it both ways so you can see what I mean
So they're the first way
Set to do the first way we need to
Which way am I doing it
My notes didn't do the easy way first we need to know
The entropy of lie
What's the probability of Y
It
.82
.18 and that was a fairly easy thing to to workout and it's also easy to work out
Epic property distribution
We're on foot
Stop
Hrvy is
H2O .18 this is a binary entropy function
Which be defined in the first electric
No
If you know
The input of a channel
Now what the entropy of lie
Well
Eva
It's Anthony this distribution
The Centre of this distribution
And those distributions both have the same niche because each other so the average of
And the entropy of this one it doesn't matter
We see this
Damsa is Christian faith of
Divine Right theory of s
Is Enfield output
Give an ex
Okay
So now we just
Look up Viner enfps
Maybe for the sake of the record or justifying what function is again
So we float back into our
How can I tell if we got these two numbers out where is no point one
Track
Andrew. 0 point
Bon
Pets
So that was
Fairly painless we just have to work out and not for distribution
And then
The conditional entropy of the output given the input was a very easy thing to write down
We can also do the calculation the other way around
And my judgment is it slightly harder book to do this one
We have to stop by working out
Diviners fee 4.1
Ancient
And then this one you do have to work out all the terms
This entry
Input given output is the sum over all possible output waited by have trouble with his that you got that
Then what is the entry of the input for that particular value
The Outpost
That we need to talk up
All of those possibilities
Does .18 chance that the output might
B
The first one we can say this name Lee yeah I put might be one
Bottom brackets
And then in that case the entropy of the input giving why is the entropy of this distribution 50/50
Terminate Divine rent fee of the 50/50 distribution
Then to finish off this calculation here
We need the 82% chance
That the output will actually be
Multiplying diviner entropy
All
The probability of the input given that the output is why we work.
That is not probability distribution is 182
81-82
Alright so now we go Presley Presley with the calculator look out by 9 p.m. off the Bunny Ranch.
182 I'm already have to work out this phone right now so that's three minor injuries which is a bit of a fast
Plus we have to do Bayes theorem to get this number I might have to do bass tournament you got this number
So that's why it feels like a bit more work we do last week at Point full 7 -
.26
Which is
What you want
How does old measured in bits and that's the same answer
As it
Should be
Okay
So what are we done we introduced the channel we pick our own input distribution pay it was completely
We could have picked anything
And then we worked out
The mutual information between the input and the output
Of the channel
And we had a completely free choice of the input distribution and what we just went through was
Special case
Fat
The probability of x
Equaling Wong
Walls
.1
Handful that special case here we have worked out
Putnam Mutual affection walls
I'll punch you want
And we could have picked any input distribution anything between 0
Moana
And we can repeat the whole calculation we just did
Broly
Housing value stab between so please do that now
Okay are you done
So when you complete the cuff
You got something looks like this
If you always put zeros into the channel then the
Output doesn't convey anything about the input anymore
If you always put in ones
Holset
It conveys
Information
It's a symmetric channel so this code must be symmetric and it's going up so it's going to have a maximum somewhere
Should I just catch
By symmetry the maximum and you can prove that has a homework
Exercise if you are
Skeptically inclined
Suck
What you going to do with this now
Hippie idea
We're going to introduce the definition
We had a free choice of this input distribution I didn't label axis of x equals 1
I did leg lifts my wife
Okay
We got a free choice of the input distribution
Something we could do is we could hunt around in the space of all possible input distribution
For the one that maximizes the mutual information wouldn't that be an interesting thing to do because then
Sucks that you have maximum
You took summation between input and output
So well then Define the thing that we get from that
To be the capacity of the channel
If I don't give you a channel you can say the capacity of that channel Q is the
Maximum overall possible input distributions PX
Alstom Eastlink Nation between the input
And the output
And the distribution does the chief this maximum is called the optimal input
Distribution
Set a timer
For example
For the binary symmetric Channel
With a flip probability app
Appoint Wong
Helpful input distribution
Is
Hahaha
Buy Cemetery
Or if you don't believe symmetry arguments let me prove it to you
Suck what is the mutual information for any choice of input distribution
I'll introduce a variable P1 which is the probability of picking warm as
Input distribution
As I bury the number P1 what happens to Mutual information wow we need
I said the easy way
We need the entropy of Y
We need the entropy of line given X
So we need the Envy of what's the probability that the outfit will be one well
Guess it by putting in a woman having a
Slipknot happen
You can get it by putting in a knot
H2O that lost
This is sorry I'm working at the age of Y -8
All
Why give an ex the second time is
What's entropy of Y given X will it doesn't matter what the input distribution is the entropy of Y if you know the input is always
Kevin Durant free
I can't answer that
The answer that something we just sketched and now you sketch this
And you put your proof
Okay it's not the complete proof
You can prove it it's in the book as well
When you maximize this
What you got is what the capacity of the finest metric Channel
Where the flip probability of f- H2
Of f
Okay what's the biggest value of the binary entropy function can possibly have
The biggest failure can have is Wong
H2O Banks his axe
Space between
The biggest failure can have his it's a chief when the argument in hair
Heather Hoff
QED the biggest the biggest Mutual information you can have is 1 - 8
Some people
I need a cheap that by making sure the argument are the Hof
And
Indy setting P1 equal to 1/2 does not for you
So what we works out
Is
The capacity
All the binary symmetric Channel
For the flight from
I'm not what we want to do next is exploring this idea what is the capacity of a channel
But the real goal is to prove that this capacity
Actually measures how fast you can reliably communicate
Over-the-counter medicine amazingly profound results that will get that by the end of the next lecture
So where were heading is waterproof Shannon's noisy Channel coding theory which says that
Reliable that is virtually error-free communication is possible over this channel
Heart rates up to
At any rate up to the capacity
Off the channel
Okay
So let's do a few more examples
And then next time we will
Indicate how to prove
Esterom
So for the binary symmetric Timeless and also to lobbyists that you can communicate reliably at this right
If we're talking about the Channel with a flip probability of
Traffic report no .1
And this capacity is roughly 0.53
So that the assertion in the steering is that you can take
Lousy destroys it flipped empcenter the best
Combine two of them together in a coming way
And you can achieve that you can emulate
A perfect
Single disk drive using the two lousy distress
So that's not obvious let's look at some other example channels where maybe it's a little bit more
Weather this theorem is correct
So let's start by looking at
A Channel with 4 inputs
Before outputs
Which has this
Set of conditional probabilities
Please work out what the capacity of this channel is
And then when you're done. See if you can invent an encoding and decoding method to communicate that not right
Original
Okay what is the optimal input distribution first
Hello
Uniform distribution
Seems reasonable gas by Cemetery
And what the capacity if you use
Fat input distribution
Two bits
So where does that come from well we can run it on either way and to be off
Output - entry lamp given inputs for example
If you use this input distribution the output distribution is also uniform
The Envy of the uniform distribution
Is
Two bits because it's
Look for
And if you know what the input is the entropy of output
Is 0 because it's a certain distribution
Can we communicate reliably with this channel
Yes because you could
Take someone who's going to lay the bits and you can say every time you get 00010
411 respectively for the next two bits and turn them into ABC's and he's in there and then use
Coming back again
A cut that's a trivial case
Let's now
Mention two more cases
Which will do
In the next lecture
Sebastian High School Veterinary confusion Channel
And
If you put in
ASU
Will you put in sees you cannot answer that you put in these you got
Random Moon
A cat
So where we heading with this task
His we want to know what's the optimal input distribution but the start with let me ask you if you put in a third of those
Now
What's the nutrition information
So have a chance your neighbor
And look at an answer for that and then if you
If you've done the first questions
The next question is what the helpful input distribution and what capacity
So when I say what's a tax obviously answers you're not sure what I'm really asking is what
What is the probability distribution of x given that information
Okay
Answer to this first question what is
Access streaming
Simple distribution and assuming that you see an output
Y equals m
What's the probability distribution of x
Any guesses or answers
No
What could X be
Christian
It could be a or b
Are they equally likely
Let me give you a hint
Okay
This is called a
Chris coetzee
The way the channel looks physical be
Okay
When you pick it in foot
You pick a card you pick one of the three times at uboc
And then it got plops down on the table at random
Am I going to swamp all this phone
All this one
And what the output is m o n is
Is it white or is it brown
Okay
Senna
If u c y equals n which means you see
Wise
What's the probability that the input was the old white count
I was supposed to say
But it was be the double-sided car
Annual
It's going to be
2/3 1/3
Vera
If you had last week then this was all familiar
Okay
So two guys once I was there
And what is the meatloaf mation please turn to your neighbor and
What passage
Okay
What's the meatloaf Nation assuming this input distribution his five things we should choose from or
Omega is something else is I've not written down
Are you ready
Votes for option A
Lug
Base 2 of 3
Minus the vitamin B12
Did I say that
Boats that 1-2 feta cheese 2/3
K12
Votes for a luxury - of head
Biloxi - Wang
1/2 - 1/3
For something else
I should have asked for that first
Okay
Right sorry I didn't give you a quite long enough that
So probably I should have left you a little bit longer cuz the interesting thing is
Typically if you have a careful audience about half of the people vote for a day and a half of the people
Because both of these are correct
And you get each of them budging the constellation the two different possible ways around so you can either say what the entropy
The input distribution Lottery and then
Find distribution whichever thing happen that's a very quick
4/8 -
The Bunny Ranch Riverside
Thanks for this is correct
But it's also true you can about this way you can send me the output
So if I pick a card and show you
The face
What the prophecy between black or white brown or white
That's
1 bit 50/50
And what's the entropy of the output if you know the input
If you know the input now you have to some over all the possible cases does Longford Champs
That you certainly got the output and so a certain distribution has no entropy
Results of a 1/3 chance
That you pick a c and have a such an n
Which has no entropy
And does a 1/3 chance
That you pick
The brown and white cars
How does a 50-50 chance you'll see Brian White romantically of that distribution
Is one bit
Which gets here
1 - 1/3
Which is correct
Supposed to be Santa's alright and it's nothing Philadelphia's but these two mathematical quantities are equal to each other
Okay
Sun
The next question is
What's the capacity
Office Channel
All right
That means you not get to pick the input distribution you want to think of a better
Input distribution
If someone's going to pick one of these cars to try and communicate with you
What distribution would you like them to
Pick from
So that
You can communicate as much as possible
Habitat to neva
Okay
What's a polenta input distribution and what's the capacity
Okay they'll probably put the three shoes a half note Bowie throw away this stupid car
Because it's useless it doesn't help adjust injection noise we keep these two and the capacity is
One bit because now we've got ourselves a channel that looks like that
Two inputs to outputs
Okay
Very good
Any questions
Right so that was a slightly silly channel
Next time we will stop with this
Very simple but slightly more interesting channel the noisy typewriter
It's
Circular symmetry
Every input Master three possible outputs
How many questions are what built into distribution
And what is
The capacity
What's up with that question
Then we will prove the noisy time of coding theorem at least for the binary symmetric Channel and in the book you can find a
The General
Prefix well
Finally has some recommended homework for you to do some recommended exercises
On the website
Which you can find by looking for ITP RNN there's a hand with some more recommended exercise
Sizes from the book
And also does some software on the website if you want to make Huffman programs in or around if you want to have a husband
Program that makes optimal Huffman codes
For you this is especially for the day's compression exercise but I said please make a
Compression method to compress
Annapolis MD
Bent coin with lots of zeros in a small number of ones
Okay thanks so much for coming and
See you next time hopefully