Welcome collector 15
We're going to start talking about a completely new topic now namely neural networks
And
I want to
Kick-off by
First mentioning where in the book
We are going to be looking at Chapters 3839 on 42 and the sum of that chapter has mentioned that
But you could take a look at 2
And
I want to motivate why we should be
Interested in neural networks O'Toole
I know. I talked about brains which is one of the
Motivations are we don't understand how brains book and so it's interesting to look at theoretical models
Open
Neural networks do have engineering applications as well
So even if you don't care about your science you might be interested
Infolding
Machine learning problems
Using your last purchase
But let's talk about brands
The first
Amazing thing about brains which we will come to in the second lecture on neural networks
Is our amazing ability to do content addressable memory and this is
Quite a remarkable thing that we
Take for granted because we do it all the time
Let me just remind you of what I mean by content addressable memory
So I can give you
Images that are noisy and blurry and I have a small number of pixels and maybe they make you think of things
And we get at the content we get at the memory that you recall when you see the image
By me showing you
Fragment an incomplete
Partial content of that memory
And that's so different from the waist down the computers what cast on the computer you know the memory is in a drawer in the file
Get the memory you need to know which filing cabinet number on which card it's on and then you go and find it there
He was saying what was the cartoon that has these holes in it so magically outcomes the card
Are you with me can you see what amount of Atlas give you justice Inglewood to
And another black and white and it's not full color
Something with numbers 0 4-9 don't know why but
That's just
37 squared
I'll give you a little q's and you actually come up with the entire memory from the cues
An amazing thing the Brain Stew
The me it's really
The most exciting thing about neural networks is that Brayden can do this and we have some models that have a little bit of
Bissell capability which will come to in the next election
Let me give another example I will tell you about an oscar-nominated actress but I wouldn't reveal her whole name
She acted as amazingly good to George Lucas film
Even though one of the pieces of information that I just giving you is incorrect
Nevertheless you all thinking of Natalie Portman my prediction
So here's another example I'm going to show you the cover of a book
And the title has several words in it and I'm going to blank at all of the title except for two letters in the title
Going to blank out almost full of the the cover
And I'm going to put that black patch over the eyes of the author baby offers on the cover
Because when you put a black patch over someone's eyes then they're very hard to recognize
But nevertheless
What was I can look
A Brief History of Time well done
Saturday
How do we do it can we get machines to do it how do brains do it for me. So really
Compelling interesting and exciting problem
We might discuss that today but it's one of the motivations for looking at neural networks so today we'll do some basic stuff with neural
Networks and maybe
Look at some engineering applications open
And this is going to be the Pinnacle of the neural Nets bet we'll come back to this question
How can we do content to this address for memory and I'll show you a solution using neural networks
Let me give you just one more
Motivation for being excited about brains and neural Nets in general
This is based on some experiments that work as follows the experiments are conducted in 1989
The subjects in the experiment for showing 725 images and four of example images
Showing on the screen now
100 of them were labeled as positive images
And 625 of them
Well labeled negative images so the subject was
Instructed to memorize
The label plus plus or minus
Early images were fairly similar in character to each other
Several months later the subjects could remember all of the positive and negative examples and could distinguish them
From other images that had not been seen earlier in the experiment and even 12 months later they could still correctly
Recall all the positive and negative labels
Band
This is impressive to me because the subjects were pigeons
And
Pigeons can learn random binary labels
Completely arbitre buy new labels associated with images they can also learn to identify a particular person
The Ashley the four images that the two on the right both have the same goal with the long hair and and Boots
And
So that's how some of the images working some of these experiments
Whether it's running labels on meaningful labels pigeons can learn them
And they can respond within a fraction of a second and correctly cite you have I seen this image before
And that ability to recognize something familiar
It's something that we still struggle to do
With modern computers so I'm going to spend a little bit more motivational times saying what is the difference
What's between a pigeon and a supercomputer
So
First let's just talk about
The hardware differences
Magma basic case there is a pigeon's fresh supercomputers pigeons are much better than craze
At this sort of task of recognizing and responding to images extremely quickly
So is it because pigeons actually have access to more Hardware
Let's count
The number of devices in a pigeon brain is about 10 ft 11 neurons
The number of cynopsis the neuron might be 10 to the three also so maybe the 10 to the 14th cynopsis
I need to think of either the neurons
All the sign ups is being Elementary device is a little bit like transistors
The number of devices in the cray
I don't know
Siri say 10 to the 10
Bits of memory
That's if you got one gig of memory of course I have palm oil
But I don't want to be unnecessarily on sad because my resources are not being completely on used what about in the sea
CPU itself
The CPU maybe is I don't know a million also devices in a single
CPU
How so you could say hi ya the pigeon is Beats the clay because it's got more devices
But the pigeons devices are slow so we better take into account the clock rate
Find
5 for a crate
I'd say
The clock right is something like a thousand megahertz
Which means that
Where in the ballpark of
Having 10 + 15/10 + 19
Device
Operations
II
I just checked the latest news on two computers is in
Super videos with lots of CPUs and tons of memory
And they can do
10 to the 16
Floating Point operations
II
So we're just two different ways of of quantifying how much you've got in a cray so this is
In terms of the the hardware
How many Hardware device operations you got per second and then it says in terms of the outfit what entire
Supercomputer
A single
Not cry anymore
This is
Today's pop soup
Supercomputer
Crank up 1016 floating Point operations per second
What about the pigeon
Well clock rate correspondence to attend milliseconds
Clock time I'd say roughly cuz a single neuron can fire a hundred times a second if you push it
You could argue that some bits of the hardware and maybe have a faster clock time maybe
I'm an advocate of the idea to do some very interesting things but
Let's run with this number anyway
That means you got 10 to the 13 operations
II
If you take the neurons as your
Operating devices
10 to the 16
Operations per second
If you view the elementary transistor like
Objects
I was being sorry for the cynopsis
Sentence of operations per second
Device operations per second the cray has got more going for it
Time the pigeon
It doesn't matter output floating operations per second
If you take the sign-ups is doing floating-point operations
There are the same level as a a supercomputer in a single pigeon brain doesn't
An amazing computational ability in a pigeon brain
But it's not actually bigger in terms of these numbers
Then I cry yes
Okay the question is what's the size of the words so you're saying for these floating Point operations
Haha
He is a floating-point operation in a cry so probably that sums of operation long lines over 30
32 bit integer getting X another 32
Bit integer or something like that
Is an absolutely perfect
Plaza sign ups
If you're lucky is probably doing
I may be too old full bits
The operation
I'll guess I'll be surprised if I'm on a time schedule just 10 minutes seconds maybe getting into a full bits
Weather channels are open or not
Integer numbers of channels
Okay
So yes the wood size is only the Precision of these operations
Is bigger for the Christ
Alpha today supercomputer
Then facilitation
And it's not the case of the pigeon has far more results is at its disposal
Maybe the pigeon is far better at this image recognizing task because it organized its Hardware differently
So
Supercomputers
Are essentially just standard serial computers wired up in a slightly
Different weight they have a CPU
Or lots of CPUs
If you want to store a new memory
Without losing any of your old memories in a standard computer you have to have some new virgin
In Hardware
So does no connection at all between old memories and you married to just put them in another place and you need to know
Weather
Meanwhile pigeon brains have
The parallel
I have high conductivity
So
A typical neuron is probably connected to about a thousand of a neurons
Where are the typical transistor
And I cry it's probably connected
Roughly 3 or 10
All the transistors
Typically
The computation however is being done
Not the way I understand it is definitely distributed
When a
Pigeon learn some new memory then you memories go in the same Hardware that's using
For everything else
We don't know how
But that's told in the same Hardware
And importantly
Pigeon brains are Robusta Hardware
Damage so you can take a pigeon brain
We can take your brain and you can damage many thousands of your neurons and you still
The following day
Current functioning okay you do this whenever you drink alcohol
You kill us in your arms but you still keep going
The Kray in contrast if you reach into it inside while going to destroy 1% of the transit
Does he miss cry it's going to be fine isn't it you find that it is not fine
So here's the hypothesis
The hypothesis is
Maybe
The difference in the performance of the pigeon and the crayon this realistic
Real world image recognition task
Is
Because of the difference in style of computation
But maybe the style of computation
Is the key
So maybe we should be getting away from cereal if we're excited about being able to solve problems that computers are still useless
I maybe we should be going to genuinely parallel
Maybe we should be looking at ways of using Hardware that you have high conductivity
Doll Distributing
And work in a completely different way
Sorry the next lecture we will come back to the the task of
Storing and recalling memories
Anvil show a way of doing it
With a simple neural network models
So
I've just giving you a
15 minute motivation for why we should be interested in parallel distributed
Which is the name of one of the old Bibles of neural networks
And this one parallel distributed processing I'm going to talk about is
Parallel processing using
Elementary devices that will cool neurons
So don't have a single neuron
We just going to be a thing to have some input
Unlock put
And then we'll go to wire them up in a variety of ways
1 way wiring them up is feed-forward
Which looks like this you have some inputs going in
Sonny Rollins
And then they can access to some money runs and we can put arrows on these I just to show which way things go
And then maybe have another neuron and then something comes out
So that's a feed-forward
Network
It's simple to describe because it's so you just put in and put these guys
Computer Discount Computer and then you're done
Another way of watering these things up would be a feedback Network why you say
Let's allowed
Everyone's outputs
To be
Everyone else is inputs
Like that
And then
The Dynamics depend on exactly how you define
The way
Holding your own sand tracks
And maybe something more exciting happens
Suck
Let's talk a little bit more about the single neuron
And then
But today's lecture I'll talk to you about
Seafood Networks
And the next election will look at feedback
Netflix
So his house a
Single neuron wax
Singing the wrong input and an output
And it's got some parameters
And the promises I'll come in the cold weight
And the promise is look here between the input and the
Body of the neuron
And his eye works it's very simple
If the weights W1 W2 trouble. W
Okay and if the inputs on X1
X2
Okay
What the neuron does is it adds up the weighted sum of its inputs
Using its own weight
And add one more number Cole the w0
But you can think all those little dangling extra
White hair connected to a virtual input to this voice.
And this wait here is also sometimes called the bias
Avenue around which is what it
Activation a will equal if all of the inputs
Are there
Then having computed it activation
It computer output
Although sometimes called activity of the neuron
Through a function
And not function
Could be
101 + 89
Which looks like.
Or it could be
Hyperbolic tangent to me
Which looks almost exactly the same
Or it could be a step function
Like that
Something we could note in passing is that we have come across neurons already without
How
Knowing it
They came up
In previous like that when we discuss the variational method for spin systems that we had
Quantity is called a which will the weighted sum of average activities of spins
Rex walls
How much I spend with pointy up
He was activation and then we slept that too attached to determine how much we were pointing up
Stop we have actually seen this
And divide rational free energy
Minimisation
For a spin system
We both have same this
A little before
One of the questions
But I
Maybest in lecture and it's only in the book is
If there are two gaussian distributions
And you don't know which
All those a datapoint comes from
And it comes along and X1
X2 space
And let's say that this guy soon is labeled last one in this one's label kustoo
If I give you a datapoint x that came from this picture to guy shins please tell me what to do thing
Think is the probability that equals 1
The answer to that question is
Apple pay
Where is this thing
And a is indeed of precisely this warm summer
Pub w k x k + w
But the question
What's the inference of what class I mean and the answer is what was 50% chance
On this line
Honda Ohio
Chance on this line in the lotions
Hummus line I'm so full
So
The answer to the question varies
With consoles that are linear
And X1 and X2
Assuming that these two gaussians have identical covariance
Matrices I think we did that exercise when you are talking about clustering earlier
We've already encountered neurons we just didn't call them the time we called them simple mathematical functions
Just what they are
So let's just familiar familiarize ourselves with the new language that were using half
And let's have a play with one neuron
Here is
A picture of the output of one neuron
And the title at the top of it we can turn the lights down
The title
Told you
What the three weights of this neuron ay3
Well
It's because this particular neuron
That was playing with her husband
Inputs
We're going to play
For a while with
The feed Food Network which consists of just one euro
With two inputs
One output
And there is as usual a little bias hanging off here what you can think of
As being a weight w 0
Connected to an input with a white wall
But everyone looks at WW2 luxhair
Right
As a function of x 1 x 2
This is what the output of a neuron
Looks like
If
The weights offsets 2-15 2 and 1 in the old bios white woman Lake to
And
The function that I'm using is the one of the OnePlus 3 to the minus a which is sometimes called the logistic function
Okay
Not at play with late so let's change the weights
For the bias change the bias of the neuron the function just trundles to and fro
The orientation of the cantos doesn't change
But I'm
Function slides around now that change weight to
What does that do
Well it doesn't change with the function
Intersex
The X to equal 0
Access
But it did
Make the function swivel around that point
Dollar exchange rate Wong
That's going to make it swivel around the place where the red curve intersects the X one equals zero
Access
So now you can maybe think of it at full swiveling
Around a point that's off the screen
This is the surface plot review let's redo what I just did Rapunzel plots his Rapunzel plot
Sneakers look right size
I'm showing a contour plot of exactly the same function that we had America with the wife set to
-50 + 2 + 1
Here is 0.5 console
Here are the consoles that I forgot .2 + .80 something like that
And the white line is a representation of the normal
The red
Cancel
And if you like it's pointing in the direction of the weight Vector so
This is the X1 X2 still is is the X2 Axis
And I'm showing avexa
That's proportional to 2 in this direction
I'm warm in this direction so proportional to the weight vector
All right
Strictly these vectors input space X1 X2 and weights
31W Jewel spaces to each other so we shouldn't necessarily go forcing them on the same
Sunscreen that's why I stretch the access to make make it look
Perpendicular
Okay so let's go through the
Three-way twiddling things we just did I'm going to try to wait zero the BIOS that makes the counter
Kendall Ryan
Next will be very WW2 the third of those weights
What makes the consoles
Wonderland black vests
And finally Albury wait one
Which will make the whole thing pivot around the place where the red line intersects the vertical axis then
All right
Okay and what I'm going to do next is very all three of them so I'm going to scale
Lights up or down by a factor and I want to check that you're with me
What's going to happen if I double all three of the weights of this neuron what's going to happen to the Contour
Chatuenate
Hopefully this is all
Are straightforward
Okay any prediction of what happens if I take all three weights in Dublin
Anyone
Stipa and where does the red line go
Moose
Stay still
It stay still
It just becomes speaker so let's go back to the
Then I
So scaling up and down the weights doesn't change the place where the activation is zero
Which is where the red line
It's
Okay so that was playing with a single
Neuron
Know what we're going to do next is really sore with a neural network consisting of just one liver on
Learning means that ye something data
On the data takes the form of a set of input
Target
Passed so Target specifies roughly what you want
The neuron to say or the neural network to say
In response
To the input
And I'll have a label cold and run through
Please
Basa
And the idea of living is that we adjust
Learning is just a silly name for adjusting
The promises
Weights
Search that
Output of your neural network why when you shove in xn
Is closed
Surolan
Obviously when someone says make
Something like that happen
What you would say just tell me that please and then I'll minimize it so I'll do it that way
Function
Which measures how good the wait saw
Okogie
To start off with a G is going to have enzymes Each of which measures how close t
Is 2 why am I measure closeness is going to be
A rose event fee
Okay
Where
Why and is my shorthand for why when you come in at 10 and have the light
Okay 7 W dependents looks in y
Nnsy
And
This objective function is a sum of terms
Beechwood either looks like this
Borat looks like
This depending whether the target
Is there a
All the target
Islam
So
If y matches the target
The objective function give you the Rock
NF why doesn't match the target you got the penalty that's increasingly big
You could think of G as being
The information content of brighter
From the point of view of the neuron who views his wife as being the correct
Kentucky distribution for the data
Sorry it's the information content
I'll be Tracer or currently it is the description length
All of the data
Assuming
But you view why
As being
The correct
Pravasi
Now when I said good day sir I'm being a bit imprecise what I mean is
The set of cheese
Text you if you've already been told where the inputs are what the exes are
And then Simon Says now I'm going to tell you that he's
This is what the description length would be if you used a perfect asthmatic Kota
Or other compression message to encode them using this new wrong
Okay so
Let's Show an example of this
So is a single neuron and has some data
The sort of data we can be talking about might be we are trying to run a vegetable salting Factory
The pigeons are going on strike because they realize how good they are compared to a super computer and they want to be paid the same wage
Images of supercomputers
So now we're trying to
A simple neuron to replace the pigeon pigeon is to sort the potatoes from the carrots or the razor
News from the Pebbles
What are we doing
Labeled Asia so we measured X1 and X2 for 10 objects
Five of them with raisins and 5 with pedals
Okay so the class is off
Color that
So we know what class each of the 10 things it in
X1 X2
And what I showed you in this input space that connects to is how a neuron can produce a function
Is a ramp
A soft sigmoid ramp
So what did learning learning is
Minimizing an objective function like this with respect to w
So what does that involve well if you're at all sensible at minimizing things you'll say
Is it easy to compute the gradient
And the answer is yes it's easy to compute the gradient
So you got the gradient
I Look a Lot G which is d g e w
And then you do something sensible downhill
Thing based on the gradient
The very simplest thing you could do with a gradient is cool gradient descend
That's not a sensible thing to do because it doesn't satisfy
Covariance that you'd like the appropriate treatment of
Vector spaces I'm that do so this mixes up Vector spaces and The Jewels which is a crime
But lots of people do it
So you just look out the gradient
Mini-site let's make a step in the direction of the gradient
So that's gradient descent
And this
Promises hair
Is binaural Network people cold the letting rate
I'm not going to talk, so that you have to set somehow
It's fairly easy to
Show on this is left as a homework exercise
That the gradient can be written as a sum over all of the
Examples of t - y * X
You can think of this as the era that the neuron is currently making on the ends example
X the input
Soap to work out the gradient you put each input in
You look at the area between the output in the target
Fenty X Arrow by the input to get the gradient and you toss it up
And that
Simple operation which we got by differentiation
Is sometimes called backpropagation the backpropagation is the neural networks community
The neural network communities name for differentiation
Backpropagation is a particular algorithm for doing differentiation in Freeport
Networks when doing it efficiently
Okay so what happens if we do that we start off the new alarm
With some randomly chosen weights
And the weights change so hit is grating just can't do anything and I'm showing you the three weight values
Bull blow up
What was happening in WW1 WW2 space looks like this the weights one that off in One Direction and then they want to know
Directions to downhill downhill changed
What was getting on well his the data is the initial weight back to the life I picked at random
So it's not doing a very good job of separating the blue from the yellow and you do gradient descent
And
The weight change on where the red line is changes and it rotates around
And then it changes and it rotates
I ran some more
And the way to getting bigger and bigger
And after 40,000 attractions that's where the weights of
Coptic
All right
So that's learning
Anyone say well
I'm not happy maybe I can do better than that because
Al moment ago before we got to this final optimized
Managed to find a place where I can put a cliff
The completely separate the other points from the blue Plains
A moment before when we was little halfway that the answer looked a bit more reasonable this is it this is now
Another example of a classified for you arrived Hillside 99.9
Sure it's a blue
But it's a yellow because it's incredibly steep cliff
Stupid
We don't like this outcome
Has managed to
Minimize objective function but maybe we picked the wrong objective function
So
If we don't like this what we do will sensible people
Change function
So now what we're going to do is learning
With
The regularisation which
As
I don't like these enormous
Steep shop
Change changes in function or Enduro that what language we wait because because you got State functions
When the waves are big
So
We added an extra turn
In the objective function to get change so it's not just G the new objective function
Letter G plus an extra time
Rick Sanchez
Others like big weights
Subjectivist change from please put the diapers all the possible to
Please put the right up but I don a penalty is for having big weights
Ew
Is going to be defined to be
Sum of w
K scratch
All right
Right so we do that
Not his what happens I've set this parameter Alpha
Which is either cold
The regularizer if you are from the statistics world
Oh sorry the regularisation Clemson
Ew is cold but regular
Or if you're in neural networks Alfred's cold the way she tell you right
When you have their own what happens to your gradient well it's just an extra ounce of the gradient of
Cheapest Alfa ew is this Loft Plus
Alpha x your weights
So you're going downhill on that means you've got to minus Alpha
W
Tom and
What happens when you do the minimisation is showing here in terms of what the weights do they used to blow up
But now I settle down
And they don't
We don't have a nevus deepening
Function
So wait to settle down and his what used to happen when we didn't have the regular rise of the orange color
Blowing up
Did what happens in WW1 WW2 space we go downhill downhill enso to stop along the trajectory
Great if I could lay is what happens so we follow message saying trajectory and weight space but we stopped
I'm at an Optimum this new objective function
This is why we used to be yelling at the 40,000 decorations of steepest descent
Not when we switch on the way Decay we go downhill and we end up in this place hair
Josh White resigns this again so it looks
Sensible
All right and you might look good
Because now it's not making completely unreasonable overconfident answers for example if you say for another Point arriving at
Location hair
What's the chance of is in the blue class it'll say about 90% instead of saying I'm a hundred percent sure
And
If you're Dutch
Another one of those yellow White Castle safe if you could see
Based on
Potato Head balloon raisins
You might still be dissatisfied and if you are hold that thought will come back to this in a moment
Not we're going to switch to
Lava Networks
And then we'll come back to the the the single neuron when we fought some more ideas
Let me just
Couple more things about the single neuron and then we'll come back to that this learning business
First I can give you an example of using a single neuron to actually do a real problem so I told you about
Golden raisins while here inside is a handwriting problem you can get yourself a dataset of handwritten digit
They're being digitized into black and white dots
In 256 Dimensions so you can get yourself a few thousand
Examples of twos and threes
And
Use the algorithm I just described
To come up with a single neuron which has 256 input has 250
Wait
And its output can be read as the probability that this thing I'm looking at is at 2 or 3 when you do that this is what the weights
Optimized
Look like
And the error rate of the classifier that you
I've made is about 10% so on this
Database of handwritten digits it gets completely useless even a single
Iran can be an interesting quick and dirty way to solve
Simpson pool
Inference problems
A question you could ask about a single neuron
Is
You can do as a communication Channel
So
This is just a little aside and there's a whole chapter on this in the book if you're interested
One way of thinking about what's going on here is
Oh I don't really believe that the output of the neuron is the correct from Realty distribution so forget that idea
But I do believe that the neuron is a helpful way to package up
The contents of the data set
So if you give me a date to that
With lots of lots of examples of handwritten digits
I can package all of that up
Into 257 middle numbers
What y'all say a single neuron
And then I can send the neuron to someone so I can send the weights w
And then someone else
Could try and reconstruct what the labels were
Bye
I'm assuming I can get the same inputs
When I get those inputs they can use the neuron to reconstruct
What the output was
So is this sort of information Theory
If you of
I think we are on
And you can ask the question
If I view the neuron as a channel
What would capacity of that channel
How many bits calendar on love
And you can pull my side question
Find the chapter in the book does this
And has a rather interesting non-trivial answer
Which comes out like this assuming that these exes are in random
The are in general position so bad
Either randomly distributed oil at least enough nastaliq alinea with each other
Taxes are in general position
Then there's a good chance
That
You can correctly learn with your neuron
Any
Random labeling
The world comes up with
Has a good chance you can learn that
As long as the number of labels
And
Is less than or equal to
Twice the number of inputs
Which is twice the number promises
So
What did I just say I said a single neuron with cayenne puts can almost certain they memorize
2K
Random binary labels
That means that the capacity of a neuron in terms of
How many bits you can stall and it's weights each of the weights only one up 2wk
Each of them is a real number
But effectively if you're using the neuron in this way as a way of Justice
Learning the labels on some examples and then reproducing them
You can reliably communicate
With that channel
Two bits
Parent Connection
That's a really handy rule of thumb
The many
Neural net
Style application
If you're using a neural net
Then maybe the effective number of bits you can learn in that
It's something like twice
The number of promises you've gotten in the network
This is precisely true for a single neuron and it may be true for all the types of neural network as well but you need to
Use that idea with cat
Fright not letting us communication under the capacity results for a single neuron
What I want to do now is move to slightly more realistic networks about bigger
And
I'm going to show you a neural network which has
A load of
What we call Hidden neurons
Simplicity I'll show you
A network with just one input which is where the mouse is pointing now
This is the bias unit if you like
And this is the output
So it's a multi-layer network with one hidden layer
Hugo from the input
Where are we
You go from the input which hair is just one dimensional
Neurons
And then you got to your output hair haven't gone through all of these guys here
Is the number of hidden
Neurons
The number of parameters in this thing
Is roughly three
H
Because this to input switch one and then this guy hair
Has roughly H Prime has going to go more actually 3/8 + 1
Okay so I want to
Explore bit more what functions look like for a neural network like this this is the simplest exam
Allpay
Multi-layer perceptron
Wigwam hidden lair
Liesl mobile apps that parents are still quite widely used
Interesting to
Understanding
Turn light switch to Yellow demo
What I'm doing here is I'm going to show you the case h = 3
I'm going to make
A random
Network unlock Sim setting all of the weights how many of the 6/10 I'm setting the 10 weights of
This network
The random values drawn from a passing distribution and then I'll update those wait and we'll see what happens to the the Run
Even function
That's a whole bunch of functions you can get
Functions of the
Input variable which is showing you the input variable X warm on the horizontal axis in the bus
Texas is the output y
Does coming out help this
Multi-layered Network
Right
So that was a little movie of a bunch of functions what are you doing we're just adding up three tentious
It's the sum of 3 hyperbolic tangent
And that's what the blue thing is this an example of what you got when you make a weighted sum of three Alba tree
Tangent functions
Another name for most neural networks that use. In the real world is
Weighted sums of hyperbolic tangent
That doesn't sound quite so sexy
Okay his only 10 hidden neurons and the blue line is a some of those 10 hyperbolic tangent
All the things that go between -1 + 1 of hyperbolic tangent functions themselves that the
10 neurons of computing
Okay we randomize the weight Seneca is very busy with
And that shows you the sort of thing that you got for a single input
Single output
Neural network
That's increase 225 and has a whole bunch of random functions
So what's it look like
It looks like a French cuff and so another way of thinking about your neural network is
Please feed forward
Multi-line not but I'll just French cuffs
And when you then bring along some data inside please fit
This girl at work today so you're just saying
Please put a French cuff
Through the data you know what I mean by friends cuz it's one of those
Bendy things you buy something
What's up
Bendy and rubbery
And it gives you a smooth curve Precinct
I don't know maybe they don't sell them anymore
But that used to be popular in in in high school so that you could
Make a bendy smooth
Smooth cuff
Right
So what can we do next
The devil I just showed you with 25 all hidden units
I drew the weights at random from a gaussian distribution I didn't tell you what the standard deviations with
Now I'm going to show you those standard deviations they were all equal a moment ago
And the screen is now showing you for equal standard deviations for the input weights
The bias weights
How many outputs which are colored Now red
Purple
And
Gray
Barre3 blue cuz I'll show you three random draws
From
Bhagat Singh distribution
Right so you can see those three functions
I know what I'm going to do is crank up and down the standard deviations just so you can see
What effect scaling the white survives the running weights
Making bigger or smaller has on the random functions so first
Let's crank up the input weights standard deviation
We see the functions of
Moore weekly shrunken hyperbolic tangent
Okay if we take
Sigma in
The standard deviation of all the input lights down broad functions that locally
You look just like straight line
Okay
Now let's treat the biases biases we can
Have big standard deviation for them
We can have
Smooth on adoration and now we got something that looks like it's a sum of about three or four hyperbolic tangent even though it's a function
So the standard deviation of the biases is 217 how many wiggles you get
Hobbit it doesn't affect
The characteristic length scale of The Wiggles that was being controlled by
The standard deviation of the inputs
Finally free prank up and down the standard deviation of the outputs this is trivial
The functions just become
Hiya vertically
Hola
All right
So that's the role of those three standard deviations
So what do we do next
Let's go sell some data
So just as with a single neuron
We
Compute the gradient steepest descent on that grade in
And we ended up
We have this perfect you separate the five yellow petals from the five blue raisins
We can do the same thing with the basis that looks like that's here off 5 beta
Point
And we can define a new objective function which instead of
Being with geha
It's going to be at Manchester real numbers
Apocalypse
The outputs onto targets so we have
A girl that function like this cold why
You have some Target values like this
These are the errors
Christian is William
American Define EDD equals sum of
Ha
TN - y n
Square
What other measure of error could you possibly have well
Obviously other ones that this is a standard thing people often some squares
And that depends on W on the weights
Through the white ends which are old
Weight dependent
Right
So what do we do with that we say this is our objective function please make the output of Twisted puppet all the targets
You compute the gradient G which by definition is DED
By the W and many people do steepest descent I'm not objective
Function set a gradient downhill
All right lights on please
And his what happens after one direction of steepest descent so I started off with 25 hidden units
Sharon by the blue line
And we start going downhill another one is racing it's already looking quite promising
Now you do another restoration and you do 2000 3000 8000 9000 is Russians
Underwear that with this green thing which perfectly goes 205 datapoint
I have learned
The function
From the 58.0 maybe say
Not rubbish that's stupid because maybe you're dealing with a noisy problem we're actually
What you really think is going on isn't there is a true on the line function and the datapoint
White bison
Additive noise and then you would be rather irritated to have
Agreeing cuz it doesn't go through every single
Detail Livernois
I guess you all just asked if I did not weigh
What do you then say
Why do you say I want to do learning with regularization
Answer you change the objective function again
And decide I need some sort of Regulation
Because I don't like this really function cuz it's a bit earlier than I was expecting
Expectation of it and not being super duper weekly
Can be expressed with regular limes are good old regular Liza
We had a moment ago ew
You can add alpha x it or maybe a bit more sophisticated and you say actually I should deserve divine
The weights in two classes because
Remember remember to get the wiggle Inus
Vestibule function
It had
A length scale it was determined by the standard deviation of infant lights
It had a number of Wiggles that was related to the standard deviation of the bias is
So it's actually number of Wiggles in a typical function with Cigna buying service
Roughly
I'm out of this cool thanks Kyle it was something to do with Sigma route to Times Square
H
So since the
Input weights
Magna shoes in the biases and outputs are affecting things in such different ways it might make sense to have three regular
One for each of these things
I need to Define
Ew13 the sum of squares
All of the weights
Summing over the biases
Gw2
The Babe sum of squares with weights
Over the input weights only
Tw3 could be half some of WK squared
Coming over the output lights
Oh man that would be a more Dimension the valence thing to do and then you can say my regular Eiza is
Some oversea goes in 1 2 3
Alfa See Ew say and then hitting something dimensioni valid
Robin just pretending that they all have the same
Regularization
So when you do that the lights on please
Instead of the data are going ever smaller as you manage to perfectly fit the data
And the white blowing up which is what just happened with no regularizar
You can add on you can settle the alphas say to one just to start off with so Alpha One
Oportun off of 301
I know you got downhill and this whole situation looks
Just like last time he keep on going downhill and just sit still
I need a for 10000 its relations
And hasn't blown up and gone terribly Wiggly to fit every detail of Illinois
For all you might say maybe that's better
But you might still be a bit dissatisfied because
Now is that really the answer to a question what was the question
Anyway the objective function that we all know minimizing cold m
Time is equal to
A multiple of Idi plus some of Alvin See Ew
That's what we're not minimizing a function has going down and settle down and we found enough of it
And the weights blown up
Okay what's next I suspect what's next is interpretation of
What we're just doing silent see ya okay
Let's go back
The single neuron
So the single neuron
Look like that
And I want to
Encourage you to feel dissatisfied with this
And feel dissatisfied with
This thing as well that we just had a moment ago
And then we'll fix your dissatisfaction
So why should you feel dissatisfied with this outcome of having trained a single neuron
As a replacement for the pigeon that discriminates
Pebble from raisins
Well
Have a think
About what
As you set altitude a different value you got a different answer for 2.1 different solution
And he said off of one and you got two different solution against one issue is how do you set the timer
But another issue even if you were happy with the with some magic that was used to set it to this value
You might say
I'm willing to believe that the predictions hereabouts are quite well tolerated to this day so I think
Look for you both. Yeah yeah so 20% is shared 80%
But I don't believe this extrapolation over here
So
If you look at points
Cold A&B
Are you happy with the idea
That would just as confident a is soda
90% certain to be in the other class
And bees overnight intensive to be in the other class
Is that reasonable
If you are dissatisfied you might be interested in
The view of learning as
Inference
So we discussed
Learning as communication
And I was going to discuss learning with legalization and weight gain
Inference
So if someone minimizes something
AR-10 today fine
I will exponentially the thing you'll minimizing and I'm going to interpret as a probability whether you like it or not
So someone take mmw which is DFW plus Alpha ew
I minimize this
I will say
All right
I'm going to interpret that in the following way
The posterior probability of the weights given the implicit assumptions you're making
Is Easter - mfw
On that
And that is equal to the product of
The probability of the data
Giving w
And the probability of w
Giving all your assumptions
So this is your poster distribution given the data on your other assumptions and that needs normalizing with something
Implicitly if you minimize this thing you are finding the most probable W given these assumptions
The probability of the data given W is e to the G
Off
W
Find the probability of w the probability is 82 - Alpha
UW
On something
So this is an interpretation of what people are already doing it doesn't change anything but it may add some useful
Perspectives
Sorry if someone minimizes this objective function
They are implicitly assuming that
It really is the case
That does an underlying function y that generated the day to buy flipping been coins with a bias of why
So that's the interpretation of
Data
Came
From
Why using a bent coin
Golf bios
Why
That's what this means
End
The regular eyes of it being used to penalizing on with weights because we decided we didn't like it always late
Is interpreted as a private Leaf about the weights that says if ew is
Pop W Squared example it's saying that the prior probability of w is a normal distribution
With mean 0
End with standard deviation Sigma squared
W
That is equal to 1 / alpha alpha
I'm going to go with a pain in the neck Alba tree regularization compliment
Is now interpreted as being the variance
Have a prior distribution
Misinterpretation can be
Ignored or it can be exploited
The exportation says okay let's take this literally and then we can do a whole load of new things
For example we can actually ask
What's the right way to turn the entrance into a prediction
If someone asks for a prediction what should you do
Well if you believe is most correct
And you're asked to predict what's the probability that the next thing that we just observe at Lowe's
Location x + x + + Wong
Is in class 1 what's the probability this new point on the screen
What's the probability that it's a potato
4 times table
Given the data we've seen so far and all the other assumptions
Well the answer to that question isn't found by saying
Please welcome the W that minimizes this and then use that to make predictions answers done
So the correct answer if you believe Ali Simpsons is you should marginalised / W + 2
BMW
* the prediction which is why
Evaluated at x n + 1
Using the premises
W
So that's what you actually ought to do if you believe the assumptions that you've been personally
Be making
That's an example of
An average value of a simple function
Under a nasty red
Distribution
And we know three ways
Elephant
We can use Monte Carlo methods
We can use variational method
Or
We can use
The prices method
So let's do that
So just to make clear what's red then nasty red distribution is this thing the posterior probability of the weight
Thanksgiving the date
I'm not
Is this thing here
It's a nasty red thing
But we can compute house before Me 2 - time of w and M we have powder formula for
So we can attack this in a variety of ways
Sumfest way I will use is cooled multicolor
So we can take Handbook of Monte Carlo methods
And
We can say
Oh goodness me
We can say 45 slides
Right
We can say
Let's give us at the Monte Carlo method
Used Monte Carlo
To evaluate this quantity k
How different is that
Well if we use
Hamiltonian Monte Carlo hamiltonian if you like to the guy that involves Computing the gradient and then going
Downhill with momentum and randomizing momentum from time to time
A very simple version of the hamiltonian want to call him at the Disco belongs remind message
Which involves
Going downhill a little bit and adding some noise
So how does that different different from steepest to sense
The difference by adding a better noise
San Francisco's on Hill
What we're going to do now is do seems to sense with a bit of noise
I'd rather than accept reject decision in there as well
So we can use the lawn Divine method
And if we go back to this thing
What will now see
Is
The laundromat head stomping from
This place of the origin
Where we used to just go downhill and his way we ended up having going downhill
What are you just saying that have computer time whole we have to do is go downhill and I have some nice there's nothing nothing huge costs
Fancy Bayesian inference method you just add some noise at the right amount of noise putting put in
September Jax to make sure it's old
Correct
His what happens I'm going to zoom in on the 1st
Elbow of the optimization
So that's the first album
Enjoying the same amount of computer time
His way we got to
With laundromat episode
Victoria Lee
What you can think of happening
If we used to go
NW spay still be wrong W-2 and it's actually three dimensional for this
Play problem we used to go downhill to an ultimate
Now we're feeling that as the minimum of a read function which has some
Strange shaped like this
And we're going downhill and adding noise in such a way as the sample from that entire red
Distribution
I got his what happens after 40000 its relations
We're going to leave samples
From the entire red
Distribution
And we can take those sample points
And add up
The predictions why for each of those so we can approximate
That's using the sound of Monte Carlo idea
Bye
This is approximately one
Some
Or is one
Y X + + 1
Using weights
Weather Eastlake wi come from
Through
The miracle of Monte Carlo
True hamiltonian
Monte Carlo
Write up the plants or just need to sum up all of them
And I'll do that right now
So I'm not going to use old 40,000 I'll just pick
$100 ice samples
His what the weights were doing with time wandering up and down in an older car related way that's what they would
Would have done if we just optimize I would have settled down and
They still thought I would doing something more interesting bubbling around looking at Poolesville outcomes
And this is
What it looks like if we take those hundred samples and I will. Visualize some of them for you in
Infospace I'm going to show you 30 of those functions
30 of these functions
Why
Xn
For the different values of w
I'm going to show you the ex dependents now
All right
And the concept is these a 30 typical plausible ideas about how to explain today's hits
7 through these noticed that the classification of b sometimes changes
Look it's on the blue side now
Still on the blue side now it's on the other side
And the conservation of a
Doesn't change the match is on the other side yellow
Just a little bit of blue yellow yellow yellow yellow
So when we add all of these together you can anticipate
So the answer for a is not going to be the same if you could be any more
Verizon
When we approximated this
Integral hair in a really stupid way
By saying
Let's approximate this
As
Bendigo VW
Delta function at w
Set to W Starr
X Y of x w
That's a really stupid approximation that says let's replace the whole distribution by had a spike
When we did that. The same answers be
Tonight let's do it right
How many do it right
Given the assumptions we just nice
You got not this which is the answer with the ultimate promises
But
And you might say
I prefer that in which case you might like
Bayesian learning and inference
Okay so that was one method
Another method is to say
I don't want to do Monte Carlo I want to use something a bit more deterministic
So you could say
I'm going to approximate this
Fly
Indigo DW
A nice distribution Q
Have a w given data
Or are they giving Pizza
X y
So you could say
I can't cope with this Monte Carlo integration approach
But if you had some simple form for example
A normal distribution
Then maybe I could come compute this fairly quickly and simply
So
The approach that I'll show you now says
Let's use the prices method
To come up with a normal approximation and it will fit into that formula and do the last step
Numerically which can be done
Are you silly
So Lights On Again
Just show you these a few more times could you get a nice soda
Illusion of non-parallel with
Okay this is a few more laundry bomb pictures before we we do LaPlace
Contrast of the objective function that went down when we minimized it
The laundromat that goes down a little over the place because we're not asking the optimizers what devices anymore
We didn't actually want to optimize it because we are not interested in the best primer interested in
What Floresville settings of the premises are
Okay
So what's next laplace's method
Here is the gaussian approximation
It is as a function of W1 W2 and W3 which you can see the three weights
And
It's Augustine distribution that I projected down onto
This W on W-2
Space for this particular figure hair
And when you
Integrate. The weights and then compute the numerical integral that you left with
You can notice that the guys going to mention isn't necessarily very good one and send play Kiss that the yellow samples from the posterior with the law
Songs about method
And that doesn't look at all like samples from the green gas you so it's not a very good approximation
But nevertheless is better than not bothering at all
And it was the predictions reopen micrometers
His predictions we got from the launch of my method and his what you got from the gas station
APA citing for a banana
Numerical detail
It's
A big difference
Okay
I think that's the end of
The
Learning is inference for the single neuron
We cannot go through the same process
RV
Feed-forward Network as well so let's go back
So
I'm going to go
We were I hope dissatisfied because the Greenline went perfectly through all the right points which is what we had to ask it to do
And I was going to say we don't like that let's use the lungs by method to sample from the posterior exact interpretation
The two times the date the time
And the wait times
Are the likelihood unlock sale in the prior
Of a Bayesian distribution
And
We use the lungs by method in just the same way so instead of competing the gradient and going downhill you compute the grade in
Go downhill and add some nice
That means that the first few steps look just the same as before
But now you got Billy Billy Billy Billy Billy instead of just settling down and going to a boarding Optimum
And you can pick from those
30000 it's rationed a few representative samples for example a dozen is probably enough so many problems
And those doesn't samples can be used to predict things like
What's your mean what's your variance and so forth so I can extract from these 12 samples which show 12
Credible hypotheses of the underlying function is
Assuming that it was made by a sum of hydraulic engines
That's 12 hypotheses and
Hair is the mean
And
Standard deviation
That you got from those 12 samples
Notice the standard deviation small wave data
Lighting and it's ultra-wide onu
Interpolating of 1/2
So that's against showing the benefit of using a Bayesian
View of this little learning
Protest and there are many other benefits that I won't go into now for example you can get automatic complexity control the volume
Alpha 1 Alpha 2 Alpha 3 become increasingly important
The mold I mentioned you you're working in
And you can use Bayesian methods to automatically info what should I have one after another for 3B
Given the date of it I've got so you can get rid of that headache as well
With the Bayesian approach
Right is there anymore in that his a graph showing what happened to the objective function
And that
Is that
Okay so I'm showing you the
Interpretation of learning as inference
And I want to wrap up my app I just telling you a few applications I'll be so to feed forward neural network methods
So these are all quite old now because I wrote this lines
A while ago and they were some
Interesting examples at the time
On the remote have come in in the intervening years
The
Very earliest application that I came across of using feed-forward neural networks to solve interest
Problems with the task of
Getting it
A neural network to read aloud and quotes the way that what was
The input
Represented seven successive Leches in a piece of text
The hidden units. To see old 7 lashes
Do some stuff and spit out
Output which is not just one number but rather a multi-dimensional representation of a phoneme so there was a binary
Encoding of the input in a binary encoding of phonemes
And the
Training Albert insalaco text and correct pronunciations and see if we can learn in general
That was an early success of neural networks cuz it didn't work
Too badly
Another very significant success which I think still has not really being sick
Beachin
Is the use of mokolea
Free photo that works to do genuine handwriting recognition
This was done by Young laocoon and colleagues at AT&T
And his an example of
An input to the network which is a three and a four with some scribbles on it and it's called zillions of hitting you
Units on the nap at the top and it says this is Rena for
And it's very impressive thing I was mean to getting my browser web page showing you
A demonstration of this thing you can you can hunt for it on for Lynette on the international
Hussy
The range of things that it could correctly
Classify
Another example that I was involved in was the muddling of weld toughness
Weld toughness is
A function of
Cookery essentially you cook the well by putting in various
Impurities and picking and eating temperatures and so forth in the weld with a whole range of properties
Toughness as a strength
Yield yield strength and
Ultimate tensile strength answer for and
If you're going to use a welding a particular component for example these things on the floor Power Station components and I need to be well
You want the well to have correct
Properties
And there are many ways of trying to model weld
Properties like toughness
But if it's a really complicated thing and toughness is
Maybe it's a good idea just to get data and train a neural network on it and that's what everybody Sharon die
Did and
This is a real photo
Boxes of welding stuff this is a photo of the real thing that was made with the help of a neural network
These components are about to be welded together with the stuff that was designed using the neural network in his the man who killed his
To do welding he's just having a practice before we have to Weld stick
The real components
Services used for real at Siemens
And it's estimated that the neural-net approach save significant resources of
Compared to the alternative which would be to make a weld test it and then make another welding test it then people changing big the cook
Capri by by hand
So that's a success and we probably two dozen papers on
Modeling various properties of wells and other types of metal
Another example that like makes like the back of time was a nature paper by Rodger Angell which describes how you cook
Could focus multiple mirror telescopes using neural network
The input to the neural network was the slightly fuzzy slightly out-of-focus image coming from
The multiple mirror telescope
Indeed
Output is the action that you should apply right now to go telescope to to clean up the the the fuzziness in
Non Focus plus out of the North Pole
Mirror images
Very up imposed on proton tricky problem solved by other methods but neural networks
We're able to do a grand job
So we talked through the probabilistic interpretation of learning and
You might say oh so will these neural networks it's just High dimensional cuz fishing isn't it
And that is exactly correct for the ones I just been telling you about these multi-level set from
Networks
Coffee Food Network
Really all just doing high-dimensional curve fitting if it's expedient to use a neural network fine but if you have other meth
Methods of doing high-dimensional coefficient that you are content with and don't get on your nerves and you could use those
As well as a concrete example of another way of doing high-dimensional coefficient is gas in processes which I described
In the book so you don't have to use neural networks you could just use a gas in process which is a high dimensional
Company Mobile
Does the brain only do high damage will cut 15 well I suspect the answer is no we don't know how brains work but I do think
The brains are more exciting things in your brain can do I don't know if you seen this picture before it's a picture
Of an animal
And
Can you see what it is hands up if you couldn't recognize it
Okay
Sorry it's a dog and it's facing that way
And it's so facing away from us
The dalmatian
And
Baptist are
Never say it not hands up
So
I find it hard to imagine that this is just a feed-forward multi-dimensional company exercise and when I look at
Image like this I find it so exciting and it feels like my brain is coming out with hypotheses and isn't active
Participant
Maybe coming up an explanation for the wells and sexual
And those anatomical evidence that they aren't just free food that works as well
So in the next like that will come back to the meet one of the most exciting questions which is how can we make contact address book
Memories and describe a very simple neural network
The console
I counted restful memory challenge here's the challenge
The challenges to make a dynamical system it should be a system with 25 degrees of freedom 25 variables that
Change with time
The dynamical system can have 300 tunable parameters
And those promises have full bits of precision
The challenge is
You are going to be given some designs memories and those memories should be fixed points of the Dynamics
So the memories might look like this here are 325 dimensional patents they look like a d a j in the sea
And you got to come up with a way of instantly saying okay I will set the 300 parameters in the following way and I will
Bose
So that
If you
Set off from a noisy version of one of those desired memories like this which is actually annoyed CD design
Dynamics system should take you to this which is a clean-up day
If I give you this as soon as you see you should end up with this
And if I give you this annoy CJ
You should end up with this
That's the challenge to come up with a way of making a dynamical system and setting its parameters so that for any choice
Or almost any choice of the fixed-points
You can
Set the parameters and create those pics points
So that it will do content addressable memory will do
Cleaning up of a noisy
Memory
Moldova
You should have the following properties it should be possible if I give you an extra memory sio here's a fourth one I just thought
You should be able to make just a little tweak to the promises
So that the three
Memories that we were already that I still that
Just like I tell you something new and you don't forget everything that you for the love
The old memory should be preserved but you should learn the new Henry to you should have a new fixed point
So I just a little prick the parameters should magic me create a new fixed point
I want it to be able to drink alcohol and still work
So you'll dynamical system should be robust
2 corrupting more than half of the promises
But it should still working still have fixed points
How those three places
Okay that's the challenge
I9 curse you to try and solve this challenge before the next lecture
I didn't expect I'll show you a solution to this problem
Thanks for listening