Let's recap where we're up to in the course and what relevant reading in the text
Book
We've done a lot of information Theory data compression and when I went to the inference and data modeling
The relevant chapters
7 haircut
What color method 91352
But I still message coming up in the next chapter 33
I'd like to highlight some additional reading
Whitcomb's material we wasn't doing lectures but it's a good thing to do
I encourage you to read a very short chapter cold
And in order to understand this life and the next one
You may want to read about icing models in you want if you're not already familiar with them
Isn't that whole bunch of recommended exercise is on the website and some of some of them are on the screen
Now you may enjoy doing that if I said anything you want
Fully understand Imperial then doing the exercises is a
Kipapa School
The course website the books website is there
We're in the middle of talking about Monte Carlo methods
In the last lecture we introduced some
Basic standard Monte Carlo methods
And the rules of the game that we are interested in
Red distribution copay
It's rats cuz it's a bit nasty
It's not
We can compute it
So we can write it as Ethan the lineup
On Zed and we have computer program
Evaluate this thing for any
Value of XX being a certified diamond small thing
These properties were interested in under the sister Beach
So the rules of the game
They can evaluate
But not that we don't know that cuz that would be of interest to be like
Want to know that we often give up on his head because it's so hot
On the problems with
Problem one says give me some samples
Repeat
Either by phone or in some other way please tell me the expected value of some functions I'm interested in
Under anesthesia red distribution
Average value of pi
Because some function I'm interested in
Not the average under the Nazi rest distribution of the function
Disable touch functions pie
You all
We can use
Solutions to problem want to answer problem too because we can just died his intestine
Mesa all
Expected value we can estimate
That's by summing up by
I hope that you got from the distribution empirical average of cost
Boy abusing
Sometimes today the nasty red distribution will be the fee
Spin systems are one example I mentioned in the last night. Maybe were interested in
Magnets
And we have a spin system with an energy
That depends on the couplings J
The Energy System the energy of a system is
The sum of a loader
Weighted
Truck X between Pairs of spins
And the mail also be local Fields H and HIV
Pale skins and there is
An n-dimensional binary that
But that's an example of a problem we want to focus all the sort of things you might want to know
But you're not a magnet what is its average energy
Fluctuations in its energy with you can get if you know the mean squared energy I mean honestly what this mean
Magnetisation which is the average of the spindle
Maybe mean squared
Magnetisation
Andrew might be interested in the entropy which which is the average
Log on everything
A bunch of things we might want tonight
Hernando magnet and you probably won't want to know all of those out of range of temperature so I can pop in it
Domino's Pizza
Like this and then recall
The inverse temperature Pizza is inverse temperature
So those are examples of things you might want to know
And I emphasize last time when we do Monte Carlo message we are not trying to find BMO
Most probable State offices
We would only be completely doing that if we set the temperature
Body cold then it will hopefully be fine
The Golem
A few samples
Look like
I'm going to try to visit the whole of it
The number of electrons in the universe
Embrace preferring lost power
Okay so that's the rules of the game and an example of what we doing last time
We discussed importance sampling rejection sampling
Get something on the Metropolis method
Metropolis method is actually a very general cancel because many of the other methods are examples
When I say the Metropolis message today I'm quite helping using a push or pull
Publix method with a simple proposal Distribution off the Titan High code
And the little
Let's repeat that little show now just to remind you what we were doing
So we have a nephew probability distribution in red and have functions whose average values
You're interested in
We looked at simple sampling from a uniform distribution and then we wait
Taking Point sampling distribution
No problem turning green the Easy distribution cute then you rewrite the point
Sampling Yuri weight
The five values
To take account of having used the wrong distribution
And we did that for a variety of distribution cookies
Then we
Rejection sampling which is a perfectly sampling from the red distribution by throwing away
Some of the samples from the green distribution
And rejection sampling
Doesn't work if you do it wrong
Nickel / dimensions
But it
Open Bible technique in small numbers of dimensions
And there are high dimensional methods which can use rejection sampling
Opponents to make them go
Something being used in one dimension as a Time
Then we go down to the Metropolis message
And my examples of metropolis message was that
Have a continuous space and the Nazi distribution is turning red
We introduced a green distribution which varies with the current states whatever your current state is required
For example
Properties of the red it doesn't have to be
So you pick any Q you want and then there's a rule when you grew up and let you but either accept thing
Florida get a proposal
I'm retarded around
The rejection lead to point piling up in the places where it is think so
Green distributions
Projections for the strength
Come Sunday
Bread distribution
And there's a fair that almost any greened recent Q
Will Givens
Long running time
Give you a sign for what Auntie comes from
Feed the thread distribution
Asymptotic time could be extremely long if you've made a poor choice of
I also showed you get something I wasn't recap for the kids that are now
But that's a little bit rock and roll
Updating one variable at a time from its conditional distribution
To get something nice property
But it doesn't have any parameters in it unlike
The public
That pickup
And that might be questioned important
Get something is not it doesn't mean to get something but at least you don't have to chew
Okay
What we're going to do now is
Focus in a bit Home Depot
And we're going to criticize it we are motivated to do the advice
So
Here are the problems with the standard most especially the Metropolis
But it gets around by random Walk and Run the books can be very slow
Second
Chocolate method I showed you
Hyukoh Stepside to it and the results that you got very sensitive
To the choice of steps I didn't choose honeysett size
If you use two biggest that side then typically you'll get nowhere very slowly
So
You have to choose exactly and it would be great for the scaffold training
How to get good results
Finally
I told you I said that's a synthetic leave this thing will converge but there's no way of telling that they send a message
Well how they can book you can run a whole letter Diagnostics that you really don't get any guarantee of confession
I'm going to look at Solutions of all three of these
Problems today
Behavior
Still have some
To those promises
Taken away
I'm finally I was discussing amazing thing for the exact time
Which is a method that
Effectively runs the change of time even though it's only uses a finite
Stop
Brilliant
Let's talk about random walk Behavior
I want to
Look at a simple a really simple example
Run home
Challenge of Running Wolf behavior is
So
Here we have
A little demo
Which is the following
Poly problem
Something you like
So for the polywell
The red distribution unnormalized
Is Wong
In a bunch of places and zero in a bunch of other
Clifton II
And it warm whenever X is in this subset of the type of windshield long to read
Zero Otto i t distribution
Which is a very good grass in your head
We're going to pretend that we can draw directly from that distribution
And to help us we're going to introduce a simple distribution that we can draw from because we do have access to a Fair coin
I'm going to make a proposal
The new from the current place at to a new place ex-prime
Can this way
We're going to flip a coin and it's going to come out
If it comes up heads will say let's move left
It comes up
Tails with a right
What unit
So this is an example of a nasty distribution which if we actually knew how
Why did walls we would realize it roughly 20
Why the Catholic I was going to be my name
The long light tile distribution
On the steps that which I was taken care
Call cool pet supplies long from getting a name to my
Stepside price at salon
Okay
What do I mean by Elwell it's something like the distance from Walton typical point in the typical set
To another physical point
Something like that
You could argue maybe that or else should be Channel
Awesome questions about this chain
Set it going you can imagine if this is plenty
Is why I could performance Poison Ivy by The Calling
Inteva moving to the right or the left
This proposed moves when you use them
Because the probability ratio between any two
I'm a cure so he's always going to be Wong
When I have to get the wool if we propose
Moving to the right
Then that will be division
And you'll get mixed up with probability of 0 Texas
So that's the first 20 steps on the screen
All This Time Staffing problem
Monogatari fight
How to get to it
I'm not princess right questions for YouTube
Western Wall
Roughly
How long will it take until the chain generate a good sample from Pig
Gold Exchange
Tannerite
That's good
Sample from 8
I have already to find few good but I just want you to send your neighbor and
Answer the question anyway this is the real world
Define things to think
So how long is it going to have to run for
And if you're struggling with that question is another question which is more precise
I think it's going to be roughly
Until
We hit
Hey
1 Willowdale
Christian Grey how long until weed
How long you think you'll be until April
Take questions two and three off precise question
I'd like you to rub plate
Tell me what that how long
It's always that one will how long until
And then you gotta think about whether those
Questions are relevant to question 1 how long do you need to run the chainsaw
Stop coughing from
Sciatica pain
Until you think you getting a good
Friends
Okay honey
Any of these questions
Okay which question are you
Anne Frank
Okay so
How to get a good sample from P you're saying it has to have a chance to
Getting quite a long way
And that's going to be quite a rare thing that manages to go a long way
So your suggestion was
Wanted made about 10 unlikely things happened then maybe we will
Anti what is off the 10.
That one in a thousand
It might be doing all right
Peacock about 10 unlocked
Interesting
Praying it may well be in writing any other ways
Answering any of these questions
Anyone
Okay
Okay so you're saying if we have long enough to hit the wall then it's probably long enough
Alright. How long is it until we
I had to work that you think this is the right time to?
About 200 that's why am I 200
Piranha
So the distance you got a typical distance you've gone there's something like the square root
Pause the number of times.
Border on the wall
Confirm
Even though
Did I only take 10 sets in principle to reach the wall
You will
Mystic
Toyota
And then if you want to get all the way from there to the other Old Navy
Broccoli
Maybe another 400-500
Do I have a chance of getting back
So let's let's go through the reasoning so
Let's define the distance that the random walk with a gum
3 is a sum of all the steps we might
So after time capital T
The distance to prom
Is Ada + 100 - could be zero if we do it rejection
But to start with
Where in the middle
Either you end up that her up answer
And then the stats are Oliva plus minus one variable
Interested in
The variance of Delta
Delta active
How far are we from Lancaster
How wide is the mission SF
Average value
Delta active the sum of independent random variables and so variances ass
The banks of LX is the sum of the variances
Would you take a single stack to see the volume
I'm tired Bavarian
Adelta X is T
Okay
So if you want
The typical distance of Kong
The elf grass
Then you need
The run this chamber time
At Salon Square running at 1 just to show you how this alien General
General
Little guy that phone is warm
These cats were size warm when I said what that means but that's ice Austin TX
Equal spread
53 L on it
All right that's a nasty scalene
Eyes getting quadratically with the ratio of the sides of your face
Good tasting
And example
But that didn't either 100 or 400 opening like that answer the question
2 question 3
And I know this may be
One of those
Which
Keep running the same
Sexiest Russians
Haiti attractions
Apprendre decoration
We have reached a wool so in this particular on a hundred was a very good guess
If you don't bunkering again
We went the last one guy 260
Hitting the same wool
Okay and then we've gone was supposed to lose
400i Generations
Unreasonably in agreement
3D edible
Back of envelope
Keep on running
Imma come back and get that way
And then maybe
400 fraction
Progress the other side
The 500
What about kissing because school
Okay
So that's what happens when you run the sink
So it takes
Thousands of iterations
To get good independent parts
One of the way of visualizing this is to imagine making a histogram over a week of being during the simulation
So hit the histogram a full TS racing
ATI 410
This is for the simulation we just did
So after 400 race engines
Life Alert
Uneven
So this is the point at which you might say I've actually got one decent independent sample from this
I forgot 500 iterations
Okay
I'm not saying
That when you run a metropolis method like this you should throw away all of the point by Juanita
Collectors talking points
The really effective number of independent samples
Just contacts
Okay
So that the random walk problem
We can analyze it a little bit more
Another way of
Look at this is
To make for ourselves the transition probability Matrix
We talk shows * 100
For the chain that we're running here
It's possible stay
And the transition probability
Staying where you are
Okay
We can now
Answer question wrong
Precisely we can say well for any particular generation where you will have
If you stop when I say zero
Any question or any
Starting position and we can plot the point where you will have I stayed upstairs
So
This is the answer to the zero set
Or in like I can 17 if that was why you stop it
Yellow and blue
Those two
Starting out with the probability of being in
Or public opinion state 17
Then after one set
You're either in these
615 East Yellow Pages
Okay this is your distribution
After three steps
That's your distribution
Can you recognize this
1331 Ingleside Street
Pascal's triangle
This one 46416 at the blue distribution
Is 146
4 and 1 steps
But that's the next row of Pascal's triangle except the right hand side. Something is happening
After 6 adoration 7
But update. Every 25
So that's up to 25 set
This is very jagged
Picture in gallery showing you
Thank you stop antenna 25 steps
It's still quite unlikely to have a war
Very likely to be in an hour
Location
If you even faces
But you have any chance of being
So after 50 attractions
Alice in Chains mutts if you saw 16 17 you're still very likely to be at the right hand side if you stopped in Middle
You're more likely be in the middle in it at the edges and you're very unlikely.
Locations
9 + 11
Very unlikely to be lucky memory of all the even
Only losing it all and even memory whenever it comes to a wolf
K75 is ricin
100 fraction
So if you said you think 100 is enough
You might look at this right now and I see pink again
Cuz if you run it for under the impression that every time
From The Middle
Turn around and around
Is it going to be even on me
You're not going to get the right numbers
100 isn't quite long enough
Even if you stopped in the middle
Indefinite not long enough if you start at 17 because
You've got a much lower transom uniform of being in 0 after I understand
Keep dying at 5
Sympathy
Okay
Pretty unicorn out of the rough
Yeah you could be pretty much anywhere after 200
Or after 4400
It's becoming fatty.
Would more likely to be in
All states
And yellow
I love it on now it will likely be an even state
We keep on going
355 360
3 * 400 set
You can hardly see on the screen the difference between
Yellow and the blue
Republicanism
After 500 stats
Okay
Good
Any questions about
Christopher
So the general message recall is
If you make sets of size at salon
But it's the distribution of dealing with his got a characteristic of blank tail
Oh in the same units
A random walk method is going to take at least one square
I think to get around it may be what because I might be other properties
Then you have to run to even longer
Service
Number regarding DSL on square is just a band it's a love I love how long
Have to run
One of these nights
Everything I've done you hair is in one dimension let's just make clear how it relates to
Hi Adonis No Problems in a typical
Problem
It's a it's an inference problem that you're working on
Nipple of these
Things called unknown parameters but not being determined by data
Then
In the real world
Promises
Answer
The nasty red distribution
They look more like this
It may be two dimensional it maybe even thousand dimensional
And it'll have some long length styles and some length styles that are
So
In general you might have
Pacific
Of the real situation
That might be damaged Dimensions gammoth Ogio good
Diamond Dimensions
Where the night Stylistics let's IL
And then there might be K -, other dimensions
The lifestyle isn't much larger
These would be the pulley determine the total number of promises
Canine is gamma dimensions of pulley just have invited I thought you haven't seen them down yet
And Gamma are welded coming by today
What is your effective number
Number of degrees of freedom
Number 1207 promises
And 59 give yourself a Stepside
Pet salon
You could imagine at Salaam
Being
As small as hell
So you could use as your step size 3 Metropolis method
Something respect the time you left alone
Or you could use something
I think
Or I could use something
Reading when you're designing in Metropolis
Thang Long
Be any size you want you pick that
What's going to happen now well
All your pets are accepted and you just do a random walk
Then it's still the case
That the typical distance you will have gum
After teeth that is growing as a square root
It's going to take you
At least I will not songs glad that you get around from one independent points into another
Effectively
Independent party
They need at least
Element
The fresh Independence Point
Fresh Independence sample
So that pushes you to say well I want at Salon to be really big then for the salon
Is a smooth possible
Which is true
They saying let's make it fun as big as we can
However
If you make at Salon really big make is big as hell for example
Big Al
Then what can actually happen
Well if you are in the typical sat and you make a proposal from this big green stair hair
Wait remember
Is
Ghana diamonds in the whole place is K dimensional
A demo of those dimensions
Take us off this time
I'm in so many looked at me
Well that means is the probability of making it except move
Going to be the ratio of
5th volume
Bitcoin
Anthony
Just think about that
You use an analog that significantly bigger than little a little like that
Then the probability of making expected move
This tiny
It's
In all of the long Dimensions you don't need to worry you're very unlikely to.
Beat the chance of thing on the pancake is is Tiny
It's going to be
The volume of the pancake
Indeed job site
You got that link Grace's how, which is the number of dimensions
Waco
Pancake
And then you divide that by the volume of the sphere that you're drawing from
This is
Accepted movie
And that is
Ratio all
Al the little length
Oval step by step one
Rice to possibly quite a big number Ghana the number of Wellington
This is a disaster
You make that phone big
Inside if you make it bigger than little Al at school
Essentially does a constrained
That
He comes
Goat app
Petland great of an owl
Is that news
Because
Even though you wanted to you know that reduced your random properties
He wanted to go hat
You're likely end up with a chain that just sit still and make proposals puzzle and all of those
Rejected
Except
A very very small capsules finally
Making a proposal it makes a nice people
Kentucky somewhat acceptable but it would happen so rarely
But you don't have to update
So in practice
Be feasible
Sensible
Patty's Restaurant
They're right
And obviously you don't want to make them that for me
Actually
This is why you want to be you want to somehow know what the smallest think Skyler distribution is
Then that's roughly
What you want just text I text
You're using a simple proposal
So in practice people using those sort of
Look up list methods
Will then find
That that ultimate song is roughly the smallest light scale
And when they run them Acropolis method with that Smollett blank status that set sign
Then
They will find
That that accepting roughly 50% of The Proposal
Resulting optimal acceptance probability
Ezra play Aha
Possibly a little bit bigger than 1/2
But not a million miles from
Okay
That I spent
Agent book about random walks
I know what we want to do is reveal some ways of getting rid of these random
Boystown Harrisburg tuition
But don't get around by random
In some way such that
You're still at
Thought
You keep going on a short timescale in it in the consistent Direct
Black Gold number one and number two is it the pain in the neck
Have to Catholic unicep cited
If you don't know what she'll just think Skyler your problem is
It will really pay off for you to find that out cuz if you use a set sizes too big
You let me be running a simulation that will do nothing about the time
Did you make it to small you're wasting time you badly
It would be brilliant have methods didn't require special sensitive password shooting
Aruba
Chooses the right that size
In a way that is valid using any soda crack
So let's know
Address both of those
By this
That we have through all of these pictures hair
Renault
Pokemap
Deficient
Montpelier message
And the first efficient method will talk about hamiltonian
Multicolor
And hamiltonian Monte Carlo it's something you couldn't do if you got yourself
A
Color method
Which is like the Metropolis message through Justice continuous State space
I didn't want used to make him small proposals of small moves using say I got you in distribution
Pool problems all that type
You may be able to use
This is how it works
Find the relevant demo
I'll show you first
A problem
Hidden problem
Distribution so we know all about gout
So I'm attempting to sample from the nasty reddish-orange casting distribution which is a highly car
Calcium distribution in two.
Staunton from an initial condition doesn't lie in this is so fat
And I'm using the Metropolis method making little circle green proposals
Circle proposals Pentatonix and
Suppose a new place in blue and
Did the show goes on screen
Tecumseh
The rejection
So that was after I sent you a post that I'm running for another fun-filled cystex
A little run
Sit still
What paint dry
So that's an example well
No
Let me describe to you how
The
Hamiltonian
Monte Carlo
I said what
Hamiltonian Monte Carlo
Has got two names actually
Either call Tony McCullough
Or in the old day that you can because hybrid Monte Carlo
Monte Carlo
Ricky Seahawks
The Cheeky waves at this what
We're imagining that we've got a nasty distribution that we are finding very difficult
The girlfriend.
What we going to do
It's going to take this difficult High dimensional problem
I'm going to say alright let's make the time in South East twice as big
Unless to find a new distribution
A new syncope
Which is going to be cold the momentum
The Joint distribution of X and P
To be
Division St distribution with us off on x
X
A simple distribution in a minus B squared
But the momentum variable
Appropriately
Normalize
What's that
So we make the problems faced by sivik
Okay you find it difficult
It's twice as big and it's not obvious why we should help at all
Well the neat thing we've done is
You can think of this probability distribution as the in the lineup and energy function
But you can think of as a potential energy in space
Plus we got the kinetic energy
N
Hawaii
I miss Ryan its total Camilia if you're thinking of your system is a physical system
For the potential energy
Honda kinetic energy
A Newton's laws are a way of getting around on a total Energy company like this
In a way that conserves energy
I hit the trick
We Define an augmented problem is twice as big
That opens up with the whole load of new moves we can do we can move around
On surfaces of constant total energy by using Newton's Laws
What does the real will do in order to sample from nasty distributions like that
But you didn't you can close and maybe trying to seem like it.
Interaction with a heat pack
I'm because these momentum variables have a very simple distribution we know how to redraw them from
Corresponding distribution
There every now and then we can have the momentum variable
But like what the real world real world use Newton's laws to make text move around and uses little say
The x. Is basically something to do with you I meant so you go in the direction of your momentum
MP. It's something to do with the floor so you go pee. Is
The derivative of energy with respect to X
I went both putting in a jetliner
What is Newton's Laws you keep going
You look at the fourth energy
State space variable
And you make the momentum change in the
All right
What time is it in Monte Carlo does
Is more complicated than what I just said
But the Roughriders this one seem like Newton's Laws
And we'll admit that we're out there doing that approximately but we're going to fix up the approximate mess
Bye
A clever
Call reject rule
The checks on what happened to the change in energy
The change in the total energy
Have your little simulation
Unset 3 is
Randomize
Levementum
Hey by growing it from the correct distribution.
And you repeat
You can close friend of mine and you run for
For a time and can be an arbitrary
Tunable promises you will still have to adjust
The simulation will involve little set sizes that you have to actually do Audino
LeapFrog method
And you have to choose Little Steps of time so it still has parameters which going to be pains in the neck
But you don't even know that you're going to be moving along way
I'll tell you that
To make this whole thing but we
Accept or reject every one of those newtonsville simulations
It's based on
Change it
Maybe I'll reject can you flip a coin to determine
W words at
If the energy goes down
But I'll accept it anyway because that's the way
I don't see what all the details are in the
Thought the book
Let go ahead and show you that thing
So we're going to stop and saying stop point
And I can do this a few times so you get to see the flavor
Of this
Here's what we did we started from the same cell function by the white Arrow
I use Newton's Laws with it quieter
Love pink set
So that let me start remember
When were at the station by the White House
NFL
And then the momentum after the second step we turned right on
Bum bum bumbum bum bumbum bum after what is it
Penalty stats of Newtonian simulation
What happened to the energy
Potential energy
Three other thing but she might think you could see them
When's the father turned around and came back
We persisted in lots of different directions
Okay
Pick up accepted and we run again
Now we've gone over that easily gone
Link-style this problem if you integrate pedometer
Huge long has gone downhill just a little bit as well
Do another run remember when we randomize eventually
But still have the same total energy
When you do step 3 that says randomize momentum
That means calm down
High speed distance time speed
Is high speed you got
Speed
Border wall
Let's go fast
Angry end up the Leatherface
Again
Grand Masti again
Friend of mine stay again
This is Johnny Contour of energy 102
Outside
Pot significantly outside again
Well let me know a while randomize mental
Now that what happened
We just happen to go over a short distance
Random
Okay
5 long way
Dynamites again
And then
Right at the bus I sometimes when we went right way
Take a right the way along the
Okay randomizer next weekend
Reducing jiggling around
I'll come back again
Randomizer
But they haven't making much ice to progress around than the standard
Ramapo let's go back to Metropolis
So what's going on
So we stopped and now we're using Metropolis method
And every one of these little you blue boxes is created by proposing a random little change and then we evaluate them
New energy in that location
The amount of computer time it takes
Make a note that and find the energy in that new location
Is about the same
As a Montague archetype if you're using Newton's Laws
Can you make a single little set of
Stimulating
Victor thing
Little change in position importance of a little bit of
Take out the energy
Right
I'm being fat little blue squares in the Metropolis
In the hamiltonian
Multicolor
Aretha V squishies that were making
Please take me to Save-A-Lot
LOL that's long Square Times
If we go back and stop exactly the same place with hamiltonian Monte Carlo
That okay
Then
With the thing like the computer time is those what was it think you'll so little blue steps
All the way to the other side
I hope this makes it really is acai
And massively reduce the random or behavior
But they have a whole bunch of promises you have around with so we may not be completely in love with it
Now let's move on to another contact goes over at station
The idea of over relaxation is
But it can be applied
The gift something problems
Get something remember doesn't have any
Tunable promises you just grew up in the conditional distribution 85014 time
And it doesn't have any obvious way of including momentum. So how can we get this
Well
Bianca Avila came up with
Pickles over outside
Where at
In standard Gibbs sampling
You would have the conditional distribution of the variable
You work out the conditional distribution of one of the variables
Conditioning conditional
Standard if I'm playing
With an s t distribution
Texas lice
What is the conditional distribution of Wong
Stable condition on the other
And wherever you are at the moment you just make a fresh grew up in that distribution
The other option is
If your current position is at prepare this point
Then in some cunning way
You deliberately draw not from the cracks conditional distribution
But from a distribution that somehow by us
The opposite side
The mode
The details are in the book
And the two ways of doing this
1 is
If the conditional distribution that you're talking about is a gascon
Pedro from the gas station that is pushed in on the side
Off the real castle
Simple squishies
Improve
Publicly you'll end up doing the right thing
The atlas method
Ratasha you now
Is a very simple method
For the conditional distributions
I got you
And you might say well how can it possibly be interesting if all your conditional distributions on Gaskins
Working with is a very simple distribution
Well that do exist interesting distributions
Pull up whose condition this weekend yet The Joint distribution is very difficult
What's up with this is an interesting Tech abilities have
Let me show you Outlook message on the gas industry shoe
Sorry son hamiltonian what color
This is what gives something looks like
For the same
We were just playing with
But has no promises at all
But the typical steps you take
When you draw from the conditional distributions this way or the conditions
Pick up those two directions
Dinner to the wind
The thing with the green distribution
So you never going to be taking stats aside Big Al there only thing to beat exercise little out
But juice
Which means that you got a random walk
Big Al on Little House Square time to get an independent sample using get something
So Atlas message that's says
It's that
That we drool
Deliberately from the opposite side
Papa distribution in one way
And then we got the other variable we draw from the opposite side of it
The net result is shown here in red they can see we're up me run along the comes up with a little bit of War
Consul
If we zoom in on this I'll show you the individual steps
Starting to you
I forget Which Way time Wednesday school reversible anyway
Let's imagine that we started from the bottom left
We started a little bit
Above the green console
And then wake me up beside still a little bit about the green Council
And then again about
And that means we persistently don't look at every other position that's what the red line is telling you
Wonder long console
And it's two dimensional problem
You can do this in high dimensions
Unfold many problems
It turns out to be around them
Sandra various ways of revealing the Improvement in performance
I'm wanted to invent some simple statistics statistics
If they feel too correlation time
Is Barry short for statistic
That nothing indication that is a good plan and quickly
The hit 8.1
Wandering around on the regular I get something
Nothing Orange
That in red is the umbrella station
Bible loathing definitely moving around
Pasta
Honda
And another country to look at this act one square and under get sampling
Around from being in the middle of being at one of the extreme
Encompass
Excellence bad is going
Up and down much faster
Accrued indication that
At least on this time problem
What is better
Tibet labor relaxation full
Conditional distribution
Doesn't involve any conditional distribution for the gas and I'm far more interesting than that
And the good news for you even if you are interesting to see you can still do
Station
Using another method ordered over allocation
An older driver allocation was invented by Radford Neal
Imagine that you are doing get something and you have to have a message
Which will draw you
The new point
From
This
Conditional distribution
And you hopped on the capability and get something to draw a one-year point in this condition distribution
Well
Benadryl
K x from that distribution
So you drool
Pay times
That gives you a whole bunch of points to my look like
All right
Make it more interesting
Couple wear
7 Greenpoint
The total set of points we have hair is a set of eight points including the one that looks currently
And the order they were stationed method says 1 2 3 4 5 6
7/8 your opposite point
Please go to the third one from the other end
Pick up the stick part in this
Whatever you want to go to the point
All right
And that means if your way over if you would get the white. Was actually
Number one in the less you would have gone
This is something any real value
Variable
And it probably correct invalid and in practice a good value of K might be something like
Additional work to get 20 rules from this distribution
Quite often not much extra work at all example if you have to use adaptive rejection sampling
If you're using a rejection sampling method to draw
The first of these points in green
Open adaptive rejection sampling has the property that you can get another one point
The pool all of the way
Consumed in getting the first part then the other ones are free
The listing be a very very cheap method and it may well
Improve your running
There's no guarantee but it was funny
Under the piece of stuff that kill bugs
Which mean faith in inference using Gibbs sampling
Buck's has been around for about 15 or 20 years now
On my way of England to give something for a whole
Different models
Using a simple declarative language and then it figured out how to run to get something for you
And I'm pretty sure that the buttons of bugs right now
Ordered over a Station built into them
So you can get this speed up for free or you can at least give you speed up
Okay
We've been gone for an hour so we just carry on with the advance message
Need a break
Let's keep going
Stop
Oberlin station
I would like to move on to this question of dependence on parameters
The vanilla
Metropolis method we're talking about
Used a gaussian distribution with somewhere and the width of that distribution was
Crucially important we wanted it to be as big as possible and no bigger
When are you turning Monte Carlo site promises
Get something doesn't have any promises which means that maybe we like it
But get something only works if you got a problem where you know how to draw from the conditional
Distribution
But it may be that you're in the world but you just
Haven't got a clue how to do that go energy function
It would be nice to have a method to automatically discovers Bristol the right Stepside
Imats looks like something goes
Are you allowed to go
Play something
Play something was invented by two people
Night night
Rapid meal
And it's a very elegant
Amazingly simple looking way of solving the problem it looks so simple you could imagine it
8A School tile in Bensonhurst Bay and eat myself
So let me show you
Buy something
I'll do it first four
Good old red one-dimensional distribution
Is you can do it in many. Mention by doing one by Mexicans just like
You pick a single dimension
The weapon for a single direction direction you want in your in your continued State space
And you
Use the method described in that one dimension
And then repeat in other dimensions
So his logos
We have
A nasty red distribution
Let me have a current location
Physical activity
And I'm not going to describe to you how we get to the next location which will collect
But it's going to be quiet
A few steps so
At the current location XT
We evaluate Pizza
This is a graph of pizza
Find week
Then
We draw a point uniformly between 0
Antique star of x
And we can think of that has picking a
Point on Metallica
Then
Recreate
Horizontal
Objects
Of with
W
Where W is going to be a set size parameter office like something method
Whose body we don't care about very much because the whole thing is going to be robust to it
Might be
We make a little object like that
Little green thing
It's height is determined by the height of white.
And it's off that
Is chosen randomly uniformly from Oak Bluff that from
The two little
End of the green Pole
It's either aligned with white uniform
3 pic
A uniform choice of this little cars uncle
Trucks coming off the telegraph Pole
All right I was tattoo
Step 3 is
Check to see
Those two places
What the value of pizza that
I must value Pizza
That
And it
Victorio's Pizza is a bug
The Greenline for today is
That's not far enough
Let's make an additional set
The 5w
And then check
You keep on stepping out until when you check
At that
Play
Are we above Pizza
We aren't the hair was already yes we're above so we stop stepping out from this direction
In this direction
We have to step out once and then go to Check Yes or above
I'm by that person street now created a wide a green object
Then
Connecting vide
Is we drool uniformly from the green line that we can just break it so you pick any point to go on the green line
Which could be for example
And this is our candidate that were probably going to end up calling XT
Check one more thing namely
If you look that
Does that
Point lie about the red cup
And if it doesn't
We're okay if it does lie about the right there
What's up no good sorry
I didn't get that does lie about right there sorry that's not good
And
To make things run a bit faster you can optionally
Wipe out all of the green stuff that live beyond this projected point
Away from it in the central away from the white.
Okay
Sorry
Propose the point on the green line
We drew on that was above the rat we rejected it and I was crying again
Until you get one and maybe in probably like that this
Of 1/2
In which case now you say no that's projected to cut it
Flying above the red cup to valuations of pizza
Green hair
Next another screen thing is really quite a snug fit around the Red Tub
The next time you're very unlikely that we're going to miss this
Live below the red cup
Homicide rate you're accepted
How many kilometers from that
Do that
Amazon
Many white everything that you have done had except you keep track of it by your pizza
And you repeat
I think that there's on the computer
Suck a location
Aurora Bushkill point in yellow
Recreate the green thing of with w
How it look the potential on the Galaxy
Now we chat all the green endpoint outside above the the red cup
The woman left
Now you drool in blue and you point in the green line
And that is underneath
The red pill
I'm sorry I'm a dog
Presta
Go to point uniformly on the line
Make a thing of width w
Girl from it
And like the loser a cup
I will done
No time when we're done
This problem has appeared at the very least it'll come back bump
We're moving right the way from one side to the other side of the distribution
Petrosmith purple line
Now we broke something high up because this is a place where p is Big possible for the green truck to be high up
Now I don't got to go so far all we
And
Let me draw from the green thing
We can't go right over into the right hand side
There's going to be rejected
We automatically stay in the place with an r o t
Because it's that bad a shorter distance
And now we feel alone will we go fight a long way
It was above the red line
They know that we try again
Again
Spice that looks like something I'll let it run for a hundred
Doing its thing
And you can associate each of the acceptances was underneath the way you prove the favorite
That's like something. The right thing did you prove it at least this distribution under the tub in Burien
That the
Technic
That looks like something full
Did not see distribution in Rat I think it looks more exciting
And more incredible would it really what
If we do it for a more
Oakwood looking distribution that might look fly
So there in red is it stalking distribution
I let you slide something on it
Right I forgot
So that's how yellow thing
Now are we done do we need
On the left playlist
But still under the right there on the right
Okay we did. Greenpoint play the rest
The respect that like that
Now and we draw a point on the Green
Blind
Is any of the Rat
Example is above the red light
Drinking tour Seattle
Now we make another girl from the green line
So he stayed home in one piece
Now
Make a cross drop
Dorothy from one place to another
And we could have done that no matter how low the valley is
Make lucky Leaf across very very
Nasty valleys in Peoria Hills could be in the way
And yet we can cuddle accustomed
Locate those going from one place to another
And now look where that yelling pointing it's really really like that was
Tonight when do the rules green thing
Dentacoin
Small please thank you
I would keep going
Spypoint
If you run it for longer
Visiting all of the peeps
So that's like something
It's pretty cool idea rapid nailer
Publix free software that implements
This message
And it's
Very very gentle all you need is the ability to evaluate a function
Where You Are
A really nice thing to next events like something is it never
Ends up rejecting
The overall proposal
Turn contrast standard Metropolis message where you want.
I have made any progress if you always will move possibly a very small distance
Maybe a typical set
So it never attacked another beauty of
It's like something is
Step size W is not a crucial parameter
If UW is accidentally 10 times as big as it needs to be
Moore Lumber bluepoint to shrink down
Shrinkage process
And if your W-2 is too small
Overly small green thing
Only small number of us will be required
To Encompass the width of the registration
So
W isn't crucial but you don't have a cow
You too small to latch
Play something. Type of property that typically you will make the steps
That is as big as the width of the people you're dealing with
Beat the final stats
Is all broccoli the optimal size
Okay
That's why something
And I would like to finish with today is talking about
Exact sampling
So how long do you need to run a Monte Carlo method for
I'm going to tell you
What feels to me like really quite amazing breakthrough of the month Tyler Community
Question
How long do I need to run it Forward well how long is he staying you don't really know you just to feel you
Mason Diagnostic lab
How long should I run at 4
You always have this type of pie
Well there was a breakthrough and it happened in approximately 1996
With the invention of methods to talk to Michael and exact time
Under the whole family of different
Perfect sampling
Method and I'm going to just drive to the easiest one to explain this probably
Tens of papers on the maybe even hundreds
How long should we run the simulations for
Well
Exact sampling is based on the idea that you should
Run it for a long time because venue fun
How long
Infinitely law
Adapter
Young Mike Tyson
Okay that sounds like a lot of computer
You can establish the outcome of an infinitely long
Computer simulation
Finite
I'm going to run
The simulation
From the past
From infinitely long in the past
The presence
So how does that help
Let me explain
Let's imagine this is the state space
Kissing license
Simplicity let's imagine with talking about the Electra flipping the coin
To determine whether he goes right or left in the Lexus IS250
Paces
Why the State Bank
Guys like this
I know what I'm asking you to imagine is it an infinite time ago
A little army of 21
Lecherous
Ulta
Infinity
In
Difference among different locations and every one of them
Then started running the Monte Carlo simulation of the Metropolis alfredo
Imagine that
Imagine that they use the same random numbers
So
Random numbers
All of them are showing hat and the first one
Dial pad
Anytime remodeling we can consult a little Encyclopedia of outcomes that we can stay at
Hi - 1732 what was it
Whenever you come back to this
Something to it will tell you
Write the all of them are getting along
The head one of them
Unisafe
Is there anyway I can figure out
Where
One of these is
At that time
Without having to stop at time minus infinity
Could you do that
Well maybe you could because
Looks like you don't know why
Any of them got to
What time - 172
It's at that you do know that
They must have been either in this table that take all this take
I miss you without knowing which of those is true if you run all funky one of them forward
In time it's excellent just see now what would happen
3 to the 21 hypotheses
So you can try all 21 of them and run them forward
Just for this time
Up to the present
And it all of these end up
Colliding with walls and that of the thing
Such a way that oil 20 Wang
End up repair
Then it must be the case but opens one of these guys have ended up even though you don't know where they were
So this is the trip
The trick is
Marketing
Monte Carlo simulations have a property that they do coalesce in time
So if you take all the
State-based - 172
Arundel Ford
Maybe you'll find it all gazillion or 21
A v state
Will have coalesced into a single site
We plan that
If you had a different time
You would have come somewhere in this point which that for is where you would have
By running this thing
So what's the exact time
Pick a time into the past
Whatever 100 * 500
Pick whatever you want it doesn't matter
There we go back a hundred steps
Now send me like pulled in time every single initial condition
That you could have been at
100 * PepsiCo
Or if you can get away with it stimulates you was in that because maybe you don't need to be like
Stimulate the most forward in time
If they reach
Different Pointe
Note that that oil using the same
Random coin flip to the numbers
But they're all using the same random numbers
That means it's two of them dudes in the same state as he tell her some point they will remain in lockstep
45 * 0
Is that they are in several States
Besides okay bummer but we're not done yet we go back
Maybe
And repeat the operation
And see if these guys
By the time you go for us
How come I haven't you.
Maybe the 400
Until
The hovel coalesced
And then you follow them along and you see where they all ended
And then you can declare this site
Is where you would have got to
That's the message
That is very expensive in general because you have to stimulate 21 initial conditions or in general
A big number
If you're really really really coming
You can establish that I have old
But a special case of the 21 letters you actually only need to stimulate
The rightmost Electra on the leftmost Electra
Are you see if those
End up sitting on top of each other
Then only intermediate letras mustard
That's the general idea of most exact
They have some way of ordering
The state space
And then you have the highest state Valera station
And then if they have coalesced
Valentine's Arrow
Ducati stop at Suffolk Temple
Haven't you just go back to exactly the same
They take the highest state
It's been like that for you have to do to prove this is valid
I'm going to show you some beautiful examples of the snow
So that example
Is
To draw a random filing of a hexagon
So here's a hexagon tiles with red
Blue and green Los Angeles
The Los Angeles Kings have three orientations and I started by the three different colors
And you can think of it also is a piling of a hexagon with
Feeling a Brickyard with cubicles
Nataska is
Please give me a random piling of asking a perfectly random piling
Hexagon
Until you invented Markov chain which is it
Adding and removing Brick from The Brickyard how long do I need to add new baby
The Brickyard lamp that can be well will do
Established that completely full Brickyard
Both have ended up in the same state
Tell him the Lester have the empty Rick Ross and on the right we have the food Brickyard
I support in time and it didn't work
So we go back from 108 that 256 that
In the past
Botanica
Keep going and there is a perfect timing of vacuum
And so that's how long it took us 256 units of computer time to get the answer
Find
Do it again
Ogden Clinic fax
Go back to the 206
That is using a different fresh set of random numbers that are defined
How's it going
Under $0.48
Know or go back to
50 Cent
Stetsonville pass
NB
When they helped coalesce because coalescence of unusual sites like when two letrozole
The answer isn't when Nicole
Simulation
All right you don't see any more of those I'll give you one more
Occasionally it takes
More than 256 Steps From the Past
When I said that that's up for this particular size of hexagon
Running this particular algorithm
And that's another calling for free
They might say who cares about filing well I'm not sure this is useful for
But things are very beautiful things and through this work on exact sampling of Thailand
Some discoveries will make
So
There is a perfect
Piling using those three voltages
I'm here is a perfect filing of an even bigger hexagon
When you look at that
You might start with a
Is something happening
Is there a perfect circle appearing
I'm at Frozen all the tiles are red
Arctic Circle
Anaconda
And they injected on the basis of this work on
Randomly generate timing
Maybe a random filing of a hexagon has the property
Beyond which is Frozen
It was discovered
Thanks to exact template
Fine example I want to show you
Is atrovent achtung models
Favorite toy weld of the
If you went back before 1996
Arrest people
Oh goodness me this very interesting icing mobile that are cut about pay transitions it's a bit of a
Middlesex that melting of ice and that sort of thing is so critical phenomena doesn't fluctuations
When it melts
Tell me I would stimulate game of the month
What should I get for I want to make a really good sample
People decide the Billabong time is it called
Slowing down
Very long time and no one really knows how long does it take for
In 96 this exact time Glen community made a breakthrough
Epic comparable to breakthrough in superconductivity When I Was An undergraduate in your warm like that
And then two years later
Turn back to the election
I could do
And a similar breakthrough Andrew lightning model
Which means that
It's not possible
To show a sample
Organizing model is a perfect sample the critical temperature
What's the temperature
Call VIP mobile
Just Dance Juicy to ising model C I think model is a spin system for every
Up or down a couple likes to be the same
But on the other hand it
Temperature so it has a tendency to
Random what's it look like
Heritage at low temperature
Tiny bit of blue
It could be
All white with a tiny bit of blue
Or it could be
Dwight Oden doble
The high temperature is it
Low temperature
Indonesia temperature
Interesting phenomenon
Sleeping stop
So long
Then below a certain temperature
It all turns into a single, eventually
The newspaper
There are other Albertsons you can use with the much quicker missing between the old blue and they will why
States
This is a different Dupree 1996 States in someone's eye or how long I
The temperature I'm really interested in them.
Arrow Barber
I want to get a perfect sample but I don't know how long
Because
74 really big things that I can measure how big
So that's the challenge
And
The exact sampling community
Came up with a method of solving this just a little bit more introductions I mentioned
Temperature
I do
Crank which way did it go
Temperature is going to the right
The cranky up the temperature
And what happens to the energy is going to make it with more energy
Put the fluctuations in Odyssey the standard deviation of the
Omelette
I need to see
At the temperature of 2.305
There's something wacky going on at the temperature melting from the mainly or blue or white
Into what three states
The average magnetisation which is how much or blue or white the mean squared minus ization
Right on Guam
And that very low temperatures it's very very magnetized it's always
In Pilot knitting Holly blue
Then as you got to be suddenly become
Certificate
Very very lucky
Okay
So that's what I can bubbles look like
There is
A I forgot how big this thing is
800 by 800
Pixel
Austin mobile asset critical temperature
And I'm going to
Show you a computer program that will make another of these perfect sample for you right now
That is a piece of software written by
Stop drop and Wilson do I choose the heroes of exact time playing
And I'm going to start running now
It's running from the past to the present and that little dog on top right
The top most
Say
I'm what was visualizing hair is no mistake of the ising model but the state of ammo General system called
The random cluster model
Which is at 8
Set appointment with edges that are either present or not present between adjacent
Points
We can then
Take all of those edges and we could show which things are connected to each other and color them different colors
Identified by the color
And then we can
Randomly taking custody to make it black or white not give us a sample
So they want done it
I'm in front of your eyes I have created a perfect sample on this
Spring me Lodge it doesn't take very long
This method
So
On the screen tab
I'm doing it now in the top left-hand corner
So you can see a bit more would look like if you were seeing this for resolution
The full resolution version
It's on the website
Okay then summary what we done today we've talked a lot about running book Behavior as how we would love to get rid of it
I'll show you some efficient methods for reducing run about Behavior I'll show you some methods for getting rid of the sensitivity to Chris
Promises
And I told you a little bit
About exact sampling
Throw some other issues respond to the last lecture someone said
How do you find the normalizing, and that's the crucial question we would love to know that normalizing constant from any of these problems
I'm the right illumise literature on very complicated and Counting methods to find cuz I like that
These must color method
So his words from literature
The final Martin compston
Bethel dump
Temper transitions annealed importance sampling LinkedIn
Radford Neal
The reason so difficult to get the dome light in Compton
Is visualized with a cartoon hat
Imagine that you go to Lake
And the Lakers going to that the Jacksonville Ikea poke stop
Imagine you've got some capability
To move your boat around on the lake and how deep the lake
He might be trying to draw uniformly distributed python samples from the light
Let's imagine that you have at least told that you've not got the capability to cool up a random point in the lake
Random intense of uniformitarianism the whole volume of the light
Tell me how deep the lake is
If you keep on pulling on that capability
And you'll complicated light completely
You will be able to go to randomly chosen point in the volume of water I need to find out how deep for like it
I just have to think about that capability if you go to all of those points
I made it home depot like it
Does that tell you, water is in Malay
Tonight
No because you could be in a lake
Prices live in places like in both dimensions
All about measurement
Stretching the the map of the lake in Baton Rouge
The ability to sample
From the volume of the light
Doesn't give you any information about
Volume Excel
Not quite so difficult that because that is the amount of water
Dim the lights they have to use other methods
Sequences of probability distributions
Trying to type
Fuel cell
To a distribution that you understand the way you know the volume
Then you go from that by seeking to stats for the real distribution of Interest
I did not weigh
That's all I wanted to say about Adventure
Are there any questions
Okay so the question is
Is at the one-dimensional variable it's like Netflix
Samantha is
The problem that you are solving maybe many dimensional
If you want to sell them any damage no problem with black something
Then what you would do
Is
You take your current location
How do you pick a direction to slice in
It could be any any direction
As long as your message using the direction doesn't depend on the current location
Upickit erection and then you say hello
To be
The distance along the direction when you operate fly sampling along that line
Pick a blue point
This is your new podcast
And then you pick another Direction at random Maybe
I need you flight something along that
So that's how you was used by something it's a lot like get something
Which goes along the axes
If you can use any Massachusetts directions
Taken
Okay
The question is can you apply exact time playing to continuous value
Braunfels Texas
Unanswered yet
You have to be very cunning
But it is possible
Soul
Some continuous problems
Disney exact something
So the critical thing you need is some way of achieving coalescence even though you felt
The number for True Value that one parameter
Did it have a China at the properties at
Sometimes all of those in
All of the points in this continuum
Kodak lens for single value
It's not easy
I bet there isn't a huge Liquors we can do Bayesian inference
That's not being a chief
Annabelle
Hey thank you very much